<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <id>https://ouchaku.github.io/ds/en/blog</id>
    <title>UFO/Bigfoot/Missing-411/Supernatural Research Blog</title>
    <updated>2024-07-18T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
    <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://ouchaku.github.io/ds/en/blog"/>
    <subtitle>UFO/Bigfoot/Missing-411/Supernatural Research Blog</subtitle>
    <icon>https://ouchaku.github.io/ds/en/img/favicon.png</icon>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Eric Ouellet：Roswell 事件の目撃者は 7人。内 5人は軍人で特別なものは見ていない。奇妙なものを見たのは残りの 2人だけ ⇒ 本当か？]]></title>
        <id>https://ouchaku.github.io/ds/en/blog/2024/07/18/eric_ouellet _roswell</id>
        <link href="https://ouchaku.github.io/ds/en/blog/2024/07/18/eric_ouellet _roswell"/>
        <updated>2024-07-18T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[前置き]]></summary>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="前置き">前置き<a class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to 前置き" title="Direct link to 前置き" href="https://ouchaku.github.io/ds/en/blog/2024/07/18/eric_ouellet%20_roswell#%E5%89%8D%E7%BD%AE%E3%81%8D">​</a></h2>
<p>Eric Ouellet はカナダの社会学者で</p>
<p>Eric Ouellet, "Illuminations: The UFO Experience as a Parapsychological", Anomalist Books, 2015</p>
<p>という「UFO はポルターガイスト現象だ」という趣旨の著書(*1)も出している。彼のインタビュー動画からタイトルの件に絞る。</p>
<h3 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="1">(*1)<a class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to (*1)" title="Direct link to (*1)" href="https://ouchaku.github.io/ds/en/blog/2024/07/18/eric_ouellet%20_roswell#1">​</a></h3>
<details class="details_lb9f alert alert--info details_b_Ee" data-collapsed="true"><summary>▼展開</summary><div><div class="collapsibleContent_i85q"><blockquote><a href="https://ouchaku.github.io/ds/img/20240718_book.jpg" target="_blank"><img alt="20240718_book.jpg" border="0" src="https://ouchaku.github.io/ds/img/20240718_book.jpg" width="90%"></a><p>UFO体験が無意識の大規模な超能力の結果だとしたら？</p><p>超心理学とUFO学は油と水のようなものだ。何十年もの間、高名な研究者たちがUFO現象の超常現象や超心理学的側面に注目しようと努力してきたにもかかわらず、両者は混じり合わないのだ。社会学者エリック・オイエレットは『イルミネーションズ』の中で、地球外生命体、タイムトラベラー、政府の秘密プロジェクト、自然現象など、これまで説明しようとするあらゆる努力に抵抗してきたこの現象に、斬新なアプローチを提供している。</p><p>超心理学、社会学、UFO学の研究を組み合わせ、オイエレットは、1952年のワシントンDCのUFOの波、1961年のベティとバーニー・ヒル誘拐事件、1980年のレンデルシャムUFO事件、1989年から1991年のベルギーのUFOの波など、いくつかの有名なUFO事件の再評価を示唆する。UFOの謎に対する最終的な解決策を持っていると主張するわけではないが、彼は、頑固なまでにとらえどころのない現象に対して、多くの考える材料と新鮮な展望を提供している。</p><p>「この分野における超心理学的なアプローチは稀である。-ジャック・ヴァレ、『見えない大学』の著者</p><p>「社会学者として、UFO目撃者として、さらに超心理学研究者として、エリック・オイエレットは、私が40年にわたるUFO調査の現場で遭遇した好奇心のバガテルを理解するためのすべての条件を満たしている。- ジェニー・ランドルズ、『マインド・モンスター』の著者</p><p>ERIC OUELLETは、カナダ王立陸軍大学およびカナダ軍大学（カナダの統合幕僚学校および陸軍大学）の国防学教授である。ヨーク大学（カナダ・トロント）で社会学の博士号を取得し、超心理学協会のカナダ担当連絡官を務める。オーストラリアン・ジャーナル・オブ・サイコロジー』、『エッジサイエンス』、『会報Métapsychique』に超心理学的研究を発表している。その他の研究テーマは軍事社会学と戦争研究である。</p><hr><p>What if UFO experiences are the result of large-scale, unconscious, psychic forces?</p><p>Parapsychology and UFOlogy are like oil and water. They just don't mix, despite the decades-long efforts of some highly respected researchers to call attention to the paranormal or parapsychological aspects of UFO events. In Illuminations, sociologist Eric Ouellet offers a novel approach to a phenomenon that has thus far resisted all other efforts to explain it, be it as extraterrestrial craft, time travelers, secret government projects, or natural phenomena.</p><p>Combining research in parapsychology, sociology, and UFOlogy, Ouellet provides a thought provoking reassessment of several well-known UFO cases, including the Washington, DC, UFO wave of 1952, the Betty and Barney Hill abduction of 1961, the Rendlesham UFO incident of 1980, and the Belgian UFO wave of 1989-1991. While not claiming to have the final solution to the UFO mystery, he offers much food for thought and a refreshing outlook on a stubbornly elusive phenomenon.</p><p>"Parapsychological approaches in this field are rare: your contribution is precious, and it is very timely." -Jacques Vallée, author of The Invisible College</p><p>"As a sociologist and a UFO witness, plus, importantly, a parapsychological researcher, Eric Ouellet ticks all the boxes to appreciate the bagatelle of curiosities that I have encountered in the field during 40 years of UFO investigation." - Jenny Randles, author of Mind Monsters</p><p>ERIC OUELLET is professor of Defence Studies at the Royal Military College of Canada, and at the Canadian Forces College (Canada's Joint Staff and War College). He has a Ph.D. in sociology from York University (Toronto, Canada), and he is the liaison officer for Canada with the Parapsychological Association. He has published parapsychological work in the Australian Journal of Psychology, EdgeScience, and the Bulletin Métapsychique. His other research works focus on military sociology and war studies.</p><p>ref: Amazon | Illuminations: The UFO Experience as a Parapsychological Event | Ouellet, Eric | Occult
<a href="https://www.amazon.co.jp/Illuminations-UFO-Experience-Parapsychological-Event/dp/193839853X" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">https://www.amazon.co.jp/Illuminations-UFO-Experience-Parapsychological-Event/dp/193839853X</a></p></blockquote></div></div></details>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="whisper-ailarge-v2-model--deepl">Whisper AI(large-v2 model) + DeepL<a class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Whisper AI(large-v2 model) + DeepL" title="Direct link to Whisper AI(large-v2 model) + DeepL" href="https://ouchaku.github.io/ds/en/blog/2024/07/18/eric_ouellet%20_roswell#whisper-ailarge-v2-model--deepl">​</a></h2>
<p>ロズウェルのようなことを指摘する人たちに何と言う？
まあ、ロズウェルは、つまり、入手可能な証拠を非常に詳細に分析した人もいる。
(00:12:20)</p>
<p>そのうちの1人は、それが何であれ、あれを実際に見た人は7人しかいない、と発表したんだ。
その7人のうち5人、その5人は軍人で、それについて特別なことは何も見ていない。
つまり、何か奇妙なことがあるのではないかと考えたのは2人だけということになる。
考えてみれば、その視点から証拠を見れば、かなり薄っぺらいもので、あとは伝聞や噂ばかりだ。
(00:12:51)</p>
<p>フィリップ・コルソのような本は誇張して書いているしね。
(00:12:55)</p>
<hr>
<p>そして、徹底的に分析した結果、そのほとんどがでっち上げであることに気づく。
だから結局、ロズウェルの話には大したことはないと思う。</p>
<hr>
<p>And what do you say to people who point to things like Roswell?
Well, Roswell, I mean, some people did a very detailed analysis of the evidence available.
(00:12:20)</p>
<p>And one of them came out with, there's only seven people who actually saw that thing, whatever it was.
And of those seven people, five, and the five of them are military, didn't see anything special about it.
So this only comes down to two people who thought that there might be something really weird about this.
It's pretty thin, if you think about it, if you look at the evidence from that perspective, and then all the rest of the story is hearsays and rumors.
(00:12:51)</p>
<p>And I mean, books like Philip Corso that exaggerate things.
(00:12:55)</p>
<hr>
<p>And then we all discover after thorough analysis that almost all of it is fabrication.
So, in the end, I think in the Roswell story, there's not a whole lot.</p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="コメント">コメント<a class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to コメント" title="Direct link to コメント" href="https://ouchaku.github.io/ds/en/blog/2024/07/18/eric_ouellet%20_roswell#%E3%82%B3%E3%83%A1%E3%83%B3%E3%83%88">​</a></h2>
<p>私は Roswell 事件で UFO の墜落はないと判断している。だが、その私ですら Eric Ouellet のタイトルの主張、</p>
<blockquote><p>入手可能な証拠を非常に詳細に分析した人もいる。そのうちの1人は、それが何であれ、あれを実際に見た人は7人しかいない、と発表したんだ。その7人のうち5人、その5人は軍人で、それについて特別なことは何も見ていない。
つまり、何か奇妙なことがあるのではないかと考えたのは2人だけということになる。</p></blockquote>
<p>は極めて疑わしく思える。</p>
<p>まず、「実際に見た人は7人」と「5人は軍人」から「つまり、何か奇妙なことがあるのではないかと考えたのは2人だけ」を導き出すようでは Eric Ouellet は論理的思考能力に問題がある（or 説明能力が貧弱）。導き出せるのは、「非軍人の目撃者はふたり」ということだけ。</p>
<p>そもそも Eric Ouellet の語るタイトルのような調査結果は初耳だが、誰の調査結果で、その根拠は何か、を Eric Ouellet は一切、語っていない。</p>
<p>私の知る範囲で、Roswell の破片に直接触れたり見たりしたと民間人は少なくとも</p>
<ol>
<li>Mack Brazel：第一発見者、牧場の委託管理者</li>
<li>Timothy D Proctor : Mack Brazel に同伴。当時 7歳</li>
<li>George Wilcox :保安官</li>
<li>Jesse Marcel Jr.：Jesse Marcel の息子</li>
<li>Jesse Marcel の妻</li>
</ol>
<p>の 5人になる。この 5人が目撃したことを疑う正当な理由はない。</p>
<p>それなのに、 Eric Ouellet （が高く評価する「詳細に分析した人」）は何を根拠に「たったふたりの非軍人の目撃者」だと言うのか？</p>
<ul>
<li>
<p>「入手可能な証拠を非常に詳細に分析した人」って誰だ？</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>「その視点から証拠を見れば、かなり薄っぺらいもので、あとは伝聞や噂ばかりだ」と言うが、その視点とやらが信用できないのだが。</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>「徹底的に分析した結果」というが、どこが徹底的なのだ？ 恣意的な分析を徹底的な分析と言い換えていないか？</p>
</li>
</ul>
<p>このように、Eric Ouellet の主張は初っ端から大きな疑問符がつく。言い換えると Eric Ouellet の主張は怪しい(*1)ので注意して扱う必要がある。</p>
<h3 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="1-1">(*1)<a class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to (*1)" title="Direct link to (*1)" href="https://ouchaku.github.io/ds/en/blog/2024/07/18/eric_ouellet%20_roswell#1-1">​</a></h3>
<p>Eric Ouellet の怪しい主張の別の具体例が下。</p>
<p><a href="https://ouchaku.github.io/ds/en/blog/2024/07/18/eric_ouellet_pilot_badmood_malfunction">Eric Ouellet：パイロットの機嫌が悪い時、航空用電子機器が正常動作しないことを示唆する研究結果がある</a></p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="動画12859">動画(1:28:59)<a class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to 動画(1:28:59)" title="Direct link to 動画(1:28:59)" href="https://ouchaku.github.io/ds/en/blog/2024/07/18/eric_ouellet%20_roswell#%E5%8B%95%E7%94%BB12859">​</a></h2>
<p>UFO's and Poltergeists with Eric Ouellet - July 11, 2024</p>
<iframe width="560" height="315" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/dPBHw12YCuU?si=Frq8sayKRIHGwgI5" title="YouTube video player" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin"></iframe>
<p><a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=dPBHw12YCuU" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">www.youtube.com/watch?v=dPBHw12YCuU</a></p>
<h3 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="動画概要欄">動画概要欄<a class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to 動画概要欄" title="Direct link to 動画概要欄" href="https://ouchaku.github.io/ds/en/blog/2024/07/18/eric_ouellet%20_roswell#%E5%8B%95%E7%94%BB%E6%A6%82%E8%A6%81%E6%AC%84">​</a></h3>
<p>1,700 views  Jul 15, 2024  2024 Shows
Originally aired on April 2, 2016</p>
<p>Since I reference this book a lot, I felt it was time to remaster and re-upload this show, with it's short Patreon segment as well.</p>
<p>Eric Ouellet joins me for a fascinating discussion of his new book, Illuminations: The UFO Experience as a Parapsychological Event. He proposes that we should examine the UFO Phenomenon as we would a poltergeist case. It's a novel way of looking at it, and may ultimately play a part in solving this enigma.</p>
<p>ERIC OUELLET is professor of Defence Studies at the Royal Military College of Canada, and at the Canadian Forces College (Canada's Joint Staff and War College). He has a Ph.D. in sociology from York University (Toronto, Canada), and he is the liaison officer for Canada with the Parapsychological Association. He has published parapsychological work in the Australian Journal of Psychology, EdgeScience, and the Bulletin Métapsychique. His other research works focus on military sociology and war studies.</p>
<p>(2024-07-18)</p>]]></content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Eric Ouellet：ベルギーでの UFO 目撃多発もポルターガイスト現象として解釈できる]]></title>
        <id>https://ouchaku.github.io/ds/en/blog/2024/07/18/eric_ouellet_belgean_ufo_flap_as_poltergeist</id>
        <link href="https://ouchaku.github.io/ds/en/blog/2024/07/18/eric_ouellet_belgean_ufo_flap_as_poltergeist"/>
        <updated>2024-07-18T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[前置き]]></summary>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="前置き">前置き<a class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to 前置き" title="Direct link to 前置き" href="https://ouchaku.github.io/ds/en/blog/2024/07/18/eric_ouellet_belgean_ufo_flap_as_poltergeist#%E5%89%8D%E7%BD%AE%E3%81%8D">​</a></h2>
<p>Eric Ouellet はカナダの社会学者で</p>
<p>Eric Ouellet, "Illuminations: The UFO Experience as a Parapsychological", Anomalist Books, 2015</p>
<p>という「UFO はポルターガイスト現象だ」という趣旨の著書(*1)も出している。彼のインタビュー動画からタイトルの件に絞る。</p>
<h3 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="1">(*1)<a class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to (*1)" title="Direct link to (*1)" href="https://ouchaku.github.io/ds/en/blog/2024/07/18/eric_ouellet_belgean_ufo_flap_as_poltergeist#1">​</a></h3>
<details class="details_lb9f alert alert--info details_b_Ee" data-collapsed="true"><summary>▼展開</summary><div><div class="collapsibleContent_i85q"><blockquote><a href="https://ouchaku.github.io/ds/img/20240718_book.jpg" target="_blank"><img alt="20240718_book.jpg" border="0" src="https://ouchaku.github.io/ds/img/20240718_book.jpg" width="90%"></a><p>UFO体験が無意識の大規模な超能力の結果だとしたら？</p><p>超心理学とUFO学は油と水のようなものだ。何十年もの間、高名な研究者たちがUFO現象の超常現象や超心理学的側面に注目しようと努力してきたにもかかわらず、両者は混じり合わないのだ。社会学者エリック・オイエレットは『イルミネーションズ』の中で、地球外生命体、タイムトラベラー、政府の秘密プロジェクト、自然現象など、これまで説明しようとするあらゆる努力に抵抗してきたこの現象に、斬新なアプローチを提供している。</p><p>超心理学、社会学、UFO学の研究を組み合わせ、オイエレットは、1952年のワシントンDCのUFOの波、1961年のベティとバーニー・ヒル誘拐事件、1980年のレンデルシャムUFO事件、1989年から1991年のベルギーのUFOの波など、いくつかの有名なUFO事件の再評価を示唆する。UFOの謎に対する最終的な解決策を持っていると主張するわけではないが、彼は、頑固なまでにとらえどころのない現象に対して、多くの考える材料と新鮮な展望を提供している。</p><p>「この分野における超心理学的なアプローチは稀である。-ジャック・ヴァレ、『見えない大学』の著者</p><p>「社会学者として、UFO目撃者として、さらに超心理学研究者として、エリック・オイエレットは、私が40年にわたるUFO調査の現場で遭遇した好奇心のバガテルを理解するためのすべての条件を満たしている。- ジェニー・ランドルズ、『マインド・モンスター』の著者</p><p>ERIC OUELLETは、カナダ王立陸軍大学およびカナダ軍大学（カナダの統合幕僚学校および陸軍大学）の国防学教授である。ヨーク大学（カナダ・トロント）で社会学の博士号を取得し、超心理学協会のカナダ担当連絡官を務める。オーストラリアン・ジャーナル・オブ・サイコロジー』、『エッジサイエンス』、『会報Métapsychique』に超心理学的研究を発表している。その他の研究テーマは軍事社会学と戦争研究である。</p><hr><p>What if UFO experiences are the result of large-scale, unconscious, psychic forces?</p><p>Parapsychology and UFOlogy are like oil and water. They just don't mix, despite the decades-long efforts of some highly respected researchers to call attention to the paranormal or parapsychological aspects of UFO events. In Illuminations, sociologist Eric Ouellet offers a novel approach to a phenomenon that has thus far resisted all other efforts to explain it, be it as extraterrestrial craft, time travelers, secret government projects, or natural phenomena.</p><p>Combining research in parapsychology, sociology, and UFOlogy, Ouellet provides a thought provoking reassessment of several well-known UFO cases, including the Washington, DC, UFO wave of 1952, the Betty and Barney Hill abduction of 1961, the Rendlesham UFO incident of 1980, and the Belgian UFO wave of 1989-1991. While not claiming to have the final solution to the UFO mystery, he offers much food for thought and a refreshing outlook on a stubbornly elusive phenomenon.</p><p>"Parapsychological approaches in this field are rare: your contribution is precious, and it is very timely." -Jacques Vallée, author of The Invisible College</p><p>"As a sociologist and a UFO witness, plus, importantly, a parapsychological researcher, Eric Ouellet ticks all the boxes to appreciate the bagatelle of curiosities that I have encountered in the field during 40 years of UFO investigation." - Jenny Randles, author of Mind Monsters</p><p>ERIC OUELLET is professor of Defence Studies at the Royal Military College of Canada, and at the Canadian Forces College (Canada's Joint Staff and War College). He has a Ph.D. in sociology from York University (Toronto, Canada), and he is the liaison officer for Canada with the Parapsychological Association. He has published parapsychological work in the Australian Journal of Psychology, EdgeScience, and the Bulletin Métapsychique. His other research works focus on military sociology and war studies.</p><p>ref: Amazon | Illuminations: The UFO Experience as a Parapsychological Event | Ouellet, Eric | Occult
<a href="https://www.amazon.co.jp/Illuminations-UFO-Experience-Parapsychological-Event/dp/193839853X" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">https://www.amazon.co.jp/Illuminations-UFO-Experience-Parapsychological-Event/dp/193839853X</a></p></blockquote></div></div></details>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="whisper-ailarge-v2-model--deepl">Whisper AI(large-v2 model) + DeepL<a class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Whisper AI(large-v2 model) + DeepL" title="Direct link to Whisper AI(large-v2 model) + DeepL" href="https://ouchaku.github.io/ds/en/blog/2024/07/18/eric_ouellet_belgean_ufo_flap_as_poltergeist#whisper-ailarge-v2-model--deepl">​</a></h2>
<p>ベルギーの国防省も何が起こっているのか不思議に思っていたからだ。
(00:28:32)</p>
<p>ベルギーの国防省も何が起こっているのか不思議に思っていたからだ。
だから、問題を取り除くにはいい方法だった。
しかし、正味の効果として、彼らの関与は、毎日の激しさは減ったものの、実際にはもっと多くの観察を生み出した。
しかし、彼らをまとめると、多くの観測が行われ、それが彼らの大規模な記者会見につながった。
(00:29:01)</p>
<p>その記者会見には軍も同席し、グループに正当性を与えた。
そこで彼らが言ったのは、我々は三角形や物体を見る傾向があり、それらは特定の行動をとる傾向があるということだ。
データを見ると、三角形の物体を目撃したUFOは全体の50％しかなかった。
それ以外のケースは、ボール、球体、四角形など、いろいろなものがあった。
(00:29:37)</p>
<p>つまり、驚きと変位がある。
そしてその話は、興味深いことに、ベルギー軍が1990年3月にベルギーの空でUFOを追跡し始めたという、最も劇的な出来事へと向かっていく。
そして最終的に彼らは、説明のつかない多くのことが提示された報告書を作成した。
そして興味深いことに、そこからこの事件は衰退し始める。
(00:30:14)</p>
<p>というのも、これらのことを研究するための非常に高度な装置をたくさん持っていた批判的な観察者たち、つまり軍は、UFOグループを非難しなかった。
彼らはただ、奇妙なものがあると言った。
私たちには説明できない。
彼らはエイリアンの説明に同意するとは言わなかった。
(00:30:42)</p>
<p>それでも、他のケースに比べれば緩やかな減少だった。
そしてやがて、この事件は収束した。
つまり、もうUFOはいなかった。
だから、抑制段階が起こったと言える。
しかし、社会的な観点から言うと、UFOの波が抑制される段階が今まさに起こっていると言える。
(00:31:16)</p>
<p>つまり、UFO事件、ごめん、ポルターガイスト事件で見られるような、事象の全体的な曲線、ベルカーブに従ったんだ。
なるほど。
(00:31:27)</p>
<hr>
<p>And that's when then at that point that a UFO group, a major UFO group in Belgium got involved.
And then they eventually were able to secure the support of the police and mostly the military in Belgium to help them out because the Ministry of Defense in Belgium was also wondering what was going on.
(00:28:32)</p>
<p>And the police was overwhelmed with UFO reports.
So it was a good way to get rid of the problems and just tell people, call that UFO group, don't call us.
But the net effect is that their involvement actually created a lot more observation, although less intense in every day.
But if you take them collectively, a lot of observation occurred, which led to a major press conference that they gave.
(00:29:01)</p>
<p>And the military was present at the press conference, giving a lot of legitimacy to the group.
And that's where they said, you know, we tend to see triangles, objects, and they tend to behave in certain ways, which actually is partially correct.
If you look at the data, only 50% of all the UFO cases they had involved a triangular object.
All the other cases were other things, balls, you had spheres, you had squares, I mean, you have all kinds of things going on.
(00:29:37)</p>
<p>And so that's really, so we have the surprise and then the displacement.
And then that story, interestingly, keeps moving towards the, I would say, the most dramatic event where the Belgian military start to chase UFOs in the sky of Belgium in March of 1990.
And eventually they produced a report where a lot of things unexplainable are presented.
And that's where, interestingly, the case starts to decline.
(00:30:14)</p>
<p>There's still UFO events, but it declined gently, which is a bit of a variation of the official model, because you can see that the critical observers, the military who had a lot of very advanced equipment to study these things, did not rebuke the UFO group.
They just say there's something weird.
We cannot explain that.
They never said they were agreeing with any alien explanation.
(00:30:42)</p>
<p>So it still declined, but more gently, I would say, than other cases.
And eventually the case stopped.
I mean, there was no more UFO, very few.
So we can say that suppression phase happened.
But I would say from a social perspective, the suppression phase of the UFO wave is happening right now, where you have a lot of people wrote with the hindsight saying, oh, no, no, it was just a mass illusion, and we should not talk about UFO anymore, and et cetera, et cetera.
(00:31:16)</p>
<p>So it kind of followed the whole curve, the bell curve of events that you see in a UFO, sorry, in a poltergeist case.
Okay.
(00:31:27)</p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="動画12859">動画(1:28:59)<a class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to 動画(1:28:59)" title="Direct link to 動画(1:28:59)" href="https://ouchaku.github.io/ds/en/blog/2024/07/18/eric_ouellet_belgean_ufo_flap_as_poltergeist#%E5%8B%95%E7%94%BB12859">​</a></h2>
<p>UFO's and Poltergeists with Eric Ouellet - July 11, 2024</p>
<iframe width="560" height="315" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/dPBHw12YCuU?si=Frq8sayKRIHGwgI5" title="YouTube video player" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin"></iframe>
<p><a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=dPBHw12YCuU" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">www.youtube.com/watch?v=dPBHw12YCuU</a></p>
<h3 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="動画概要欄">動画概要欄<a class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to 動画概要欄" title="Direct link to 動画概要欄" href="https://ouchaku.github.io/ds/en/blog/2024/07/18/eric_ouellet_belgean_ufo_flap_as_poltergeist#%E5%8B%95%E7%94%BB%E6%A6%82%E8%A6%81%E6%AC%84">​</a></h3>
<p>1,700 views  Jul 15, 2024  2024 Shows
Originally aired on April 2, 2016</p>
<p>Since I reference this book a lot, I felt it was time to remaster and re-upload this show, with it's short Patreon segment as well.</p>
<p>Eric Ouellet joins me for a fascinating discussion of his new book, Illuminations: The UFO Experience as a Parapsychological Event. He proposes that we should examine the UFO Phenomenon as we would a poltergeist case. It's a novel way of looking at it, and may ultimately play a part in solving this enigma.</p>
<p>ERIC OUELLET is professor of Defence Studies at the Royal Military College of Canada, and at the Canadian Forces College (Canada's Joint Staff and War College). He has a Ph.D. in sociology from York University (Toronto, Canada), and he is the liaison officer for Canada with the Parapsychological Association. He has published parapsychological work in the Australian Journal of Psychology, EdgeScience, and the Bulletin Métapsychique. His other research works focus on military sociology and war studies.</p>
<p>(2024-07-18)</p>]]></content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Eric Ouellet：ベルギーでの UFO 目撃多発時、周囲の国家は大きな変革がおきていた]]></title>
        <id>https://ouchaku.github.io/ds/en/blog/2024/07/18/eric_ouellet_belgium_ufo_reason</id>
        <link href="https://ouchaku.github.io/ds/en/blog/2024/07/18/eric_ouellet_belgium_ufo_reason"/>
        <updated>2024-07-18T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[前置き]]></summary>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="前置き">前置き<a class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to 前置き" title="Direct link to 前置き" href="https://ouchaku.github.io/ds/en/blog/2024/07/18/eric_ouellet_belgium_ufo_reason#%E5%89%8D%E7%BD%AE%E3%81%8D">​</a></h2>
<p>Eric Ouellet はカナダの社会学者で</p>
<p>Eric Ouellet, "Illuminations: The UFO Experience as a Parapsychological", Anomalist Books, 2015</p>
<p>という「UFO はポルターガイスト現象だ」という趣旨の著書(*1)も出している。彼のインタビュー動画からタイトルの件に絞る。</p>
<h3 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="1">(*1)<a class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to (*1)" title="Direct link to (*1)" href="https://ouchaku.github.io/ds/en/blog/2024/07/18/eric_ouellet_belgium_ufo_reason#1">​</a></h3>
<details class="details_lb9f alert alert--info details_b_Ee" data-collapsed="true"><summary>▼展開</summary><div><div class="collapsibleContent_i85q"><blockquote><a href="https://ouchaku.github.io/ds/img/20240718_book.jpg" target="_blank"><img alt="20240718_book.jpg" border="0" src="https://ouchaku.github.io/ds/img/20240718_book.jpg" width="90%"></a><p>UFO体験が無意識の大規模な超能力の結果だとしたら？</p><p>超心理学とUFO学は油と水のようなものだ。何十年もの間、高名な研究者たちがUFO現象の超常現象や超心理学的側面に注目しようと努力してきたにもかかわらず、両者は混じり合わないのだ。社会学者エリック・オイエレットは『イルミネーションズ』の中で、地球外生命体、タイムトラベラー、政府の秘密プロジェクト、自然現象など、これまで説明しようとするあらゆる努力に抵抗してきたこの現象に、斬新なアプローチを提供している。</p><p>超心理学、社会学、UFO学の研究を組み合わせ、オイエレットは、1952年のワシントンDCのUFOの波、1961年のベティとバーニー・ヒル誘拐事件、1980年のレンデルシャムUFO事件、1989年から1991年のベルギーのUFOの波など、いくつかの有名なUFO事件の再評価を示唆する。UFOの謎に対する最終的な解決策を持っていると主張するわけではないが、彼は、頑固なまでにとらえどころのない現象に対して、多くの考える材料と新鮮な展望を提供している。</p><p>「この分野における超心理学的なアプローチは稀である。-ジャック・ヴァレ、『見えない大学』の著者</p><p>「社会学者として、UFO目撃者として、さらに超心理学研究者として、エリック・オイエレットは、私が40年にわたるUFO調査の現場で遭遇した好奇心のバガテルを理解するためのすべての条件を満たしている。- ジェニー・ランドルズ、『マインド・モンスター』の著者</p><p>ERIC OUELLETは、カナダ王立陸軍大学およびカナダ軍大学（カナダの統合幕僚学校および陸軍大学）の国防学教授である。ヨーク大学（カナダ・トロント）で社会学の博士号を取得し、超心理学協会のカナダ担当連絡官を務める。オーストラリアン・ジャーナル・オブ・サイコロジー』、『エッジサイエンス』、『会報Métapsychique』に超心理学的研究を発表している。その他の研究テーマは軍事社会学と戦争研究である。</p><hr><p>What if UFO experiences are the result of large-scale, unconscious, psychic forces?</p><p>Parapsychology and UFOlogy are like oil and water. They just don't mix, despite the decades-long efforts of some highly respected researchers to call attention to the paranormal or parapsychological aspects of UFO events. In Illuminations, sociologist Eric Ouellet offers a novel approach to a phenomenon that has thus far resisted all other efforts to explain it, be it as extraterrestrial craft, time travelers, secret government projects, or natural phenomena.</p><p>Combining research in parapsychology, sociology, and UFOlogy, Ouellet provides a thought provoking reassessment of several well-known UFO cases, including the Washington, DC, UFO wave of 1952, the Betty and Barney Hill abduction of 1961, the Rendlesham UFO incident of 1980, and the Belgian UFO wave of 1989-1991. While not claiming to have the final solution to the UFO mystery, he offers much food for thought and a refreshing outlook on a stubbornly elusive phenomenon.</p><p>"Parapsychological approaches in this field are rare: your contribution is precious, and it is very timely." -Jacques Vallée, author of The Invisible College</p><p>"As a sociologist and a UFO witness, plus, importantly, a parapsychological researcher, Eric Ouellet ticks all the boxes to appreciate the bagatelle of curiosities that I have encountered in the field during 40 years of UFO investigation." - Jenny Randles, author of Mind Monsters</p><p>ERIC OUELLET is professor of Defence Studies at the Royal Military College of Canada, and at the Canadian Forces College (Canada's Joint Staff and War College). He has a Ph.D. in sociology from York University (Toronto, Canada), and he is the liaison officer for Canada with the Parapsychological Association. He has published parapsychological work in the Australian Journal of Psychology, EdgeScience, and the Bulletin Métapsychique. His other research works focus on military sociology and war studies.</p><p>ref: Amazon | Illuminations: The UFO Experience as a Parapsychological Event | Ouellet, Eric | Occult
<a href="https://www.amazon.co.jp/Illuminations-UFO-Experience-Parapsychological-Event/dp/193839853X" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">https://www.amazon.co.jp/Illuminations-UFO-Experience-Parapsychological-Event/dp/193839853X</a></p></blockquote></div></div></details>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="whisper-ailarge-v2-model--deepl">Whisper AI(large-v2 model) + DeepL<a class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Whisper AI(large-v2 model) + DeepL" title="Direct link to Whisper AI(large-v2 model) + DeepL" href="https://ouchaku.github.io/ds/en/blog/2024/07/18/eric_ouellet_belgium_ufo_reason#whisper-ailarge-v2-model--deepl">​</a></h2>
<p>では、苦しんでいるのは誰なのか？
それに関わる中心人物は何だろう？
それはUFO事件における問題の1つだ。
しかし、ベルギーのUFOの波が、ベルリンの壁の崩壊と東欧圏で起こった革命とまったく同じ時期に起こったことを忘れてはならない。
(00:33:35)</p>
<p>だから、東ドイツ、ハンガリー、チェコ共和国、ルーマニアのもっと激しい革命の中にあった。
これらすべてのUFO事件は、まさに同じ時期に起こった。
ベルギーはNATOの国でもある。
政治本部はブリュッセルにある。
軍司令部はブリュッセルからほど近いモンスにある。
そうして、あっという間に人々は、ああ、もうソ連圏はないんだからNATOはもう必要ないんだ、と言い始める。
(00:34:14)</p>
<p>鉄のカーテンの東側にいた人たちは、自国の政府が武力や暴力を使って、みんなを共産主義体制に強制的に戻すのではないかと、とても心配していた。
ある意味、彼らはNATOが関与してくれることを望んでいた。
しかし、彼らは鉄のカーテンの向こう側で立ち往生していたため、話すことができなかった。
(00:34:47)</p>
<p>だからある意味、それがNATOに助けを求める彼らの方法だった。
もちろん、これは推測の域を出ないが、手がかりを得るためには、実際のUFO事件そのものを見なければならない。
(00:35:02)</p>
<hr>
<p>興味深いUFOの説明には、非常に興味深い象徴主義がある。
有名な三角形の物体について考えてみよう。
それらはすべて三角形のそれぞれの角に3つの白い光を持っていて、真ん中に弱い赤い光を持っている。
西側のNATOは白い星、シンボルであり、ソ連圏は赤い星だったことを思い出すと面白い。
(00:35:30)</p>
<p>赤い星が白い星に囲まれている。
それは一つの側面だ。
もう一つの側面は、やはり三角形について話すと、目撃者の記述の多くが、ブリュッセルのNATOビルの前にある金属製の彫刻を彷彿とさせるということだ。
それは黒っぽい金属で、三角形でできている。
つまり、一連の三角形が組み合わさって、NATOの有名なシンボルであるNATOの星を作っているのだ。
(00:36:03)</p>
<p>そしてまた、この並列はとても印象的だ。
繰り返すが、これは象徴的な合図なのだ。
そして、実際の出来事の中には、例えば赤いボールを使ったり、水の中で釣りをしたりするものもある。
つまり、赤い側の人間がカーテンの向こう側から助けを得ようとする。
だから、カーテンの向こう側にいる人たちが、もしかしたらフォーカスされた人物なのかもしれないという方向性を指し示す象徴がいくつもあるんだ。
(00:36:37)</p>
<p>推測の域を出ないが、真剣に考える価値のある別の説明だと思う。
なるほど。
ユングで言うところの集合的無意識のようなものから、これを生み出しているのは社会的グループなんだろうか？
そうだ。
ポルターガイストは非常に小規模な現象だ。
でもUFOも同じようなもので、集団のレベルなんだ。
(00:37:04)</p>
<p>だから国家だ。
だから、フォーカスパーソンというのは、実際にはフォーカスグループ、つまり、話すことができない、とても心配している、あるいはとても深刻な精神的苦痛を持っている人たちのグループで、彼らは同時に集団でそれを共有する。
だから、集合的超心理学的な出来事を活性化させる集合的無意識と呼ぶことができる。
ポルターガイスト』よりも大きなショーになるが、全体的な力学や出来事の全体的な構造は非常に似ている。
(00:37:38)</p>
<p>なるほど。
UFOを見た人が、ドライブ中にUFOを見て、その人に大きな影響を与える。
それはポルターガイストのような出来事に近いだろうか？
というのも、ポルターガイストの定義によれば、数週間から数カ月にわたって繰り返されるものだからだ。
(00:38:08)</p>
<p>というのも、ポルターガイストの定義は、数週間から数ヶ月にわたって繰り返されるものだからだ。
しかし、『ポルターガイスト』の中には超心理学から引き出された要素がある。
つまり、サイコキネシスやマインド・オーバー・マター、超感覚的知覚について考えるなら、非正常的な手段で情報にアクセスすることは、非常に多くの場合、これらの単一の出来事に組み込まれている。
(00:38:36)</p>
<hr>
<p>So that brings us to who would be the people suffering?
What would be the focus persons involved in that?
So there's no obvious one, and that's one of the problem in UFO cases.
It seems to be not apparent, but we have to remember that the UFO wave of Belgium happened exactly at the same time as the fall of the Berlin Wall and all the revolutions that were going in on the Eastern bloc.
(00:33:35)</p>
<p>So in East Germany, Hungary, Czech Republic, it was in the more violent revolution in Romania.
All these UFO events happened exactly at the same time.
And then also we have to remember that Belgium is also the land of NATO.
The political headquarters are in Brussels.
The military headquarters are in Mons, which is just not far from Brussels.
And so, and very quickly, people start to ask, oh, you know, there's no more Soviet bloc, so there's no need for NATO anymore.
(00:34:14)</p>
<p>And so, wondering if there's people on the Eastern side of the Iron Curtain that was very worried that the government of their countries might use force and violence to force back everybody into a communist regime.
And in a way, they were hoping that NATO does, gets involved.
But they couldn't speak because, you know, they were stuck in the other side of the Iron Curtain.
(00:34:47)</p>
<p>And so, in a way, that was their way to call for help to NATO.
Now, this is very speculative, of course, but we have to look at the actual UFO event itself for some clues.
(00:35:02)</p>
<hr>
<p>Some of the interesting UFO description is there's some very interesting symbolism in it.
We think about the famous triangular objects.
They all have three white lights at each of the corner of the triangle and a weak red light in the middle.
It's interesting to remember that NATO in the West is a white star, the symbol, and the Soviet bloc, it was a red star.
(00:35:30)</p>
<p>So as if the red star was surrounded by a white star.
That's one aspect.
The other dimension of it, again, if we talk about the triangles, is a lot of descriptions of the objects from the witnesses is very reminiscent of a metal sculpture in front of the NATO building in Brussels.
And that's dark metal and made of triangles.
So a series of triangles together that makes the star of NATO, the famous symbol of NATO.
(00:36:03)</p>
<p>And again, the parallel is very striking.
So again, maybe it's a symbolic cue towards that.
And some of the actual events involve, for instance, using red balls, fishing in water.
So again, this notion that people from the red side try to get help from the other side of the curtain.
So there's a number of symbolism that points in the direction that maybe people on the other side of the curtain were the focus person.
(00:36:37)</p>
<p>So speculative, yes, but I think it's an alternative explanation that worth considering seriously.
Okay.
Now, would it be maybe a social group that's sort of generating this out of like a collective unconscious as Jung would say?
Yes.
So, Poltergeist is a very small scale event.
It's a family very often, but UFO would be the same thing, but at the level of the collective.
(00:37:04)</p>
<p>So a nation.
So the focus person would actually be a focus group, a group of people who have, who can't speak and that they're very worried or they have very serious psychological pain that they share collectively at the same time.
So yes, we can call it some sort of collective unconscious that activates some sort of collective parapsychological event.
And so that's, it becomes a bigger show than a family Poltergeist, but the overall dynamics or the overall structure of events is very similar.
(00:37:38)</p>
<p>Okay.
Now that's for a UFO way for a singular sighting, like someone out driving along, sees a UFO and it has a profound effect on them.
Would that be closer to like a Poltergeist event happening with that one person?
I would say that the Poltergeist model to look at those single events, probably not the good way to approach it because by definition of Poltergeist is something that repeats itself for a few weeks, a few months.
(00:38:08)</p>
<p>And so in that case, I would not say that it's the good model.
However, there are sub elements within Poltergeist drawn from parapsychology.
So if we think about psychokinesis or mind over matter or extrasensory perception, so accessing information through non-normal means that are very often embedded into those single events.
(00:38:36)</p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="コメント">コメント<a class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to コメント" title="Direct link to コメント" href="https://ouchaku.github.io/ds/en/blog/2024/07/18/eric_ouellet_belgium_ufo_reason#%E3%82%B3%E3%83%A1%E3%83%B3%E3%83%88">​</a></h2>
<p>私は一部の例外を除き、大半の社会学者の主張は評価できないが、その理由はこのような融通無限な「社会学的」見解が横行しているから。</p>
<p>「三箇所の頂点に白、中央に赤のライト」がある三角形型 UFO はアメリカでも頻繁に目撃されている。そして一般のアメリカ人は EU なんて眼中にない。ゆえに Eric Ouellet のこの説明は破綻している。良く言っても こじつけ が過ぎる。</p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="動画12859">動画(1:28:59)<a class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to 動画(1:28:59)" title="Direct link to 動画(1:28:59)" href="https://ouchaku.github.io/ds/en/blog/2024/07/18/eric_ouellet_belgium_ufo_reason#%E5%8B%95%E7%94%BB12859">​</a></h2>
<p>UFO's and Poltergeists with Eric Ouellet - July 11, 2024</p>
<iframe width="560" height="315" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/dPBHw12YCuU?si=Frq8sayKRIHGwgI5" title="YouTube video player" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin"></iframe>
<p><a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=dPBHw12YCuU" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">www.youtube.com/watch?v=dPBHw12YCuU</a></p>
<h3 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="動画概要欄">動画概要欄<a class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to 動画概要欄" title="Direct link to 動画概要欄" href="https://ouchaku.github.io/ds/en/blog/2024/07/18/eric_ouellet_belgium_ufo_reason#%E5%8B%95%E7%94%BB%E6%A6%82%E8%A6%81%E6%AC%84">​</a></h3>
<p>1,700 views  Jul 15, 2024  2024 Shows
Originally aired on April 2, 2016</p>
<p>Since I reference this book a lot, I felt it was time to remaster and re-upload this show, with it's short Patreon segment as well.</p>
<p>Eric Ouellet joins me for a fascinating discussion of his new book, Illuminations: The UFO Experience as a Parapsychological Event. He proposes that we should examine the UFO Phenomenon as we would a poltergeist case. It's a novel way of looking at it, and may ultimately play a part in solving this enigma.</p>
<p>ERIC OUELLET is professor of Defence Studies at the Royal Military College of Canada, and at the Canadian Forces College (Canada's Joint Staff and War College). He has a Ph.D. in sociology from York University (Toronto, Canada), and he is the liaison officer for Canada with the Parapsychological Association. He has published parapsychological work in the Australian Journal of Psychology, EdgeScience, and the Bulletin Métapsychique. His other research works focus on military sociology and war studies.</p>
<p>(2024-07-18)</p>]]></content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Eric Ouellet：Betty/Barney Hill は事件前にテレパシーの実験をした]]></title>
        <id>https://ouchaku.github.io/ds/en/blog/2024/07/18/eric_ouellet_betty_hill_teltepathy</id>
        <link href="https://ouchaku.github.io/ds/en/blog/2024/07/18/eric_ouellet_betty_hill_teltepathy"/>
        <updated>2024-07-18T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[前置き]]></summary>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="前置き">前置き<a class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to 前置き" title="Direct link to 前置き" href="https://ouchaku.github.io/ds/en/blog/2024/07/18/eric_ouellet_betty_hill_teltepathy#%E5%89%8D%E7%BD%AE%E3%81%8D">​</a></h2>
<p>Eric Ouellet はカナダの社会学者で</p>
<p>Eric Ouellet, "Illuminations: The UFO Experience as a Parapsychological", Anomalist Books, 2015</p>
<p>という「UFO はポルターガイスト現象だ」という趣旨の著書(*1)も出している。彼のインタビュー動画からタイトルの件に絞る。</p>
<h3 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="1">(*1)<a class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to (*1)" title="Direct link to (*1)" href="https://ouchaku.github.io/ds/en/blog/2024/07/18/eric_ouellet_betty_hill_teltepathy#1">​</a></h3>
<details class="details_lb9f alert alert--info details_b_Ee" data-collapsed="true"><summary>▼展開</summary><div><div class="collapsibleContent_i85q"><blockquote><a href="https://ouchaku.github.io/ds/img/20240718_book.jpg" target="_blank"><img alt="20240718_book.jpg" border="0" src="https://ouchaku.github.io/ds/img/20240718_book.jpg" width="90%"></a><p>UFO体験が無意識の大規模な超能力の結果だとしたら？</p><p>超心理学とUFO学は油と水のようなものだ。何十年もの間、高名な研究者たちがUFO現象の超常現象や超心理学的側面に注目しようと努力してきたにもかかわらず、両者は混じり合わないのだ。社会学者エリック・オイエレットは『イルミネーションズ』の中で、地球外生命体、タイムトラベラー、政府の秘密プロジェクト、自然現象など、これまで説明しようとするあらゆる努力に抵抗してきたこの現象に、斬新なアプローチを提供している。</p><p>超心理学、社会学、UFO学の研究を組み合わせ、オイエレットは、1952年のワシントンDCのUFOの波、1961年のベティとバーニー・ヒル誘拐事件、1980年のレンデルシャムUFO事件、1989年から1991年のベルギーのUFOの波など、いくつかの有名なUFO事件の再評価を示唆する。UFOの謎に対する最終的な解決策を持っていると主張するわけではないが、彼は、頑固なまでにとらえどころのない現象に対して、多くの考える材料と新鮮な展望を提供している。</p><p>「この分野における超心理学的なアプローチは稀である。-ジャック・ヴァレ、『見えない大学』の著者</p><p>「社会学者として、UFO目撃者として、さらに超心理学研究者として、エリック・オイエレットは、私が40年にわたるUFO調査の現場で遭遇した好奇心のバガテルを理解するためのすべての条件を満たしている。- ジェニー・ランドルズ、『マインド・モンスター』の著者</p><p>ERIC OUELLETは、カナダ王立陸軍大学およびカナダ軍大学（カナダの統合幕僚学校および陸軍大学）の国防学教授である。ヨーク大学（カナダ・トロント）で社会学の博士号を取得し、超心理学協会のカナダ担当連絡官を務める。オーストラリアン・ジャーナル・オブ・サイコロジー』、『エッジサイエンス』、『会報Métapsychique』に超心理学的研究を発表している。その他の研究テーマは軍事社会学と戦争研究である。</p><hr><p>What if UFO experiences are the result of large-scale, unconscious, psychic forces?</p><p>Parapsychology and UFOlogy are like oil and water. They just don't mix, despite the decades-long efforts of some highly respected researchers to call attention to the paranormal or parapsychological aspects of UFO events. In Illuminations, sociologist Eric Ouellet offers a novel approach to a phenomenon that has thus far resisted all other efforts to explain it, be it as extraterrestrial craft, time travelers, secret government projects, or natural phenomena.</p><p>Combining research in parapsychology, sociology, and UFOlogy, Ouellet provides a thought provoking reassessment of several well-known UFO cases, including the Washington, DC, UFO wave of 1952, the Betty and Barney Hill abduction of 1961, the Rendlesham UFO incident of 1980, and the Belgian UFO wave of 1989-1991. While not claiming to have the final solution to the UFO mystery, he offers much food for thought and a refreshing outlook on a stubbornly elusive phenomenon.</p><p>"Parapsychological approaches in this field are rare: your contribution is precious, and it is very timely." -Jacques Vallée, author of The Invisible College</p><p>"As a sociologist and a UFO witness, plus, importantly, a parapsychological researcher, Eric Ouellet ticks all the boxes to appreciate the bagatelle of curiosities that I have encountered in the field during 40 years of UFO investigation." - Jenny Randles, author of Mind Monsters</p><p>ERIC OUELLET is professor of Defence Studies at the Royal Military College of Canada, and at the Canadian Forces College (Canada's Joint Staff and War College). He has a Ph.D. in sociology from York University (Toronto, Canada), and he is the liaison officer for Canada with the Parapsychological Association. He has published parapsychological work in the Australian Journal of Psychology, EdgeScience, and the Bulletin Métapsychique. His other research works focus on military sociology and war studies.</p><p>ref: Amazon | Illuminations: The UFO Experience as a Parapsychological Event | Ouellet, Eric | Occult
<a href="https://www.amazon.co.jp/Illuminations-UFO-Experience-Parapsychological-Event/dp/193839853X" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">https://www.amazon.co.jp/Illuminations-UFO-Experience-Parapsychological-Event/dp/193839853X</a></p></blockquote></div></div></details>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="whisper-ailarge-v2-model--deepl">Whisper AI(large-v2 model) + DeepL<a class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Whisper AI(large-v2 model) + DeepL" title="Direct link to Whisper AI(large-v2 model) + DeepL" href="https://ouchaku.github.io/ds/en/blog/2024/07/18/eric_ouellet_betty_hill_teltepathy#whisper-ailarge-v2-model--deepl">​</a></h2>
<p>ケネス・リングがオメガ・プロジェクトで臨死体験やUFOとの接触の後遺症について研究したように、最初の遭遇の後にも多くの超常現象が起こっていることを発見したんだ。
その通りだ。
そして、純粋に、物理的に、厳密に物理的なUFO体験をしたと思われる人たちでさえ、実際にはあらゆる種類の超常現象に巻き込まれている。
(00:25:34)</p>
<p>バーニーとベティ・ヒルの有名なケースは、多くの人が知らないことだけど、彼らはその出来事の前に、実は夫婦でテレパシーの練習をしていたんだ。
だから、彼らはすでに超心理学に興味を持っていた。
そしてその後、彼らにも奇妙なことがいくつか起こった。
だから、このような事件でさえも、一見単純明快に見えるが、実は忘れてはならない別の側面があるのだ。
(00:26:07)</p>
<hr>
<p>And I know like Kenneth Ring did his study on the Omega Project, looking at the after effects of near-death experiences and UFO contact and found that very same thing, that there's a lot of paranormal stuff going on after the initial encounter.
That's correct.
And even people that we think that had a purely, I would say, physical, strictly physical UFO experience, they are actually mixed up with all kinds of paranormal event.
(00:25:34)</p>
<p>The famous case of Barney and Betty Hill, something that a lot of people don't really know is that they had before the event, they're actually practicing telepathy as a couple.
So already they had an interest in the parapsychology.
And then afterward, they had a few weird things happening to them as well, so that they mentioned.
So even a case like that, that seems to be so nuts and bolts, there's actually other aspects to it that we should not forget.
(00:26:07)</p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="動画12859">動画(1:28:59)<a class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to 動画(1:28:59)" title="Direct link to 動画(1:28:59)" href="https://ouchaku.github.io/ds/en/blog/2024/07/18/eric_ouellet_betty_hill_teltepathy#%E5%8B%95%E7%94%BB12859">​</a></h2>
<p>UFO's and Poltergeists with Eric Ouellet - July 11, 2024</p>
<iframe width="560" height="315" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/dPBHw12YCuU?si=Frq8sayKRIHGwgI5" title="YouTube video player" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin"></iframe>
<p><a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=dPBHw12YCuU" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">www.youtube.com/watch?v=dPBHw12YCuU</a></p>
<h3 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="動画概要欄">動画概要欄<a class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to 動画概要欄" title="Direct link to 動画概要欄" href="https://ouchaku.github.io/ds/en/blog/2024/07/18/eric_ouellet_betty_hill_teltepathy#%E5%8B%95%E7%94%BB%E6%A6%82%E8%A6%81%E6%AC%84">​</a></h3>
<p>1,700 views  Jul 15, 2024  2024 Shows
Originally aired on April 2, 2016</p>
<p>Since I reference this book a lot, I felt it was time to remaster and re-upload this show, with it's short Patreon segment as well.</p>
<p>Eric Ouellet joins me for a fascinating discussion of his new book, Illuminations: The UFO Experience as a Parapsychological Event. He proposes that we should examine the UFO Phenomenon as we would a poltergeist case. It's a novel way of looking at it, and may ultimately play a part in solving this enigma.</p>
<p>ERIC OUELLET is professor of Defence Studies at the Royal Military College of Canada, and at the Canadian Forces College (Canada's Joint Staff and War College). He has a Ph.D. in sociology from York University (Toronto, Canada), and he is the liaison officer for Canada with the Parapsychological Association. He has published parapsychological work in the Australian Journal of Psychology, EdgeScience, and the Bulletin Métapsychique. His other research works focus on military sociology and war studies.</p>
<p>(2024-07-18)</p>]]></content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Eric Ouellet：EMF と脳は、互いに双方向に影響している]]></title>
        <id>https://ouchaku.github.io/ds/en/blog/2024/07/18/eric_ouellet_emf_brain_bi_directional_affect</id>
        <link href="https://ouchaku.github.io/ds/en/blog/2024/07/18/eric_ouellet_emf_brain_bi_directional_affect"/>
        <updated>2024-07-18T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[前置き]]></summary>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="前置き">前置き<a class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to 前置き" title="Direct link to 前置き" href="https://ouchaku.github.io/ds/en/blog/2024/07/18/eric_ouellet_emf_brain_bi_directional_affect#%E5%89%8D%E7%BD%AE%E3%81%8D">​</a></h2>
<p>Eric Ouellet はカナダの社会学者で</p>
<p>Eric Ouellet, "Illuminations: The UFO Experience as a Parapsychological", Anomalist Books, 2015</p>
<p>という「UFO はポルターガイスト現象だ」という趣旨の著書(*1)も出している。彼のインタビュー動画からタイトルの件に絞る。</p>
<h3 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="1">(*1)<a class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to (*1)" title="Direct link to (*1)" href="https://ouchaku.github.io/ds/en/blog/2024/07/18/eric_ouellet_emf_brain_bi_directional_affect#1">​</a></h3>
<details class="details_lb9f alert alert--info details_b_Ee" data-collapsed="true"><summary>▼展開</summary><div><div class="collapsibleContent_i85q"><blockquote><a href="https://ouchaku.github.io/ds/img/20240718_book.jpg" target="_blank"><img alt="20240718_book.jpg" border="0" src="https://ouchaku.github.io/ds/img/20240718_book.jpg" width="90%"></a><p>UFO体験が無意識の大規模な超能力の結果だとしたら？</p><p>超心理学とUFO学は油と水のようなものだ。何十年もの間、高名な研究者たちがUFO現象の超常現象や超心理学的側面に注目しようと努力してきたにもかかわらず、両者は混じり合わないのだ。社会学者エリック・オイエレットは『イルミネーションズ』の中で、地球外生命体、タイムトラベラー、政府の秘密プロジェクト、自然現象など、これまで説明しようとするあらゆる努力に抵抗してきたこの現象に、斬新なアプローチを提供している。</p><p>超心理学、社会学、UFO学の研究を組み合わせ、オイエレットは、1952年のワシントンDCのUFOの波、1961年のベティとバーニー・ヒル誘拐事件、1980年のレンデルシャムUFO事件、1989年から1991年のベルギーのUFOの波など、いくつかの有名なUFO事件の再評価を示唆する。UFOの謎に対する最終的な解決策を持っていると主張するわけではないが、彼は、頑固なまでにとらえどころのない現象に対して、多くの考える材料と新鮮な展望を提供している。</p><p>「この分野における超心理学的なアプローチは稀である。-ジャック・ヴァレ、『見えない大学』の著者</p><p>「社会学者として、UFO目撃者として、さらに超心理学研究者として、エリック・オイエレットは、私が40年にわたるUFO調査の現場で遭遇した好奇心のバガテルを理解するためのすべての条件を満たしている。- ジェニー・ランドルズ、『マインド・モンスター』の著者</p><p>ERIC OUELLETは、カナダ王立陸軍大学およびカナダ軍大学（カナダの統合幕僚学校および陸軍大学）の国防学教授である。ヨーク大学（カナダ・トロント）で社会学の博士号を取得し、超心理学協会のカナダ担当連絡官を務める。オーストラリアン・ジャーナル・オブ・サイコロジー』、『エッジサイエンス』、『会報Métapsychique』に超心理学的研究を発表している。その他の研究テーマは軍事社会学と戦争研究である。</p><hr><p>What if UFO experiences are the result of large-scale, unconscious, psychic forces?</p><p>Parapsychology and UFOlogy are like oil and water. They just don't mix, despite the decades-long efforts of some highly respected researchers to call attention to the paranormal or parapsychological aspects of UFO events. In Illuminations, sociologist Eric Ouellet offers a novel approach to a phenomenon that has thus far resisted all other efforts to explain it, be it as extraterrestrial craft, time travelers, secret government projects, or natural phenomena.</p><p>Combining research in parapsychology, sociology, and UFOlogy, Ouellet provides a thought provoking reassessment of several well-known UFO cases, including the Washington, DC, UFO wave of 1952, the Betty and Barney Hill abduction of 1961, the Rendlesham UFO incident of 1980, and the Belgian UFO wave of 1989-1991. While not claiming to have the final solution to the UFO mystery, he offers much food for thought and a refreshing outlook on a stubbornly elusive phenomenon.</p><p>"Parapsychological approaches in this field are rare: your contribution is precious, and it is very timely." -Jacques Vallée, author of The Invisible College</p><p>"As a sociologist and a UFO witness, plus, importantly, a parapsychological researcher, Eric Ouellet ticks all the boxes to appreciate the bagatelle of curiosities that I have encountered in the field during 40 years of UFO investigation." - Jenny Randles, author of Mind Monsters</p><p>ERIC OUELLET is professor of Defence Studies at the Royal Military College of Canada, and at the Canadian Forces College (Canada's Joint Staff and War College). He has a Ph.D. in sociology from York University (Toronto, Canada), and he is the liaison officer for Canada with the Parapsychological Association. He has published parapsychological work in the Australian Journal of Psychology, EdgeScience, and the Bulletin Métapsychique. His other research works focus on military sociology and war studies.</p><p>ref: Amazon | Illuminations: The UFO Experience as a Parapsychological Event | Ouellet, Eric | Occult
<a href="https://www.amazon.co.jp/Illuminations-UFO-Experience-Parapsychological-Event/dp/193839853X" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">https://www.amazon.co.jp/Illuminations-UFO-Experience-Parapsychological-Event/dp/193839853X</a></p></blockquote></div></div></details>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="whisper-ailarge-v2-model--deepl">Whisper AI(large-v2 model) + DeepL<a class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Whisper AI(large-v2 model) + DeepL" title="Direct link to Whisper AI(large-v2 model) + DeepL" href="https://ouchaku.github.io/ds/en/blog/2024/07/18/eric_ouellet_emf_brain_bi_directional_affect#whisper-ailarge-v2-model--deepl">​</a></h2>
<p>では、UFOに関係する電磁気学について話そう。
これはどのように関係するのだろうか？
まあ、過去に行われた研究は、超心理学的な能力は、通常、無意識的な精神的プロセスと結びついていることを示しているようだが、なんというか、電磁気学はある場面で、私たちが意識変容状態と呼んでいるものを作り出す。
(00:51:37)</p>
<p>つまり、ちょっとしたトランス状態、あるいはオフの状態だ。
そして、意識はある種傍らにあり、無意識はある種前の席に行くから、超心理学的な能力がより効果的に起こる可能性があるんだ。
そういう側面もある。
もう一つは、人間の心は電磁気システムと相互作用することができるようだ。
(00:52:05)</p>
<p>ポルターガイスト現象では、電気機器がある特定の行動をとることに気づく。
例えば、電球が破裂する。
また、ポール・デ・リューの研究によると、彼は地球の光を非常に近くから見たという。
そして、ある特定の方向に行こうと考えていたら、実際にその特定の方向に行ったという。
(00:52:44)</p>
<p>あるいは、ある行動を取ると思っていたら、その行動を取り始めた。
つまり、電磁気には双方向性があるということだ。
つまり、電磁気は私たちの脳に影響を及ぼしてトランス状態にさせ、幻覚を見せることもあるのだ。
(00:53:01)</p>
<hr>
<p>でも、電磁気システムに影響を与えることもできるようだ。
この現象全体に対する非常に興味深いアプローチだね。
UFOの報告中に車がエンストしたりするのと同じ理由だと思う？
そうだと思う。
それと大いに関係があると思う。
特に地球の光があると、電気系統が電磁気によって妨害されるんだ。
(00:53:28)</p>
<p>あるいはサイコキネシスかもしれない。
関係者が電気系統に影響を与えるんだ。</p>
<hr>
<p>So today's, it's hard to assess if there's more UFOs because of the capacity to assess the reporting is weaker now than it was in the past.
Okay, let's talk about the electromagnetism that's connected with UFOs.
How does this play in?
Well, the research done in the past seems to indicate that parapsychological abilities, which are usually linked to unconscious mental processes, are more, how can I say, electromagnetism in some occasions creates what we call altered states of consciousness.
(00:51:37)</p>
<p>So you're a little bit in trance or you're off.
And because your conscious mind is kind of on the side and your unconscious mind kind of goes to the front seat, then there's a possibility that those parapsychological capacities more effectively happening.
So that's one aspect.
The other one also is that it seems that the human mind is able to interact with electromagnetic systems.
(00:52:05)</p>
<p>We notice in poltergeist events that the electrical equipment seems to behave in certain ways that, let's say, angry because the person, the focus person is angry.
So you will have light bulbs bursting, for instance.
Also, Paul De Rue in his research said that he saw one of those earth lights from very close.
And when he was thinking of it to go in a particular direction, it was actually going that particular direction.
(00:52:44)</p>
<p>Or if he was thinking of it having a certain behavior, it started to have this behavior.
So it seems that the electromagnetism has a two-way street.
So they influence our brain to make us go into a state of trance, and then we may have some hallucinations.
(00:53:01)</p>
<hr>
<p>But also, it seems that we can influence those electromagnetic systems.
So that's a very interesting approach to the whole phenomenon.
So you think this would be the same reason like cars stall out during UFO reports and such?
I think so.
I think that has a lot to do with that.
And especially if you do have earth light, the electrical systems will be disturbed by the electromagnetism.
(00:53:28)</p>
<p>Or it could be a psychokinesis.
So the person involved does influence the electrical system.</p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="動画12859">動画(1:28:59)<a class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to 動画(1:28:59)" title="Direct link to 動画(1:28:59)" href="https://ouchaku.github.io/ds/en/blog/2024/07/18/eric_ouellet_emf_brain_bi_directional_affect#%E5%8B%95%E7%94%BB12859">​</a></h2>
<p>UFO's and Poltergeists with Eric Ouellet - July 11, 2024</p>
<iframe width="560" height="315" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/dPBHw12YCuU?si=Frq8sayKRIHGwgI5" title="YouTube video player" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin"></iframe>
<p><a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=dPBHw12YCuU" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">www.youtube.com/watch?v=dPBHw12YCuU</a></p>
<h3 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="動画概要欄">動画概要欄<a class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to 動画概要欄" title="Direct link to 動画概要欄" href="https://ouchaku.github.io/ds/en/blog/2024/07/18/eric_ouellet_emf_brain_bi_directional_affect#%E5%8B%95%E7%94%BB%E6%A6%82%E8%A6%81%E6%AC%84">​</a></h3>
<p>1,700 views  Jul 15, 2024  2024 Shows
Originally aired on April 2, 2016</p>
<p>Since I reference this book a lot, I felt it was time to remaster and re-upload this show, with it's short Patreon segment as well.</p>
<p>Eric Ouellet joins me for a fascinating discussion of his new book, Illuminations: The UFO Experience as a Parapsychological Event. He proposes that we should examine the UFO Phenomenon as we would a poltergeist case. It's a novel way of looking at it, and may ultimately play a part in solving this enigma.</p>
<p>ERIC OUELLET is professor of Defence Studies at the Royal Military College of Canada, and at the Canadian Forces College (Canada's Joint Staff and War College). He has a Ph.D. in sociology from York University (Toronto, Canada), and he is the liaison officer for Canada with the Parapsychological Association. He has published parapsychological work in the Australian Journal of Psychology, EdgeScience, and the Bulletin Métapsychique. His other research works focus on military sociology and war studies.</p>
<p>(2024-07-18)</p>]]></content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Eric Ouellet：磁界の影響で ESP 能力が高まるという説がある]]></title>
        <id>https://ouchaku.github.io/ds/en/blog/2024/07/18/eric_ouellet_magnetic_esp</id>
        <link href="https://ouchaku.github.io/ds/en/blog/2024/07/18/eric_ouellet_magnetic_esp"/>
        <updated>2024-07-18T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[前置き]]></summary>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="前置き">前置き<a class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to 前置き" title="Direct link to 前置き" href="https://ouchaku.github.io/ds/en/blog/2024/07/18/eric_ouellet_magnetic_esp#%E5%89%8D%E7%BD%AE%E3%81%8D">​</a></h2>
<p>Eric Ouellet はカナダの社会学者で</p>
<p>Eric Ouellet, "Illuminations: The UFO Experience as a Parapsychological", Anomalist Books, 2015</p>
<p>という「UFO はポルターガイスト現象だ」という趣旨の著書(*1)も出している。彼のインタビュー動画からタイトルの件に絞る。</p>
<h3 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="1">(*1)<a class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to (*1)" title="Direct link to (*1)" href="https://ouchaku.github.io/ds/en/blog/2024/07/18/eric_ouellet_magnetic_esp#1">​</a></h3>
<details class="details_lb9f alert alert--info details_b_Ee" data-collapsed="true"><summary>▼展開</summary><div><div class="collapsibleContent_i85q"><blockquote><a href="https://ouchaku.github.io/ds/img/20240718_book.jpg" target="_blank"><img alt="20240718_book.jpg" border="0" src="https://ouchaku.github.io/ds/img/20240718_book.jpg" width="90%"></a><p>UFO体験が無意識の大規模な超能力の結果だとしたら？</p><p>超心理学とUFO学は油と水のようなものだ。何十年もの間、高名な研究者たちがUFO現象の超常現象や超心理学的側面に注目しようと努力してきたにもかかわらず、両者は混じり合わないのだ。社会学者エリック・オイエレットは『イルミネーションズ』の中で、地球外生命体、タイムトラベラー、政府の秘密プロジェクト、自然現象など、これまで説明しようとするあらゆる努力に抵抗してきたこの現象に、斬新なアプローチを提供している。</p><p>超心理学、社会学、UFO学の研究を組み合わせ、オイエレットは、1952年のワシントンDCのUFOの波、1961年のベティとバーニー・ヒル誘拐事件、1980年のレンデルシャムUFO事件、1989年から1991年のベルギーのUFOの波など、いくつかの有名なUFO事件の再評価を示唆する。UFOの謎に対する最終的な解決策を持っていると主張するわけではないが、彼は、頑固なまでにとらえどころのない現象に対して、多くの考える材料と新鮮な展望を提供している。</p><p>「この分野における超心理学的なアプローチは稀である。-ジャック・ヴァレ、『見えない大学』の著者</p><p>「社会学者として、UFO目撃者として、さらに超心理学研究者として、エリック・オイエレットは、私が40年にわたるUFO調査の現場で遭遇した好奇心のバガテルを理解するためのすべての条件を満たしている。- ジェニー・ランドルズ、『マインド・モンスター』の著者</p><p>ERIC OUELLETは、カナダ王立陸軍大学およびカナダ軍大学（カナダの統合幕僚学校および陸軍大学）の国防学教授である。ヨーク大学（カナダ・トロント）で社会学の博士号を取得し、超心理学協会のカナダ担当連絡官を務める。オーストラリアン・ジャーナル・オブ・サイコロジー』、『エッジサイエンス』、『会報Métapsychique』に超心理学的研究を発表している。その他の研究テーマは軍事社会学と戦争研究である。</p><hr><p>What if UFO experiences are the result of large-scale, unconscious, psychic forces?</p><p>Parapsychology and UFOlogy are like oil and water. They just don't mix, despite the decades-long efforts of some highly respected researchers to call attention to the paranormal or parapsychological aspects of UFO events. In Illuminations, sociologist Eric Ouellet offers a novel approach to a phenomenon that has thus far resisted all other efforts to explain it, be it as extraterrestrial craft, time travelers, secret government projects, or natural phenomena.</p><p>Combining research in parapsychology, sociology, and UFOlogy, Ouellet provides a thought provoking reassessment of several well-known UFO cases, including the Washington, DC, UFO wave of 1952, the Betty and Barney Hill abduction of 1961, the Rendlesham UFO incident of 1980, and the Belgian UFO wave of 1989-1991. While not claiming to have the final solution to the UFO mystery, he offers much food for thought and a refreshing outlook on a stubbornly elusive phenomenon.</p><p>"Parapsychological approaches in this field are rare: your contribution is precious, and it is very timely." -Jacques Vallée, author of The Invisible College</p><p>"As a sociologist and a UFO witness, plus, importantly, a parapsychological researcher, Eric Ouellet ticks all the boxes to appreciate the bagatelle of curiosities that I have encountered in the field during 40 years of UFO investigation." - Jenny Randles, author of Mind Monsters</p><p>ERIC OUELLET is professor of Defence Studies at the Royal Military College of Canada, and at the Canadian Forces College (Canada's Joint Staff and War College). He has a Ph.D. in sociology from York University (Toronto, Canada), and he is the liaison officer for Canada with the Parapsychological Association. He has published parapsychological work in the Australian Journal of Psychology, EdgeScience, and the Bulletin Métapsychique. His other research works focus on military sociology and war studies.</p><p>ref: Amazon | Illuminations: The UFO Experience as a Parapsychological Event | Ouellet, Eric | Occult
<a href="https://www.amazon.co.jp/Illuminations-UFO-Experience-Parapsychological-Event/dp/193839853X" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">https://www.amazon.co.jp/Illuminations-UFO-Experience-Parapsychological-Event/dp/193839853X</a></p></blockquote></div></div></details>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="whisper-ailarge-v2-model--deepl">Whisper AI(large-v2 model) + DeepL<a class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Whisper AI(large-v2 model) + DeepL" title="Direct link to Whisper AI(large-v2 model) + DeepL" href="https://ouchaku.github.io/ds/en/blog/2024/07/18/eric_ouellet_magnetic_esp#whisper-ailarge-v2-model--deepl">​</a></h2>
<p>実は、プラズマと地球の光について尋ねようと思っていたんだ。
(00:47:05)</p>
<p>つまり、他にどのように、それらがこの全体的なことに関与しているのか？
まあ、それがすべてを説明するとは思わないけど、より物理的なもの、あるいは簡単に実証できる物理的な側面があるものは、もっと大きな役割を果たしていると思うよ。
つまり、それについては多くの研究がなされていて、それらが犯人であることがますます明らかになってきているんだ。
(00:47:24)</p>
<p>つまり、1980年代にポール・デリューがそのことについて主要な本を書いた。
彼は、彼らが世界でいかに重要な役割を果たしているかを示すことができたと思う。
知覚というのは、彼らが常に存在しているという意味ではない。
彼らの他の側面として、彼らは非常に強く磁化されているため、私たちが彼らの近くにいるとき、彼らは私たちの脳に影響を与えるようだ。
(00:47:52)</p>
<p>(00:47:00)そして、いくつかの研究によると、超常現象や超心理学的な能力は、超常現象や超心理学的な能力はわからないが、サイコキネシスやテレパシーやそのようなものは、より多く、私たちは多くの磁気にさらされているときに、これらのタイプの経験をする傾向があるようだ。
つまり、知覚、電磁気、地球の光とUFO現象には関係があるようだ。
(00:48:31)</p>
<p>多くの場合、それらはつながっているようだ。
常にそうだとは言わないが、多くの場合、非常に奇妙なUFO体験を生み出す条件の結びつきを見ることができる。</p>
<hr>
<p>I was actually just going to ask you about plasma and earth lights.
(00:47:05)</p>
<p>I mean, how else, how more do they play a part in this whole thing?
Well, I don't think they explain everything, but the ones that are more physical or easily demonstrable physical aspects to them, I'm sure they play a much bigger role.
I mean, a lot of research has been done about that and we see more and more that they are the culprit.
(00:47:24)</p>
<p>I mean, there is a Paul DeRue made the major books on that in the 1980s.
And I think he was able to show that how important they play a role in the world.
Perception doesn't mean they are present all the time.
The other aspects of them also is that because they are so highly magnetized, they seem to when we're close to them, seems to have an impact on our brain.
(00:47:52)</p>
<p>And some research shows that the paranormal or parapsychological capacity, so I don't know the paranormal or parapsychological capacity, so either psychokinesis or telepathy and things like that, seems to be more, we seem to be more prone to have these types of experiences when we're under a lot of magnetism.
So again, it seems that there is a relationship between perceptions, electromagnetism, earth lights and UFO events.
(00:48:31)</p>
<p>They seem to connect in a number of cases.
I'm not saying they're there all the time, but in a number of cases, we can see that nexus of conditions to create a very weird UFO experience.</p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="動画12859">動画(1:28:59)<a class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to 動画(1:28:59)" title="Direct link to 動画(1:28:59)" href="https://ouchaku.github.io/ds/en/blog/2024/07/18/eric_ouellet_magnetic_esp#%E5%8B%95%E7%94%BB12859">​</a></h2>
<p>UFO's and Poltergeists with Eric Ouellet - July 11, 2024</p>
<iframe width="560" height="315" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/dPBHw12YCuU?si=Frq8sayKRIHGwgI5" title="YouTube video player" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin"></iframe>
<p><a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=dPBHw12YCuU" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">www.youtube.com/watch?v=dPBHw12YCuU</a></p>
<h3 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="動画概要欄">動画概要欄<a class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to 動画概要欄" title="Direct link to 動画概要欄" href="https://ouchaku.github.io/ds/en/blog/2024/07/18/eric_ouellet_magnetic_esp#%E5%8B%95%E7%94%BB%E6%A6%82%E8%A6%81%E6%AC%84">​</a></h3>
<p>1,700 views  Jul 15, 2024  2024 Shows
Originally aired on April 2, 2016</p>
<p>Since I reference this book a lot, I felt it was time to remaster and re-upload this show, with it's short Patreon segment as well.</p>
<p>Eric Ouellet joins me for a fascinating discussion of his new book, Illuminations: The UFO Experience as a Parapsychological Event. He proposes that we should examine the UFO Phenomenon as we would a poltergeist case. It's a novel way of looking at it, and may ultimately play a part in solving this enigma.</p>
<p>ERIC OUELLET is professor of Defence Studies at the Royal Military College of Canada, and at the Canadian Forces College (Canada's Joint Staff and War College). He has a Ph.D. in sociology from York University (Toronto, Canada), and he is the liaison officer for Canada with the Parapsychological Association. He has published parapsychological work in the Australian Journal of Psychology, EdgeScience, and the Bulletin Métapsychique. His other research works focus on military sociology and war studies.</p>
<p>(2024-07-18)</p>]]></content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Eric Ouellet：原発周辺に UFO が出現する理由は原発の磁気だ]]></title>
        <id>https://ouchaku.github.io/ds/en/blog/2024/07/18/eric_ouellet_neclearr_powerplant_magnetic</id>
        <link href="https://ouchaku.github.io/ds/en/blog/2024/07/18/eric_ouellet_neclearr_powerplant_magnetic"/>
        <updated>2024-07-18T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[前置き]]></summary>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="前置き">前置き<a class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to 前置き" title="Direct link to 前置き" href="https://ouchaku.github.io/ds/en/blog/2024/07/18/eric_ouellet_neclearr_powerplant_magnetic#%E5%89%8D%E7%BD%AE%E3%81%8D">​</a></h2>
<p>Eric Ouellet はカナダの社会学者で</p>
<p>Eric Ouellet, "Illuminations: The UFO Experience as a Parapsychological", Anomalist Books, 2015</p>
<p>という「UFO はポルターガイスト現象だ」という趣旨の著書(*1)も出している。彼のインタビュー動画からタイトルの件に絞る。</p>
<h3 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="1">(*1)<a class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to (*1)" title="Direct link to (*1)" href="https://ouchaku.github.io/ds/en/blog/2024/07/18/eric_ouellet_neclearr_powerplant_magnetic#1">​</a></h3>
<details class="details_lb9f alert alert--info details_b_Ee" data-collapsed="true"><summary>▼展開</summary><div><div class="collapsibleContent_i85q"><blockquote><a href="https://ouchaku.github.io/ds/img/20240718_book.jpg" target="_blank"><img alt="20240718_book.jpg" border="0" src="https://ouchaku.github.io/ds/img/20240718_book.jpg" width="90%"></a><p>UFO体験が無意識の大規模な超能力の結果だとしたら？</p><p>超心理学とUFO学は油と水のようなものだ。何十年もの間、高名な研究者たちがUFO現象の超常現象や超心理学的側面に注目しようと努力してきたにもかかわらず、両者は混じり合わないのだ。社会学者エリック・オイエレットは『イルミネーションズ』の中で、地球外生命体、タイムトラベラー、政府の秘密プロジェクト、自然現象など、これまで説明しようとするあらゆる努力に抵抗してきたこの現象に、斬新なアプローチを提供している。</p><p>超心理学、社会学、UFO学の研究を組み合わせ、オイエレットは、1952年のワシントンDCのUFOの波、1961年のベティとバーニー・ヒル誘拐事件、1980年のレンデルシャムUFO事件、1989年から1991年のベルギーのUFOの波など、いくつかの有名なUFO事件の再評価を示唆する。UFOの謎に対する最終的な解決策を持っていると主張するわけではないが、彼は、頑固なまでにとらえどころのない現象に対して、多くの考える材料と新鮮な展望を提供している。</p><p>「この分野における超心理学的なアプローチは稀である。-ジャック・ヴァレ、『見えない大学』の著者</p><p>「社会学者として、UFO目撃者として、さらに超心理学研究者として、エリック・オイエレットは、私が40年にわたるUFO調査の現場で遭遇した好奇心のバガテルを理解するためのすべての条件を満たしている。- ジェニー・ランドルズ、『マインド・モンスター』の著者</p><p>ERIC OUELLETは、カナダ王立陸軍大学およびカナダ軍大学（カナダの統合幕僚学校および陸軍大学）の国防学教授である。ヨーク大学（カナダ・トロント）で社会学の博士号を取得し、超心理学協会のカナダ担当連絡官を務める。オーストラリアン・ジャーナル・オブ・サイコロジー』、『エッジサイエンス』、『会報Métapsychique』に超心理学的研究を発表している。その他の研究テーマは軍事社会学と戦争研究である。</p><hr><p>What if UFO experiences are the result of large-scale, unconscious, psychic forces?</p><p>Parapsychology and UFOlogy are like oil and water. They just don't mix, despite the decades-long efforts of some highly respected researchers to call attention to the paranormal or parapsychological aspects of UFO events. In Illuminations, sociologist Eric Ouellet offers a novel approach to a phenomenon that has thus far resisted all other efforts to explain it, be it as extraterrestrial craft, time travelers, secret government projects, or natural phenomena.</p><p>Combining research in parapsychology, sociology, and UFOlogy, Ouellet provides a thought provoking reassessment of several well-known UFO cases, including the Washington, DC, UFO wave of 1952, the Betty and Barney Hill abduction of 1961, the Rendlesham UFO incident of 1980, and the Belgian UFO wave of 1989-1991. While not claiming to have the final solution to the UFO mystery, he offers much food for thought and a refreshing outlook on a stubbornly elusive phenomenon.</p><p>"Parapsychological approaches in this field are rare: your contribution is precious, and it is very timely." -Jacques Vallée, author of The Invisible College</p><p>"As a sociologist and a UFO witness, plus, importantly, a parapsychological researcher, Eric Ouellet ticks all the boxes to appreciate the bagatelle of curiosities that I have encountered in the field during 40 years of UFO investigation." - Jenny Randles, author of Mind Monsters</p><p>ERIC OUELLET is professor of Defence Studies at the Royal Military College of Canada, and at the Canadian Forces College (Canada's Joint Staff and War College). He has a Ph.D. in sociology from York University (Toronto, Canada), and he is the liaison officer for Canada with the Parapsychological Association. He has published parapsychological work in the Australian Journal of Psychology, EdgeScience, and the Bulletin Métapsychique. His other research works focus on military sociology and war studies.</p><p>ref: Amazon | Illuminations: The UFO Experience as a Parapsychological Event | Ouellet, Eric | Occult
<a href="https://www.amazon.co.jp/Illuminations-UFO-Experience-Parapsychological-Event/dp/193839853X" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">https://www.amazon.co.jp/Illuminations-UFO-Experience-Parapsychological-Event/dp/193839853X</a></p></blockquote></div></div></details>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="whisper-ailarge-v2-model--deepl">Whisper AI(large-v2 model) + DeepL<a class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Whisper AI(large-v2 model) + DeepL" title="Direct link to Whisper AI(large-v2 model) + DeepL" href="https://ouchaku.github.io/ds/en/blog/2024/07/18/eric_ouellet_neclearr_powerplant_magnetic#whisper-ailarge-v2-model--deepl">​</a></h2>
<p>原子力発電所、ここには方程式に関係するような他の何かがある。UFOの出来事のいくつかは、私たちがアースライトと呼んでいるものや、非常に磁化されたある種の自然のプラズマとおそらく関連していると思う。
(00:46:34)</p>
<p>原発は電気を作るから、磁気が強くなる。
だから、これらのプラズマの球が、原発や発電所に向かって磁気のために引き寄せられるのは理にかなっている。
したがって、なぜ原子力発電所の周辺にUFOが多いのか、もっと物理的な説明ができるかもしれない。</p>
<hr>
<p>Nuclear plant, here there's something else that maybe play in equations is that some, I think, of the UFO events are probably linked to what we call earth lights or some sort of natural plasma that are highly magnetized.
(00:46:34)</p>
<p>And when you have a nuclear plant, because it produces electricity, it has higher magnetism.
And so it would make sense that these balls of plasma are being quote unquote attracted because of the magnetism towards those nuclear plants and power plants.
And so therefore, there might be a more physical explanation as why there will be more UFOs around nuclear plants.</p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="コメント">コメント<a class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to コメント" title="Direct link to コメント" href="https://ouchaku.github.io/ds/en/blog/2024/07/18/eric_ouellet_neclearr_powerplant_magnetic#%E3%82%B3%E3%83%A1%E3%83%B3%E3%83%88">​</a></h2>
<p>Eric Ouellet のこの説明も無理がある。原発と他の発電方式（水力、火力）で磁界の強度に本質的な違いはない。どれもタービン（発電機）を回して発電するので違いが生じる筈がない。</p>
<p>磁界強度が問題なのであれば、送配電網、特に変電所周辺に UFO が集まることになる。だが、そのような報告事例は僅か。</p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="動画12859">動画(1:28:59)<a class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to 動画(1:28:59)" title="Direct link to 動画(1:28:59)" href="https://ouchaku.github.io/ds/en/blog/2024/07/18/eric_ouellet_neclearr_powerplant_magnetic#%E5%8B%95%E7%94%BB12859">​</a></h2>
<p>UFO's and Poltergeists with Eric Ouellet - July 11, 2024</p>
<iframe width="560" height="315" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/dPBHw12YCuU?si=Frq8sayKRIHGwgI5" title="YouTube video player" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin"></iframe>
<p><a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=dPBHw12YCuU" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">www.youtube.com/watch?v=dPBHw12YCuU</a></p>
<h3 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="動画概要欄">動画概要欄<a class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to 動画概要欄" title="Direct link to 動画概要欄" href="https://ouchaku.github.io/ds/en/blog/2024/07/18/eric_ouellet_neclearr_powerplant_magnetic#%E5%8B%95%E7%94%BB%E6%A6%82%E8%A6%81%E6%AC%84">​</a></h3>
<p>1,700 views  Jul 15, 2024  2024 Shows
Originally aired on April 2, 2016</p>
<p>Since I reference this book a lot, I felt it was time to remaster and re-upload this show, with it's short Patreon segment as well.</p>
<p>Eric Ouellet joins me for a fascinating discussion of his new book, Illuminations: The UFO Experience as a Parapsychological Event. He proposes that we should examine the UFO Phenomenon as we would a poltergeist case. It's a novel way of looking at it, and may ultimately play a part in solving this enigma.</p>
<p>ERIC OUELLET is professor of Defence Studies at the Royal Military College of Canada, and at the Canadian Forces College (Canada's Joint Staff and War College). He has a Ph.D. in sociology from York University (Toronto, Canada), and he is the liaison officer for Canada with the Parapsychological Association. He has published parapsychological work in the Australian Journal of Psychology, EdgeScience, and the Bulletin Métapsychique. His other research works focus on military sociology and war studies.</p>
<p>(2024-07-18)</p>]]></content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Eric Ouellet：パイロットの機嫌が悪い時、航空用電子機器が正常動作しないことを示唆する研究結果がある]]></title>
        <id>https://ouchaku.github.io/ds/en/blog/2024/07/18/eric_ouellet_pilot_badmood_malfunction</id>
        <link href="https://ouchaku.github.io/ds/en/blog/2024/07/18/eric_ouellet_pilot_badmood_malfunction"/>
        <updated>2024-07-18T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[前置き]]></summary>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="前置き">前置き<a class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to 前置き" title="Direct link to 前置き" href="https://ouchaku.github.io/ds/en/blog/2024/07/18/eric_ouellet_pilot_badmood_malfunction#%E5%89%8D%E7%BD%AE%E3%81%8D">​</a></h2>
<p>Eric Ouellet はカナダの社会学者で</p>
<p>Eric Ouellet, "Illuminations: The UFO Experience as a Parapsychological", Anomalist Books, 2015</p>
<p>という「UFO はポルターガイスト現象だ」という趣旨の著書(*1)も出している。彼のインタビュー動画からタイトルの件に絞る。</p>
<h3 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="1">(*1)<a class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to (*1)" title="Direct link to (*1)" href="https://ouchaku.github.io/ds/en/blog/2024/07/18/eric_ouellet_pilot_badmood_malfunction#1">​</a></h3>
<details class="details_lb9f alert alert--info details_b_Ee" data-collapsed="true"><summary>▼展開</summary><div><div class="collapsibleContent_i85q"><blockquote><a href="https://ouchaku.github.io/ds/img/20240718_book.jpg" target="_blank"><img alt="20240718_book.jpg" border="0" src="https://ouchaku.github.io/ds/img/20240718_book.jpg" width="90%"></a><p>UFO体験が無意識の大規模な超能力の結果だとしたら？</p><p>超心理学とUFO学は油と水のようなものだ。何十年もの間、高名な研究者たちがUFO現象の超常現象や超心理学的側面に注目しようと努力してきたにもかかわらず、両者は混じり合わないのだ。社会学者エリック・オイエレットは『イルミネーションズ』の中で、地球外生命体、タイムトラベラー、政府の秘密プロジェクト、自然現象など、これまで説明しようとするあらゆる努力に抵抗してきたこの現象に、斬新なアプローチを提供している。</p><p>超心理学、社会学、UFO学の研究を組み合わせ、オイエレットは、1952年のワシントンDCのUFOの波、1961年のベティとバーニー・ヒル誘拐事件、1980年のレンデルシャムUFO事件、1989年から1991年のベルギーのUFOの波など、いくつかの有名なUFO事件の再評価を示唆する。UFOの謎に対する最終的な解決策を持っていると主張するわけではないが、彼は、頑固なまでにとらえどころのない現象に対して、多くの考える材料と新鮮な展望を提供している。</p><p>「この分野における超心理学的なアプローチは稀である。-ジャック・ヴァレ、『見えない大学』の著者</p><p>「社会学者として、UFO目撃者として、さらに超心理学研究者として、エリック・オイエレットは、私が40年にわたるUFO調査の現場で遭遇した好奇心のバガテルを理解するためのすべての条件を満たしている。- ジェニー・ランドルズ、『マインド・モンスター』の著者</p><p>ERIC OUELLETは、カナダ王立陸軍大学およびカナダ軍大学（カナダの統合幕僚学校および陸軍大学）の国防学教授である。ヨーク大学（カナダ・トロント）で社会学の博士号を取得し、超心理学協会のカナダ担当連絡官を務める。オーストラリアン・ジャーナル・オブ・サイコロジー』、『エッジサイエンス』、『会報Métapsychique』に超心理学的研究を発表している。その他の研究テーマは軍事社会学と戦争研究である。</p><hr><p>What if UFO experiences are the result of large-scale, unconscious, psychic forces?</p><p>Parapsychology and UFOlogy are like oil and water. They just don't mix, despite the decades-long efforts of some highly respected researchers to call attention to the paranormal or parapsychological aspects of UFO events. In Illuminations, sociologist Eric Ouellet offers a novel approach to a phenomenon that has thus far resisted all other efforts to explain it, be it as extraterrestrial craft, time travelers, secret government projects, or natural phenomena.</p><p>Combining research in parapsychology, sociology, and UFOlogy, Ouellet provides a thought provoking reassessment of several well-known UFO cases, including the Washington, DC, UFO wave of 1952, the Betty and Barney Hill abduction of 1961, the Rendlesham UFO incident of 1980, and the Belgian UFO wave of 1989-1991. While not claiming to have the final solution to the UFO mystery, he offers much food for thought and a refreshing outlook on a stubbornly elusive phenomenon.</p><p>"Parapsychological approaches in this field are rare: your contribution is precious, and it is very timely." -Jacques Vallée, author of The Invisible College</p><p>"As a sociologist and a UFO witness, plus, importantly, a parapsychological researcher, Eric Ouellet ticks all the boxes to appreciate the bagatelle of curiosities that I have encountered in the field during 40 years of UFO investigation." - Jenny Randles, author of Mind Monsters</p><p>ERIC OUELLET is professor of Defence Studies at the Royal Military College of Canada, and at the Canadian Forces College (Canada's Joint Staff and War College). He has a Ph.D. in sociology from York University (Toronto, Canada), and he is the liaison officer for Canada with the Parapsychological Association. He has published parapsychological work in the Australian Journal of Psychology, EdgeScience, and the Bulletin Métapsychique. His other research works focus on military sociology and war studies.</p><p>ref: Amazon | Illuminations: The UFO Experience as a Parapsychological Event | Ouellet, Eric | Occult
<a href="https://www.amazon.co.jp/Illuminations-UFO-Experience-Parapsychological-Event/dp/193839853X" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">https://www.amazon.co.jp/Illuminations-UFO-Experience-Parapsychological-Event/dp/193839853X</a></p></blockquote></div></div></details>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="whisper-ailarge-v2-model--deepl">Whisper AI(large-v2 model) + DeepL<a class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Whisper AI(large-v2 model) + DeepL" title="Direct link to Whisper AI(large-v2 model) + DeepL" href="https://ouchaku.github.io/ds/en/blog/2024/07/18/eric_ouellet_pilot_badmood_malfunction#whisper-ailarge-v2-model--deepl">​</a></h2>
<p>ところで、コンピュータのような敏感なシステムについては、非常に深刻な研究がなされている。
人の心の状態が、誤作動を起こしたコンピューターに影響を与えるようだ。
それに関する研究は、飛行機の電子機器を心配する人がいるほど深刻なものだった。
(00:54:03)</p>
<p>パイロットが非常に機嫌が悪かった場合、実際に何らかのシステムが正常に機能しなくなる可能性がある。
そして、その仮説が正しいことを示す証拠もいくつかある。</p>
<hr>
<p>The state of mind of people seems to affect computers that misbehave because it seems to affect some of the electronic components, at least for a short period of time.
And the research about that was serious enough that there were people worried about the electronics of airplanes.
(00:54:03)</p>
<p>If pilots were in a very bad mood, they may actually make some system not functioning properly.
And there is some evidence to show that it seems to be correct, that the hypothesis, at least we are pointing in the right direction with that.</p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="コメント">コメント<a class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to コメント" title="Direct link to コメント" href="https://ouchaku.github.io/ds/en/blog/2024/07/18/eric_ouellet_pilot_badmood_malfunction#%E3%82%B3%E3%83%A1%E3%83%B3%E3%83%88">​</a></h2>
<p>Eric Ouellet の主張は信用にたる根拠がない。良く言っても「疑わしい」。航空機の操縦を左右する電子機器の信頼性については膨大な実績データが積み上がっているが、その中に</p>
<blockquote><p>「それに関する研究は、飛行機の電子機器を心配する人がいるほど深刻なものだった。
(00:54:03)</p><p>パイロットが非常に機嫌が悪かった場合、実際に何らかのシステムが正常に機能しなくなる可能性がある。
そして、その仮説が正しいことを示す証拠もいくつかある。</p></blockquote>
<p>を示すデータは存在しない。存在したら、今頃大騒ぎになっている。</p>
<p>仮に、</p>
<blockquote><p>ところで、コンピュータのような敏感なシステムについては、非常に深刻な研究がなされている。
人の心の状態が、誤作動を起こしたコンピューターに影響を与えるようだ。</p></blockquote>
<p>であれば、PC も高機能携帯電話機も、インターネットに接続された無数のデータセンタも、周囲の人間の機嫌次第で誤動作する筈だが、それを示す統計データは皆無。</p>
<h3 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="関連">関連<a class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to 関連" title="Direct link to 関連" href="https://ouchaku.github.io/ds/en/blog/2024/07/18/eric_ouellet_pilot_badmood_malfunction#%E9%96%A2%E9%80%A3">​</a></h3>
<p><a href="http://news21c.blog.fc2.com/blog-entry-21849.html" target="_blank">❏ Global Consciousness Project の「大衆の意識が乱数発生器に干渉した」という実験データは観察者バイアスだろう</a> (2024-01-26)</p>
<p><a href="http://news21c.blog.fc2.com/blog-entry-22293.html" target="_blank">❏ "Global Consciousness Project" の解説動画 : 文字起こし＋和訳</a> (2024-05-21)</p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="動画12859">動画(1:28:59)<a class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to 動画(1:28:59)" title="Direct link to 動画(1:28:59)" href="https://ouchaku.github.io/ds/en/blog/2024/07/18/eric_ouellet_pilot_badmood_malfunction#%E5%8B%95%E7%94%BB12859">​</a></h2>
<p>UFO's and Poltergeists with Eric Ouellet - July 11, 2024</p>
<iframe width="560" height="315" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/dPBHw12YCuU?si=Frq8sayKRIHGwgI5" title="YouTube video player" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin"></iframe>
<p><a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=dPBHw12YCuU" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">www.youtube.com/watch?v=dPBHw12YCuU</a></p>
<h3 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="動画概要欄">動画概要欄<a class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to 動画概要欄" title="Direct link to 動画概要欄" href="https://ouchaku.github.io/ds/en/blog/2024/07/18/eric_ouellet_pilot_badmood_malfunction#%E5%8B%95%E7%94%BB%E6%A6%82%E8%A6%81%E6%AC%84">​</a></h3>
<p>1,700 views  Jul 15, 2024  2024 Shows
Originally aired on April 2, 2016</p>
<p>Since I reference this book a lot, I felt it was time to remaster and re-upload this show, with it's short Patreon segment as well.</p>
<p>Eric Ouellet joins me for a fascinating discussion of his new book, Illuminations: The UFO Experience as a Parapsychological Event. He proposes that we should examine the UFO Phenomenon as we would a poltergeist case. It's a novel way of looking at it, and may ultimately play a part in solving this enigma.</p>
<p>ERIC OUELLET is professor of Defence Studies at the Royal Military College of Canada, and at the Canadian Forces College (Canada's Joint Staff and War College). He has a Ph.D. in sociology from York University (Toronto, Canada), and he is the liaison officer for Canada with the Parapsychological Association. He has published parapsychological work in the Australian Journal of Psychology, EdgeScience, and the Bulletin Métapsychique. His other research works focus on military sociology and war studies.</p>
<p>(2024-07-18)</p>]]></content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Eric Ouellet：ポルターガイスト現象の推移パターンと発生源]]></title>
        <id>https://ouchaku.github.io/ds/en/blog/2024/07/18/eric_ouellet_poltergeist_pattern</id>
        <link href="https://ouchaku.github.io/ds/en/blog/2024/07/18/eric_ouellet_poltergeist_pattern"/>
        <updated>2024-07-18T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[前置き]]></summary>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="前置き">前置き<a class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to 前置き" title="Direct link to 前置き" href="https://ouchaku.github.io/ds/en/blog/2024/07/18/eric_ouellet_poltergeist_pattern#%E5%89%8D%E7%BD%AE%E3%81%8D">​</a></h2>
<p>Eric Ouellet はカナダの社会学者で</p>
<p>Eric Ouellet, "Illuminations: The UFO Experience as a Parapsychological", Anomalist Books, 2015</p>
<p>という「UFO はポルターガイスト現象だ」という趣旨の著書(*1)も出している。彼のインタビュー動画からタイトルの件に絞る。</p>
<h3 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="1">(*1)<a class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to (*1)" title="Direct link to (*1)" href="https://ouchaku.github.io/ds/en/blog/2024/07/18/eric_ouellet_poltergeist_pattern#1">​</a></h3>
<details class="details_lb9f alert alert--info details_b_Ee" data-collapsed="true"><summary>▼展開</summary><div><div class="collapsibleContent_i85q"><blockquote><a href="https://ouchaku.github.io/ds/img/20240718_book.jpg" target="_blank"><img alt="20240718_book.jpg" border="0" src="https://ouchaku.github.io/ds/img/20240718_book.jpg" width="90%"></a><p>UFO体験が無意識の大規模な超能力の結果だとしたら？</p><p>超心理学とUFO学は油と水のようなものだ。何十年もの間、高名な研究者たちがUFO現象の超常現象や超心理学的側面に注目しようと努力してきたにもかかわらず、両者は混じり合わないのだ。社会学者エリック・オイエレットは『イルミネーションズ』の中で、地球外生命体、タイムトラベラー、政府の秘密プロジェクト、自然現象など、これまで説明しようとするあらゆる努力に抵抗してきたこの現象に、斬新なアプローチを提供している。</p><p>超心理学、社会学、UFO学の研究を組み合わせ、オイエレットは、1952年のワシントンDCのUFOの波、1961年のベティとバーニー・ヒル誘拐事件、1980年のレンデルシャムUFO事件、1989年から1991年のベルギーのUFOの波など、いくつかの有名なUFO事件の再評価を示唆する。UFOの謎に対する最終的な解決策を持っていると主張するわけではないが、彼は、頑固なまでにとらえどころのない現象に対して、多くの考える材料と新鮮な展望を提供している。</p><p>「この分野における超心理学的なアプローチは稀である。-ジャック・ヴァレ、『見えない大学』の著者</p><p>「社会学者として、UFO目撃者として、さらに超心理学研究者として、エリック・オイエレットは、私が40年にわたるUFO調査の現場で遭遇した好奇心のバガテルを理解するためのすべての条件を満たしている。- ジェニー・ランドルズ、『マインド・モンスター』の著者</p><p>ERIC OUELLETは、カナダ王立陸軍大学およびカナダ軍大学（カナダの統合幕僚学校および陸軍大学）の国防学教授である。ヨーク大学（カナダ・トロント）で社会学の博士号を取得し、超心理学協会のカナダ担当連絡官を務める。オーストラリアン・ジャーナル・オブ・サイコロジー』、『エッジサイエンス』、『会報Métapsychique』に超心理学的研究を発表している。その他の研究テーマは軍事社会学と戦争研究である。</p><hr><p>What if UFO experiences are the result of large-scale, unconscious, psychic forces?</p><p>Parapsychology and UFOlogy are like oil and water. They just don't mix, despite the decades-long efforts of some highly respected researchers to call attention to the paranormal or parapsychological aspects of UFO events. In Illuminations, sociologist Eric Ouellet offers a novel approach to a phenomenon that has thus far resisted all other efforts to explain it, be it as extraterrestrial craft, time travelers, secret government projects, or natural phenomena.</p><p>Combining research in parapsychology, sociology, and UFOlogy, Ouellet provides a thought provoking reassessment of several well-known UFO cases, including the Washington, DC, UFO wave of 1952, the Betty and Barney Hill abduction of 1961, the Rendlesham UFO incident of 1980, and the Belgian UFO wave of 1989-1991. While not claiming to have the final solution to the UFO mystery, he offers much food for thought and a refreshing outlook on a stubbornly elusive phenomenon.</p><p>"Parapsychological approaches in this field are rare: your contribution is precious, and it is very timely." -Jacques Vallée, author of The Invisible College</p><p>"As a sociologist and a UFO witness, plus, importantly, a parapsychological researcher, Eric Ouellet ticks all the boxes to appreciate the bagatelle of curiosities that I have encountered in the field during 40 years of UFO investigation." - Jenny Randles, author of Mind Monsters</p><p>ERIC OUELLET is professor of Defence Studies at the Royal Military College of Canada, and at the Canadian Forces College (Canada's Joint Staff and War College). He has a Ph.D. in sociology from York University (Toronto, Canada), and he is the liaison officer for Canada with the Parapsychological Association. He has published parapsychological work in the Australian Journal of Psychology, EdgeScience, and the Bulletin Métapsychique. His other research works focus on military sociology and war studies.</p><p>ref: Amazon | Illuminations: The UFO Experience as a Parapsychological Event | Ouellet, Eric | Occult
<a href="https://www.amazon.co.jp/Illuminations-UFO-Experience-Parapsychological-Event/dp/193839853X" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">https://www.amazon.co.jp/Illuminations-UFO-Experience-Parapsychological-Event/dp/193839853X</a></p></blockquote></div></div></details>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="whisper-ailarge-v2-model--deepl">Whisper AI(large-v2 model) + DeepL<a class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Whisper AI(large-v2 model) + DeepL" title="Direct link to Whisper AI(large-v2 model) + DeepL" href="https://ouchaku.github.io/ds/en/blog/2024/07/18/eric_ouellet_poltergeist_pattern#whisper-ailarge-v2-model--deepl">​</a></h2>
<p>この本では、ポルターガイスト現象がどのように展開するのか、その一部始終を紹介しているんだけど、もしそれが誰から来ているのかを突き止め、彼らが抱えている問題を解決する手助けをすることができれば、ポルターガイストの活動は収まる傾向にあるとも言っているんだ。
(00:17:52)</p>
<p>その通りだ。
ポルターガイストの状況になると、たいてい一人の人が心理的にとても苦しんでいるんだけど、何らかの理由で、その苦しみや痛みを表現できないんだ。
だから話さない。
そのため、その苦しみは無意識のものとなる。
そしてある状況下では、無意識の人たちはその痛みを表現するために、通常とは違う手段、つまりマインド・オーバー・マターを使って、必要な助けを得られるようにする。
(00:18:32)</p>
<p>そして、いったんその人が自分の痛みの原因となった本当の問題について話し始めると、通常、ポルターガイスト現象における超常現象は非常に激減する。
なるほど。
ポルターガイスト事件における典型的な手順を説明してくれる？
そうだね。
フォン・ルカドゥがドイツやヨーロッパで経験的に研究したところ、ポルターガイスト現象はすべて同じように展開する傾向があることがわかったんだ。
(00:19:08)</p>
<p>つまり、非常に穏やかに始まる時期があり、これを彼はサプライズと呼んだ。
穏やかに始まり、奇妙なことや奇妙な音に驚く。
だから、身近な環境、たいていは家族や職場が、何が起こっているのだろうと思い始める。
しかし、その時点ではまだよくわからない。
超常的な力について強い仮説を立てるわけでもなく、ただあまり確信が持てないだけなのだ。
(00:19:44)</p>
<p>そして普通はもっと時間がかかる。
それは強度を増し始める。
でもその時点で、超常現象を強く信じる人たちが現場にやってくる。
ゴースト・ハンターか、家の霊を追い払おうとする人たちだ。
そして彼らの行動そのものが、超常的な何かがこの世に存在しないという信念を強めているのだ。
(00:20:19)</p>
<p>そしてこれは奇妙な効果をもたらし、誰もがそれが何であるかを信じるようになり、それが強化され、何でもポルターガイスト現象の一部であるように見えるようになる。
しかし、苦しんでいる人の注意は、その人から、霊や幽霊と思われるものへと移ってしまう。
(00:20:42)</p>
<hr>
<p>だからこそ、彼はこの第二段階を「ズレ」と呼んだのだ。
焦点となる人物、本当に苦しんでいる人物から注意がそれる。
そして第三段階がある。
やがて、もう少し懐疑的な人々が登場する。
科学者であったり、福祉サービスであったり、ケースによる。
そして彼らは、より綿密な質問をする。
彼らは何が起こっているのか、より批判的な観察者なのだ。
(00:21:12)</p>
<p>そして彼らは通常その時点で、その現象が、焦点を当てた人が特定の部屋や特定の建物にいるときに起こることを理解し始める。
そこで彼らは、その現象をある人物に関連づけ始める。
そして通常、その現象の強さが弱まり始める。
しかし同時に、その人、つまりフォーカスしている人、苦しんでいる人が注目され始める。
(00:21:39)</p>
<p>それが最終的に彼らが必要とし、望んでいることなのだ。
だから一方では、自分の痛みを伝えるために普通ではない手段を使う必要は少なくなる。
しかし一方では、その現象のために多くの注目を浴びる傾向もある。
だからその時、注目されている人は、注目され続けるために、ごまかしやデマに手を染め始めることがよくある。
(00:22:06)</p>
<p>そしてしばしば捕まる。
それがその段階だ。
それが衰退と呼ばれる第3の段階だ。
そして最後に第4段階がある。
それは抑制と呼ばれるものだ。
報道されたり、警察が関与したり、自治体が関与したりすることで、社会全体が、「あれはデマだったんだ。
(00:22:34)</p>
<p>ポルターガイスト現象はとても不穏なものだからだ。
そして、その出来事は完全に終結し、通常は完全に止まる。
だから、事象のベルカーブのようなものがある。
これがフォン・ルカドゥが提唱したモデルで、UFO波を研究するためのものだ。
なるほど。
そのモデルの完璧な例として、エンフィールド・ポルターガイスト事件を挙げたんだね。
(00:23:02)</p>
<p>その通りだ。
リスナーがその事件をどれだけ知っているかはわからないが、その状況をよく表している。
心霊研究協会が関与し、より批判的な観察者、元マジシャンがより批判的になる。
そして最後には、少女がデマを流したことを認めるのだが、他の多くのことはデマではないと主張し、彼女を信じる十分な理由もある。
(00:23:35)</p>
<p>そして、最終的には完全に終わった。
しかし問題の少女は、両親が離婚したばかりでトラウマを抱えていた。
彼女は結局、社宅に住むことになり、妹や弟と一緒に暮らすことになった。
だから、彼女の小さな世界はあっという間に崩壊していった。
でも何らかの理由で、彼女はそれを表現することができなかった。
だからこれは、フォン・ルカドゥが話したモデルを説明するのにとてもいいケースなのだ。
(00:24:05)</p>
<p>なるほど。
さて、ここでUFOに関する超常現象のアイデアの歴史について少し触れよう。
(00:24:11)</p>
<hr>
<p>その通りだ。
テレパシーであれ、予感であれ、ポルターガイスト的な現象がUFO体験の最中に起こったり、UFO体験の直後に起こったりする。
また、UFOを体験した後、人々はより精神的に自覚的になる傾向がある。
だから、彼らは人々が考えていること、未来がどうなるかに同調しやすくなる時期があるようだ。
(00:24:53)</p>
<p>だから、UFO体験を超常現象の領域から完全に切り離すことはできないようだ。
そうだね。
ケネス・リングがオメガ・プロジェクトで臨死体験やUFOとの接触の後遺症について研究したように、最初の遭遇の後にも多くの超常現象が起こっていることを発見したんだ。
その通りだ。
そして、純粋に、物理的に、厳密に物理的なUFO体験をしたと思われる人たちでさえ、実際にはあらゆる種類の超常現象に巻き込まれている。
(00:25:34)</p>
<p>バーニーとベティ・ヒルの有名なケースは、多くの人が知らないことだけど、彼らはその出来事の前に、実は夫婦でテレパシーの練習をしていたんだ。
だから、彼らはすでに超心理学に興味を持っていた。
そしてその後、彼らにも奇妙なことがいくつか起こった。
だから、このような事件でさえも、一見単純明快に見えるが、実は忘れてはならない別の側面があるのだ。
(00:26:07)</p>
<p>そうだね。
このポルターガイストのような現象に当てはまるUFOの波について、あなたは本の中で3つの主な例を挙げている。
そのうちの一つを選んで、あなたが話していることのアイデアを人々に与えたい？
もちろんだ。
この本では、このモデルを使った3つのケーススタディを紹介している。
つまり、UFOの、ごめん、ポルターガイストの領域からのベル曲線だ。
(00:26:33)</p>
<p>一つは1952年のワシントンDCのUFOの波だ。
もう一つは1989年、1991年のベルギーのUFOの波だ。
そして最後のものは、UFOの波というほどではないが、1980年のレルダーシャムUFO事件としてよく知られているもので、これもベル曲線に非常によく似た形で展開した。
これは大きなUFOの波だと思うので、ベルギーのものを使うことにする。
(00:27:02)</p>
<p>比較的最近のことだ。
(00:27:02)比較的最近のものだ。
そして、多くの類似点がある。
その波はとても穏やかに始まった。
いくつかの観測記録がある。
しかし、当時は誰も波について深く考えていなかった。
しかし、ある夜、ブームが起こり、100以上の観測がなされ、いくつかの観測は警察を巻き込み、多くの警察官が非常に奇妙なことを報告した。
(00:27:42)</p>
<p>だから、それは驚きとしてブームのように始まった。
新聞はすぐにこの記事を取り上げた。
でも彼らは比較的、冷静だったと言える。
彼らは、よし、何か奇妙なことが起こっている、と言ったんだ。
(00:27:57)</p>
<hr>
<p>それが何なのかはわからない。
宇宙から来たエイリアンかもしれない。
他の何かかもしれない。
わからない。</p>
<hr>
<p>And in the book, one of the things you mentioned is that you lay out a whole part segment of how poltergeist phenomena unfold, but you also say that if you can figure out who it's coming from and get them actually help with the problems they're dealing with, because these are often unconscious expulsions that are creating the poltergeist, the poltergeist activity tends to go away.
(00:17:52)</p>
<p>Absolutely.
And there's a lot of empirical evidence to support that, that when we have a poltergeist situation, there's one person usually suffering psychologically a lot, but for whatever reasons, cannot express that pain, that suffering, usually because social dynamics around them is very bad.
So they don't speak.
And so that pain becomes unconscious.
And in some situation, the unconscious use non-normal means, so mind over matter, to express that pain so that they can get the help they need.
(00:18:32)</p>
<p>And once that the person starts to talk about the real issue that caused their pain, usually we see a very drastic reduction of the paranormal phenomena in a poltergeist event.
Okay.
And do you want to explain the typical steps there in a poltergeist case?
Yes.
So the Von Lucadou who studied empirically a number of cases in Germany and in Europe found that they all tend to unfold the same way.
(00:19:08)</p>
<p>So there is a period where it starts very gently, and this is a phase that he called surprise.
So it starts gently, and then people are surprised that weird things happens, strange noises.
So the immediate environment, so usually a family or a workplace, start to wonder what's going on.
But at that point, they're not really sure.
They don't make any strong hypothesis about the paranormal force, or they're just kind of not too sure.
(00:19:44)</p>
<p>And usually it takes more.
It starts to grow in intensity.
But at that point, we usually have people who are strong believers in the paranormal that arrive on the scene.
Either it's ghost hunters or all kinds of people who want to clear houses of spirits.
And by their very action, they actually reinforce the belief that there's something paranormal out of this world that is causing that.
(00:20:19)</p>
<p>And this has a strange effect that then everybody believes that what it is, which reinforces then anything will appear as being part of the poltergeist event, even a normal thing.
But the person who's suffering, the attention is displaced from him or her towards an alleged spirit or alleged ghost.
(00:20:42)</p>
<hr>
<p>And that's why he called this second phase the displacement.
The attention is displaced away from the focus person, the person who's really suffering.
And then there's a third phase.
Eventually, there are people a little bit more skeptical that arrives on the scene.
Either they're scientists or they could be social services, depends on the case.
And they ask a lot more thorough questions.
They're much more critical observers of what's going on.
(00:21:12)</p>
<p>And they usually at that point start to figure out that the phenomenon is usually happening when the focus person is in a particular room or a particular building.
So they start to associate the phenomenon with a person.
And then usually that's when the phenomenon starts to decline in intensity.
But also, then the person, the focus person, the person suffering starts to get attention.
(00:21:39)</p>
<p>That's ultimately what they need and what they want.
So there's less need to use the non-normal means to communicate their pain on one hand.
But on the other hand, they tend also to get a lot of attentions because of the phenomenon.
So oftentimes at that time, the person who's the focus person starts to engage in cheating or hoaxing, so just to continue to have the attention.
(00:22:06)</p>
<p>And oftentimes they get caught.
That's that phase.
That's the third phase that is called the decline.
And then there's a fourth phase at the end.
It's called suppression.
It's that when the rest of society, so when it gets into the press or the police is involved or the municipality, whatever is the case, then they say, okay, that was a hoax and that's it.
(00:22:34)</p>
<p>We don't want to hear about this because it's very disturbing, a poltergeist event.
And that put full closure to the event and it usually stops completely.
So you have a bit like a bell curve of events.
And so that's the model proposed by Von Lucadou, a use for studying UFO waves.
Okay.
And you give the Enfield poltergeist case as like a perfect example of that model.
(00:23:02)</p>
<p>Absolutely.
I don't know how much your listeners are aware of that case, but it follows very well that situation.
You have the Society for Psychical Research gets involved and then more critical observers, former magicians, so are much more critical.
And then at the end, it's just the girl admits that she did some hoaxing, although she claims that a lot of other things were not hoax and there's good reason to believe her as well.
(00:23:35)</p>
<p>And then, eventually it's completely end.
But the little girl in question, she was living a trauma because her parents just divorced.
She ended up being in a social housing, so a situation with all her sisters and brother.
And so her little world was falling apart very quickly.
But for some reason, she was not able to express that.
So this is a very good case to illustrate the model talked about by Von Lucadou.
(00:24:05)</p>
<p>Okay.
Now, there's a little bit of history here of paranormal idea with UFOs.
(00:24:11)</p>
<hr>
<p>Absolutely.
I mean, a lot of UFO events have a degree of paranormal or psychological aspects to them, whether it's telepathy, premonition, either that there is actually poltergeist events that occurs during a UFO event or just after.
And also people, after having a UFO experience, they tend to be more psychically aware.
So they seem to have a period of time where they seem to be more in tune with what people are thinking, what the future holds.
(00:24:53)</p>
<p>And so it seems that we cannot really drastically separate the UFO experience from the realm of the paranormal.
Yeah.
And I know like Kenneth Ring did his study on the Omega Project, looking at the after effects of near-death experiences and UFO contact and found that very same thing, that there's a lot of paranormal stuff going on after the initial encounter.
That's correct.
And even people that we think that had a purely, I would say, physical, strictly physical UFO experience, they are actually mixed up with all kinds of paranormal event.
(00:25:34)</p>
<p>The famous case of Barney and Betty Hill, something that a lot of people don't really know is that they had before the event, they're actually practicing telepathy as a couple.
So already they had an interest in the parapsychology.
And then afterward, they had a few weird things happening to them as well, so that they mentioned.
So even a case like that, that seems to be so nuts and bolts, there's actually other aspects to it that we should not forget.
(00:26:07)</p>
<p>Yeah.
So do you want to lay out, you give three main examples in the book of UFO waves that fit this poltergeist-like phenomena.
Do you just want to pick one of those and give people an idea of what you're talking about?
Sure.
In the book, I present three case studies using the model.
So the bell curves, if you want, of the UFO, sorry, from the poltergeist realm.
(00:26:33)</p>
<p>So one is the 1952 Washington DC UFO wave.
Another one is the Belgian UFO wave of 1989, 1991.
And the last one, it was not really a UFO wave, but it's a well-known event as the Relderscham UFO incident of 1980, which also unfolded in ways very similar to the bell curve.
I'll use the Belgian one because I think that's a big UFO wave.
(00:27:02)</p>
<p>It's relatively recent.
I mean, it's getting old now.
And the thing is, it has a lot of similarities.
So the wave started very gently.
There are a few observations that were recorded.
But no one was really thinking about the wave at the time.
But then one night, boom, there was over 100 observations that were made, some involving and it's very well documented, so involving the police, many police officers reporting things that were very, very weird.
(00:27:42)</p>
<p>So it started like boom as a surprise.
And then the newspaper picked up the story quickly.
But they were actually relatively, I would say, level-headed.
They say, okay, there's something weird going on.
(00:27:57)</p>
<hr>
<p>We don't know what it is.
It may be aliens from outer space.
It may be something else.
We don't know.</p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="動画12859">動画(1:28:59)<a class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to 動画(1:28:59)" title="Direct link to 動画(1:28:59)" href="https://ouchaku.github.io/ds/en/blog/2024/07/18/eric_ouellet_poltergeist_pattern#%E5%8B%95%E7%94%BB12859">​</a></h2>
<p>UFO's and Poltergeists with Eric Ouellet - July 11, 2024</p>
<iframe width="560" height="315" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/dPBHw12YCuU?si=Frq8sayKRIHGwgI5" title="YouTube video player" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin"></iframe>
<p><a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=dPBHw12YCuU" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">www.youtube.com/watch?v=dPBHw12YCuU</a></p>
<h3 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="動画概要欄">動画概要欄<a class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to 動画概要欄" title="Direct link to 動画概要欄" href="https://ouchaku.github.io/ds/en/blog/2024/07/18/eric_ouellet_poltergeist_pattern#%E5%8B%95%E7%94%BB%E6%A6%82%E8%A6%81%E6%AC%84">​</a></h3>
<p>1,700 views  Jul 15, 2024  2024 Shows
Originally aired on April 2, 2016</p>
<p>Since I reference this book a lot, I felt it was time to remaster and re-upload this show, with it's short Patreon segment as well.</p>
<p>Eric Ouellet joins me for a fascinating discussion of his new book, Illuminations: The UFO Experience as a Parapsychological Event. He proposes that we should examine the UFO Phenomenon as we would a poltergeist case. It's a novel way of looking at it, and may ultimately play a part in solving this enigma.</p>
<p>ERIC OUELLET is professor of Defence Studies at the Royal Military College of Canada, and at the Canadian Forces College (Canada's Joint Staff and War College). He has a Ph.D. in sociology from York University (Toronto, Canada), and he is the liaison officer for Canada with the Parapsychological Association. He has published parapsychological work in the Australian Journal of Psychology, EdgeScience, and the Bulletin Métapsychique. His other research works focus on military sociology and war studies.</p>
<p>(2024-07-18)</p>]]></content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Eric Ouellet：UFO 目撃頻度や ESP 能力は太陽活動の影響を受けている]]></title>
        <id>https://ouchaku.github.io/ds/en/blog/2024/07/18/eric_ouellet_sun_activity</id>
        <link href="https://ouchaku.github.io/ds/en/blog/2024/07/18/eric_ouellet_sun_activity"/>
        <updated>2024-07-18T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[前置き]]></summary>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="前置き">前置き<a class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to 前置き" title="Direct link to 前置き" href="https://ouchaku.github.io/ds/en/blog/2024/07/18/eric_ouellet_sun_activity#%E5%89%8D%E7%BD%AE%E3%81%8D">​</a></h2>
<p>Eric Ouellet はカナダの社会学者で</p>
<p>Eric Ouellet, "Illuminations: The UFO Experience as a Parapsychological", Anomalist Books, 2015</p>
<p>という「UFO はポルターガイスト現象だ」という趣旨の著書(*1)も出している。彼のインタビュー動画からタイトルの件に絞る。</p>
<h3 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="1">(*1)<a class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to (*1)" title="Direct link to (*1)" href="https://ouchaku.github.io/ds/en/blog/2024/07/18/eric_ouellet_sun_activity#1">​</a></h3>
<details class="details_lb9f alert alert--info details_b_Ee" data-collapsed="true"><summary>▼展開</summary><div><div class="collapsibleContent_i85q"><blockquote><a href="https://ouchaku.github.io/ds/img/20240718_book.jpg" target="_blank"><img alt="20240718_book.jpg" border="0" src="https://ouchaku.github.io/ds/img/20240718_book.jpg" width="90%"></a><p>UFO体験が無意識の大規模な超能力の結果だとしたら？</p><p>超心理学とUFO学は油と水のようなものだ。何十年もの間、高名な研究者たちがUFO現象の超常現象や超心理学的側面に注目しようと努力してきたにもかかわらず、両者は混じり合わないのだ。社会学者エリック・オイエレットは『イルミネーションズ』の中で、地球外生命体、タイムトラベラー、政府の秘密プロジェクト、自然現象など、これまで説明しようとするあらゆる努力に抵抗してきたこの現象に、斬新なアプローチを提供している。</p><p>超心理学、社会学、UFO学の研究を組み合わせ、オイエレットは、1952年のワシントンDCのUFOの波、1961年のベティとバーニー・ヒル誘拐事件、1980年のレンデルシャムUFO事件、1989年から1991年のベルギーのUFOの波など、いくつかの有名なUFO事件の再評価を示唆する。UFOの謎に対する最終的な解決策を持っていると主張するわけではないが、彼は、頑固なまでにとらえどころのない現象に対して、多くの考える材料と新鮮な展望を提供している。</p><p>「この分野における超心理学的なアプローチは稀である。-ジャック・ヴァレ、『見えない大学』の著者</p><p>「社会学者として、UFO目撃者として、さらに超心理学研究者として、エリック・オイエレットは、私が40年にわたるUFO調査の現場で遭遇した好奇心のバガテルを理解するためのすべての条件を満たしている。- ジェニー・ランドルズ、『マインド・モンスター』の著者</p><p>ERIC OUELLETは、カナダ王立陸軍大学およびカナダ軍大学（カナダの統合幕僚学校および陸軍大学）の国防学教授である。ヨーク大学（カナダ・トロント）で社会学の博士号を取得し、超心理学協会のカナダ担当連絡官を務める。オーストラリアン・ジャーナル・オブ・サイコロジー』、『エッジサイエンス』、『会報Métapsychique』に超心理学的研究を発表している。その他の研究テーマは軍事社会学と戦争研究である。</p><hr><p>What if UFO experiences are the result of large-scale, unconscious, psychic forces?</p><p>Parapsychology and UFOlogy are like oil and water. They just don't mix, despite the decades-long efforts of some highly respected researchers to call attention to the paranormal or parapsychological aspects of UFO events. In Illuminations, sociologist Eric Ouellet offers a novel approach to a phenomenon that has thus far resisted all other efforts to explain it, be it as extraterrestrial craft, time travelers, secret government projects, or natural phenomena.</p><p>Combining research in parapsychology, sociology, and UFOlogy, Ouellet provides a thought provoking reassessment of several well-known UFO cases, including the Washington, DC, UFO wave of 1952, the Betty and Barney Hill abduction of 1961, the Rendlesham UFO incident of 1980, and the Belgian UFO wave of 1989-1991. While not claiming to have the final solution to the UFO mystery, he offers much food for thought and a refreshing outlook on a stubbornly elusive phenomenon.</p><p>"Parapsychological approaches in this field are rare: your contribution is precious, and it is very timely." -Jacques Vallée, author of The Invisible College</p><p>"As a sociologist and a UFO witness, plus, importantly, a parapsychological researcher, Eric Ouellet ticks all the boxes to appreciate the bagatelle of curiosities that I have encountered in the field during 40 years of UFO investigation." - Jenny Randles, author of Mind Monsters</p><p>ERIC OUELLET is professor of Defence Studies at the Royal Military College of Canada, and at the Canadian Forces College (Canada's Joint Staff and War College). He has a Ph.D. in sociology from York University (Toronto, Canada), and he is the liaison officer for Canada with the Parapsychological Association. He has published parapsychological work in the Australian Journal of Psychology, EdgeScience, and the Bulletin Métapsychique. His other research works focus on military sociology and war studies.</p><p>ref: Amazon | Illuminations: The UFO Experience as a Parapsychological Event | Ouellet, Eric | Occult
<a href="https://www.amazon.co.jp/Illuminations-UFO-Experience-Parapsychological-Event/dp/193839853X" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">https://www.amazon.co.jp/Illuminations-UFO-Experience-Parapsychological-Event/dp/193839853X</a></p></blockquote></div></div></details>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="whisper-ailarge-v2-model--deepl">Whisper AI(large-v2 model) + DeepL<a class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Whisper AI(large-v2 model) + DeepL" title="Direct link to Whisper AI(large-v2 model) + DeepL" href="https://ouchaku.github.io/ds/en/blog/2024/07/18/eric_ouellet_sun_activity#whisper-ailarge-v2-model--deepl">​</a></h2>
<p>では、太陽活動が活発なときに、UFOの目撃情報は増えるのだろうか？
これについては、まだ結論が出ていない。
太陽活動が最大になるときと最小になるときでは、UFOの活動が多くなるようだ。
(00:49:02)</p>
<p>今、このことに関する研究とデータは古くなってきている。
しかし、UFOの波と、少なくとも多くのUFOを見ることと、太陽のサイクルには何らかの関係があるようだ。
(00:49:27)</p>
<hr>
<p>ロバート・ショックが本を出版して、超能力を実験室とかでテストするとき、テストされる人たちは太陽活動が活発な時期によくなることを示唆したんだ。
確かにそうだ。
それに関する研究もいくつかある。
また、ギャンブルでサイコロや何かを予言しようとする人たちの研究もいくつか覚えている。
(00:49:54)</p>
<p>ということは、何かありそうだ。
我々が持っている証拠はその方向を示しているが、明確なケースではない。
もしUFOがほとんど超常現象だとしたら、太陽活動もその一端を担っているような気がする。
そうだね。
でも、その関わり方はとても複雑で微妙だと思う。
(00:50:18)</p>
<p>それで、残念なことに、今の時代、昔のようによく調査されたUFOの報告はあまりない。
ショックには理由がある。UFOグループは昔よりずっと少なくなったからだ。
彼らはボランティアであり、時間とお金がある。
だから、目撃されたことについて何か奇妙なことが実際にあったのかどうか、綿密な調査をする時間がある人はあまりいないんだ。
(00:50:52)</p>
<p>そのため、現在ではUFOの数が多いかどうかを評価するのは難しい。なぜなら、報告書を評価する能力が昔より弱まっているからだ</p>
<hr>
<p>Now, do we see more UFO reports during high solar activity?
That jury is out on this.
It seems that when we have maximas of solar activities and when we have minimas, there seems to be more UFO activities.
(00:49:02)</p>
<p>Now, the research and the data on this is start to be dated.
So I don't know if we do research on this again, how well that hypothesis will survive, but there seems to be some sort of relationship between UFO waves and, or at least seeing a lot of UFOs and solar cycles.
(00:49:27)</p>
<hr>
<p>I know Robert Schock had published a book and it suggested that psychic abilities, like when they test them in laboratories and stuff, people being tested do better during periods of high solar activity.
Indeed, indeed.
There are some research on that.
I remember also some research of people gambling and try to predict whatever the dice or the things, and it seems to links to be linked somewhat to solar activities.
(00:49:54)</p>
<p>So there seems to be something there.
The evidence we have points in that direction, but it's not a clear cut case.
Yeah, but it seems like it might play a part in, you know, if UFOs are mostly paranormal, it seems like solar activity might play a part in that as well.
Yes, yes, I think so it does.
But I think the way, how it plays might be very complex and subtle.
(00:50:18)</p>
<p>So, and unfortunately I would say in this day and age, we don't have a lot of well investigated UFO reports as it was in the past.
Schock has a reason, mostly because UFO groups are way less now than there was in the past.
And, you know, they are volunteers and, you know, there's their time and their money.
So not many people have the time to do an in-depth investigation to see if, you know, was it, was there anything actually odd about the sighting or not?
(00:50:52)</p>
<p>So today's, it's hard to assess if there's more UFOs because of the capacity to assess the reporting is weaker now than it was in the past.</p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="動画12859">動画(1:28:59)<a class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to 動画(1:28:59)" title="Direct link to 動画(1:28:59)" href="https://ouchaku.github.io/ds/en/blog/2024/07/18/eric_ouellet_sun_activity#%E5%8B%95%E7%94%BB12859">​</a></h2>
<p>UFO's and Poltergeists with Eric Ouellet - July 11, 2024</p>
<iframe width="560" height="315" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/dPBHw12YCuU?si=Frq8sayKRIHGwgI5" title="YouTube video player" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin"></iframe>
<p><a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=dPBHw12YCuU" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">www.youtube.com/watch?v=dPBHw12YCuU</a></p>
<h3 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="動画概要欄">動画概要欄<a class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to 動画概要欄" title="Direct link to 動画概要欄" href="https://ouchaku.github.io/ds/en/blog/2024/07/18/eric_ouellet_sun_activity#%E5%8B%95%E7%94%BB%E6%A6%82%E8%A6%81%E6%AC%84">​</a></h3>
<p>1,700 views  Jul 15, 2024  2024 Shows
Originally aired on April 2, 2016</p>
<p>Since I reference this book a lot, I felt it was time to remaster and re-upload this show, with it's short Patreon segment as well.</p>
<p>Eric Ouellet joins me for a fascinating discussion of his new book, Illuminations: The UFO Experience as a Parapsychological Event. He proposes that we should examine the UFO Phenomenon as we would a poltergeist case. It's a novel way of looking at it, and may ultimately play a part in solving this enigma.</p>
<p>ERIC OUELLET is professor of Defence Studies at the Royal Military College of Canada, and at the Canadian Forces College (Canada's Joint Staff and War College). He has a Ph.D. in sociology from York University (Toronto, Canada), and he is the liaison officer for Canada with the Parapsychological Association. He has published parapsychological work in the Australian Journal of Psychology, EdgeScience, and the Bulletin Métapsychique. His other research works focus on military sociology and war studies.</p>
<p>(2024-07-18)</p>]]></content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Eric Ouellet：UFO はポルターガイスト現象として解釈できる]]></title>
        <id>https://ouchaku.github.io/ds/en/blog/2024/07/18/eric_ouellet_ufo_seemed_poltergeist</id>
        <link href="https://ouchaku.github.io/ds/en/blog/2024/07/18/eric_ouellet_ufo_seemed_poltergeist"/>
        <updated>2024-07-18T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[前置き]]></summary>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="前置き">前置き<a class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to 前置き" title="Direct link to 前置き" href="https://ouchaku.github.io/ds/en/blog/2024/07/18/eric_ouellet_ufo_seemed_poltergeist#%E5%89%8D%E7%BD%AE%E3%81%8D">​</a></h2>
<p>Eric Ouellet はカナダの社会学者で</p>
<p>Eric Ouellet, "Illuminations: The UFO Experience as a Parapsychological", Anomalist Books, 2015</p>
<p>という「UFO はポルターガイスト現象だ」という趣旨の著書(*1)も出している。彼のインタビュー動画からタイトルの件に絞る。</p>
<h3 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="1">(*1)<a class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to (*1)" title="Direct link to (*1)" href="https://ouchaku.github.io/ds/en/blog/2024/07/18/eric_ouellet_ufo_seemed_poltergeist#1">​</a></h3>
<details class="details_lb9f alert alert--info details_b_Ee" data-collapsed="true"><summary>▼展開</summary><div><div class="collapsibleContent_i85q"><blockquote><a href="https://ouchaku.github.io/ds/img/20240718_book.jpg" target="_blank"><img alt="20240718_book.jpg" border="0" src="https://ouchaku.github.io/ds/img/20240718_book.jpg" width="90%"></a><p>UFO体験が無意識の大規模な超能力の結果だとしたら？</p><p>超心理学とUFO学は油と水のようなものだ。何十年もの間、高名な研究者たちがUFO現象の超常現象や超心理学的側面に注目しようと努力してきたにもかかわらず、両者は混じり合わないのだ。社会学者エリック・オイエレットは『イルミネーションズ』の中で、地球外生命体、タイムトラベラー、政府の秘密プロジェクト、自然現象など、これまで説明しようとするあらゆる努力に抵抗してきたこの現象に、斬新なアプローチを提供している。</p><p>超心理学、社会学、UFO学の研究を組み合わせ、オイエレットは、1952年のワシントンDCのUFOの波、1961年のベティとバーニー・ヒル誘拐事件、1980年のレンデルシャムUFO事件、1989年から1991年のベルギーのUFOの波など、いくつかの有名なUFO事件の再評価を示唆する。UFOの謎に対する最終的な解決策を持っていると主張するわけではないが、彼は、頑固なまでにとらえどころのない現象に対して、多くの考える材料と新鮮な展望を提供している。</p><p>「この分野における超心理学的なアプローチは稀である。-ジャック・ヴァレ、『見えない大学』の著者</p><p>「社会学者として、UFO目撃者として、さらに超心理学研究者として、エリック・オイエレットは、私が40年にわたるUFO調査の現場で遭遇した好奇心のバガテルを理解するためのすべての条件を満たしている。- ジェニー・ランドルズ、『マインド・モンスター』の著者</p><p>ERIC OUELLETは、カナダ王立陸軍大学およびカナダ軍大学（カナダの統合幕僚学校および陸軍大学）の国防学教授である。ヨーク大学（カナダ・トロント）で社会学の博士号を取得し、超心理学協会のカナダ担当連絡官を務める。オーストラリアン・ジャーナル・オブ・サイコロジー』、『エッジサイエンス』、『会報Métapsychique』に超心理学的研究を発表している。その他の研究テーマは軍事社会学と戦争研究である。</p><hr><p>What if UFO experiences are the result of large-scale, unconscious, psychic forces?</p><p>Parapsychology and UFOlogy are like oil and water. They just don't mix, despite the decades-long efforts of some highly respected researchers to call attention to the paranormal or parapsychological aspects of UFO events. In Illuminations, sociologist Eric Ouellet offers a novel approach to a phenomenon that has thus far resisted all other efforts to explain it, be it as extraterrestrial craft, time travelers, secret government projects, or natural phenomena.</p><p>Combining research in parapsychology, sociology, and UFOlogy, Ouellet provides a thought provoking reassessment of several well-known UFO cases, including the Washington, DC, UFO wave of 1952, the Betty and Barney Hill abduction of 1961, the Rendlesham UFO incident of 1980, and the Belgian UFO wave of 1989-1991. While not claiming to have the final solution to the UFO mystery, he offers much food for thought and a refreshing outlook on a stubbornly elusive phenomenon.</p><p>"Parapsychological approaches in this field are rare: your contribution is precious, and it is very timely." -Jacques Vallée, author of The Invisible College</p><p>"As a sociologist and a UFO witness, plus, importantly, a parapsychological researcher, Eric Ouellet ticks all the boxes to appreciate the bagatelle of curiosities that I have encountered in the field during 40 years of UFO investigation." - Jenny Randles, author of Mind Monsters</p><p>ERIC OUELLET is professor of Defence Studies at the Royal Military College of Canada, and at the Canadian Forces College (Canada's Joint Staff and War College). He has a Ph.D. in sociology from York University (Toronto, Canada), and he is the liaison officer for Canada with the Parapsychological Association. He has published parapsychological work in the Australian Journal of Psychology, EdgeScience, and the Bulletin Métapsychique. His other research works focus on military sociology and war studies.</p><p>ref: Amazon | Illuminations: The UFO Experience as a Parapsychological Event | Ouellet, Eric | Occult
<a href="https://www.amazon.co.jp/Illuminations-UFO-Experience-Parapsychological-Event/dp/193839853X" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">https://www.amazon.co.jp/Illuminations-UFO-Experience-Parapsychological-Event/dp/193839853X</a></p></blockquote></div></div></details>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="whisper-ailarge-v2-model--deepl">Whisper AI(large-v2 model) + DeepL<a class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Whisper AI(large-v2 model) + DeepL" title="Direct link to Whisper AI(large-v2 model) + DeepL" href="https://ouchaku.github.io/ds/en/blog/2024/07/18/eric_ouellet_ufo_seemed_poltergeist#whisper-ailarge-v2-model--deepl">​</a></h2>
<p>そして、あなたが指摘している主なものは、ポルターガイスト事件の見解である。
そうだね。
私の本では、ドイツの超心理学者、ヴァルター・フォン・ルカドゥがポルターガイストを研究するために開発したモデルを使っているんだ。
(00:15:47)</p>
<p>しかし、ポルターガイストとは、超心理学の観点から言うと、霊や幽霊のようなものではなく、ある個人がその環境、つまり周囲の人々と連動して、サイコキネシス、つまりマインド・オーバー・マターを使って、物を動かしたり、音を出したり、申し訳ないが、本当に奇妙で奇妙な状況を作り出すことである。
しかし、それは個人、または個人とそれに関与する人々のグループである。
(00:16:24)</p>
<p>だから、私はそのモデルを使っているんだ。でも規模は違うけど、UFOがポルターガイストとして展開する可能性を見ている。
だから、私の本の大部分はそのアプローチを使っている。
例えば、誰かが空に光を見たなら、それは地球外生命体に違いない。しかし、家の中で同じような光を見たら、それは幽霊に違いない。
(00:16:46)</p>
<p>まったくだ。
(00:16:47)</p>
<hr>
<p>そしてそれは、場違いなもの、奇妙なもの、異様なものという知覚の問題なんだ。
そして、その奇妙なことの解釈は全く別のものだ。
そして、物事の解釈の仕方は、私たちが何を信じ、何を心に抱いているかに大きく関係していることを知っている。
だから、私たち人間、私たちの文化、私たちの信念、私たち個人の心理、私たちが奇妙な現象をどのように表現するか、どのように報告するか、どのように汚すか、そのような側面を調べることはとても重要なことなのだ。
(00:17:29)</p>
<hr>
<p>And the main thing you point to is the view of poltergeist cases.
Yes.
In my book, I'm using a model that was developed by a parapsychologist from Germany, Walter von Lukadu, to study poltergeist.
(00:15:47)</p>
<p>But poltergeist, again, from a point of view of parapsychology, is not a spirit or some sort of ghosts, but one individual in conjunctions with his or her environment, so the other people around, who through the use of psychokinesis, so mind over matter, make things move, create sounds, sorry, and really create a situation that is really strange and weird.
But that's an individual or person and a group of person that are involved in that.
(00:16:24)</p>
<p>And so I'm using that model, but on a different scale, look at could UFO unfold as a poltergeist.
And so a good chunk of my book is using that approach.
And we've noted on this show many times before that, for instance, if someone sees a light in the sky, it must be extraterrestrials, but you see a light in a house, the same type of light in a house, and now it's a ghost.
(00:16:46)</p>
<p>Absolutely.
(00:16:47)</p>
<hr>
<p>And that's really here an issue of the perception of something that is out of place, that is strange, that is bizarre, that's one thing.
And then the interpretation of that bizarre thing is quite another one.
And we know that the way we interpret things has a lot to do with what we believe and what we have in our minds.
So it's very important to look into that aspect of us human, our culture, our beliefs, our individual psychology, how it's actually taint or how we report, how we describe strange phenomena.
(00:17:29)</p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="動画12859">動画(1:28:59)<a class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to 動画(1:28:59)" title="Direct link to 動画(1:28:59)" href="https://ouchaku.github.io/ds/en/blog/2024/07/18/eric_ouellet_ufo_seemed_poltergeist#%E5%8B%95%E7%94%BB12859">​</a></h2>
<p>UFO's and Poltergeists with Eric Ouellet - July 11, 2024</p>
<iframe width="560" height="315" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/dPBHw12YCuU?si=Frq8sayKRIHGwgI5" title="YouTube video player" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin"></iframe>
<p><a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=dPBHw12YCuU" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">www.youtube.com/watch?v=dPBHw12YCuU</a></p>
<h3 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="動画概要欄">動画概要欄<a class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to 動画概要欄" title="Direct link to 動画概要欄" href="https://ouchaku.github.io/ds/en/blog/2024/07/18/eric_ouellet_ufo_seemed_poltergeist#%E5%8B%95%E7%94%BB%E6%A6%82%E8%A6%81%E6%AC%84">​</a></h3>
<p>1,700 views  Jul 15, 2024  2024 Shows
Originally aired on April 2, 2016</p>
<p>Since I reference this book a lot, I felt it was time to remaster and re-upload this show, with it's short Patreon segment as well.</p>
<p>Eric Ouellet joins me for a fascinating discussion of his new book, Illuminations: The UFO Experience as a Parapsychological Event. He proposes that we should examine the UFO Phenomenon as we would a poltergeist case. It's a novel way of looking at it, and may ultimately play a part in solving this enigma.</p>
<p>ERIC OUELLET is professor of Defence Studies at the Royal Military College of Canada, and at the Canadian Forces College (Canada's Joint Staff and War College). He has a Ph.D. in sociology from York University (Toronto, Canada), and he is the liaison officer for Canada with the Parapsychological Association. He has published parapsychological work in the Australian Journal of Psychology, EdgeScience, and the Bulletin Métapsychique. His other research works focus on military sociology and war studies.</p>
<p>(2024-07-18)</p>]]></content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Eric Ouellet：米政府は UFO を超心理学の観点から調査している ⇒ DoD が UFO/UAP の武器応用を検討した公式書類があるのだが？]]></title>
        <id>https://ouchaku.github.io/ds/en/blog/2024/07/18/ric_ouellet_gvmt</id>
        <link href="https://ouchaku.github.io/ds/en/blog/2024/07/18/ric_ouellet_gvmt"/>
        <updated>2024-07-18T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[前置き]]></summary>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="前置き">前置き<a class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to 前置き" title="Direct link to 前置き" href="https://ouchaku.github.io/ds/en/blog/2024/07/18/ric_ouellet_gvmt#%E5%89%8D%E7%BD%AE%E3%81%8D">​</a></h2>
<p>Eric Ouellet はカナダの社会学者で</p>
<p>Eric Ouellet, "Illuminations: The UFO Experience as a Parapsychological", Anomalist Books, 2015</p>
<p>という「UFO はポルターガイスト現象だ」という趣旨の著書(*1)も出している。彼のインタビュー動画からタイトルの件に絞る。</p>
<h3 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="1">(*1)<a class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to (*1)" title="Direct link to (*1)" href="https://ouchaku.github.io/ds/en/blog/2024/07/18/ric_ouellet_gvmt#1">​</a></h3>
<details class="details_lb9f alert alert--info details_b_Ee" data-collapsed="true"><summary>▼展開</summary><div><div class="collapsibleContent_i85q"><blockquote><a href="https://ouchaku.github.io/ds/img/20240718_book.jpg" target="_blank"><img alt="20240718_book.jpg" border="0" src="https://ouchaku.github.io/ds/img/20240718_book.jpg" width="90%"></a><p>UFO体験が無意識の大規模な超能力の結果だとしたら？</p><p>超心理学とUFO学は油と水のようなものだ。何十年もの間、高名な研究者たちがUFO現象の超常現象や超心理学的側面に注目しようと努力してきたにもかかわらず、両者は混じり合わないのだ。社会学者エリック・オイエレットは『イルミネーションズ』の中で、地球外生命体、タイムトラベラー、政府の秘密プロジェクト、自然現象など、これまで説明しようとするあらゆる努力に抵抗してきたこの現象に、斬新なアプローチを提供している。</p><p>超心理学、社会学、UFO学の研究を組み合わせ、オイエレットは、1952年のワシントンDCのUFOの波、1961年のベティとバーニー・ヒル誘拐事件、1980年のレンデルシャムUFO事件、1989年から1991年のベルギーのUFOの波など、いくつかの有名なUFO事件の再評価を示唆する。UFOの謎に対する最終的な解決策を持っていると主張するわけではないが、彼は、頑固なまでにとらえどころのない現象に対して、多くの考える材料と新鮮な展望を提供している。</p><p>「この分野における超心理学的なアプローチは稀である。-ジャック・ヴァレ、『見えない大学』の著者</p><p>「社会学者として、UFO目撃者として、さらに超心理学研究者として、エリック・オイエレットは、私が40年にわたるUFO調査の現場で遭遇した好奇心のバガテルを理解するためのすべての条件を満たしている。- ジェニー・ランドルズ、『マインド・モンスター』の著者</p><p>ERIC OUELLETは、カナダ王立陸軍大学およびカナダ軍大学（カナダの統合幕僚学校および陸軍大学）の国防学教授である。ヨーク大学（カナダ・トロント）で社会学の博士号を取得し、超心理学協会のカナダ担当連絡官を務める。オーストラリアン・ジャーナル・オブ・サイコロジー』、『エッジサイエンス』、『会報Métapsychique』に超心理学的研究を発表している。その他の研究テーマは軍事社会学と戦争研究である。</p><hr><p>What if UFO experiences are the result of large-scale, unconscious, psychic forces?</p><p>Parapsychology and UFOlogy are like oil and water. They just don't mix, despite the decades-long efforts of some highly respected researchers to call attention to the paranormal or parapsychological aspects of UFO events. In Illuminations, sociologist Eric Ouellet offers a novel approach to a phenomenon that has thus far resisted all other efforts to explain it, be it as extraterrestrial craft, time travelers, secret government projects, or natural phenomena.</p><p>Combining research in parapsychology, sociology, and UFOlogy, Ouellet provides a thought provoking reassessment of several well-known UFO cases, including the Washington, DC, UFO wave of 1952, the Betty and Barney Hill abduction of 1961, the Rendlesham UFO incident of 1980, and the Belgian UFO wave of 1989-1991. While not claiming to have the final solution to the UFO mystery, he offers much food for thought and a refreshing outlook on a stubbornly elusive phenomenon.</p><p>"Parapsychological approaches in this field are rare: your contribution is precious, and it is very timely." -Jacques Vallée, author of The Invisible College</p><p>"As a sociologist and a UFO witness, plus, importantly, a parapsychological researcher, Eric Ouellet ticks all the boxes to appreciate the bagatelle of curiosities that I have encountered in the field during 40 years of UFO investigation." - Jenny Randles, author of Mind Monsters</p><p>ERIC OUELLET is professor of Defence Studies at the Royal Military College of Canada, and at the Canadian Forces College (Canada's Joint Staff and War College). He has a Ph.D. in sociology from York University (Toronto, Canada), and he is the liaison officer for Canada with the Parapsychological Association. He has published parapsychological work in the Australian Journal of Psychology, EdgeScience, and the Bulletin Métapsychique. His other research works focus on military sociology and war studies.</p><p>ref: Amazon | Illuminations: The UFO Experience as a Parapsychological Event | Ouellet, Eric | Occult
<a href="https://www.amazon.co.jp/Illuminations-UFO-Experience-Parapsychological-Event/dp/193839853X" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">https://www.amazon.co.jp/Illuminations-UFO-Experience-Parapsychological-Event/dp/193839853X</a></p></blockquote></div></div></details>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="whisper-ailarge-v2-model--deepl">Whisper AI(large-v2 model) + DeepL<a class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Whisper AI(large-v2 model) + DeepL" title="Direct link to Whisper AI(large-v2 model) + DeepL" href="https://ouchaku.github.io/ds/en/blog/2024/07/18/ric_ouellet_gvmt#whisper-ailarge-v2-model--deepl">​</a></h2>
<p>例えば、政府の中に、本当は何が起こっているのかを理解している人がいると思う？
地球外生命体という考えではなく、この現象が本当は何なのか、もっとよく分かっているのではないだろうか？
現時点ではわからない。
(00:13:22)</p>
<p>でも、世界中のほとんどの政府は、この現象にまったく関心を持っていないと思うよ。
それは確かだ。
しかし、CIAの公開ウェブサイトを見ると、70年代と80年代には多少の関心を持っていた。
そして、超心理学の観点からこの問題を調査している。
つまり、超常現象や超心理学的な何かが存在するという同じ方向に向かっていたのだと思う。
(00:13:56)</p>
<p>でも、これも推測に過ぎない。
だから彼らは諦めたんだ、証拠がなかったから。
彼らにはもっと大きな獲物があったのだろう。
彼らはまた、マインドコントロールの実験や、UFOグループとの工作なども行っているようだ。
ああ、おそらく過去にいくつかの実験が行われたんだろう。
とても残念なことだけど、そういうこともあったと思う。
(00:14:23)</p>
<hr>
<p>Do you think there's any level of government that may understand, for instance, what's really going on?
Not so much an extraterrestrial idea, but may have a better idea of what the phenomena really is?
At the present time, I don't know.
(00:13:22)</p>
<p>But I would think that most governments in the world have absolutely no interest in the phenomenon.
So I'm pretty sure of that.
However, if you go on the public website of the CIA, they had some interest in the 70s and 80s.
And they look into the top, the issue from a parapsychology perspective.
So I think that their thinking was, I mean, the few there in the CIA that had an interest in that, I think the thinking was going in the same direction that there's something paranormal or parapsychological.
(00:13:56)</p>
<p>But again, there were just probably speculations.
And that's why they gave up, because they didn't have evidence.
And they had probably much bigger fish to fry.
They also seem to be experimenting with mind control and just manipulation with UFO groups and stuff as well.
Yeah, there's probably been some experiments that have been done in the past.
Very unfortunately, I would think that happened.
(00:14:23)</p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="コメント">コメント<a class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to コメント" title="Direct link to コメント" href="https://ouchaku.github.io/ds/en/blog/2024/07/18/ric_ouellet_gvmt#%E3%82%B3%E3%83%A1%E3%83%B3%E3%83%88">​</a></h2>
<p>Eric Ouellet の主張は正しくない（不完全）。DoD の公式書類には UFO/UAP の武器応用が列挙されている。</p>
<p>こういった発言に事欠かないゆえに Eric Ouellet は信用できない。</p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="動画12859">動画(1:28:59)<a class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to 動画(1:28:59)" title="Direct link to 動画(1:28:59)" href="https://ouchaku.github.io/ds/en/blog/2024/07/18/ric_ouellet_gvmt#%E5%8B%95%E7%94%BB12859">​</a></h2>
<p>UFO's and Poltergeists with Eric Ouellet - July 11, 2024</p>
<iframe width="560" height="315" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/dPBHw12YCuU?si=Frq8sayKRIHGwgI5" title="YouTube video player" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin"></iframe>
<p><a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=dPBHw12YCuU" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">www.youtube.com/watch?v=dPBHw12YCuU</a></p>
<h3 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="動画概要欄">動画概要欄<a class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to 動画概要欄" title="Direct link to 動画概要欄" href="https://ouchaku.github.io/ds/en/blog/2024/07/18/ric_ouellet_gvmt#%E5%8B%95%E7%94%BB%E6%A6%82%E8%A6%81%E6%AC%84">​</a></h3>
<p>1,700 views  Jul 15, 2024  2024 Shows
Originally aired on April 2, 2016</p>
<p>Since I reference this book a lot, I felt it was time to remaster and re-upload this show, with it's short Patreon segment as well.</p>
<p>Eric Ouellet joins me for a fascinating discussion of his new book, Illuminations: The UFO Experience as a Parapsychological Event. He proposes that we should examine the UFO Phenomenon as we would a poltergeist case. It's a novel way of looking at it, and may ultimately play a part in solving this enigma.</p>
<p>ERIC OUELLET is professor of Defence Studies at the Royal Military College of Canada, and at the Canadian Forces College (Canada's Joint Staff and War College). He has a Ph.D. in sociology from York University (Toronto, Canada), and he is the liaison officer for Canada with the Parapsychological Association. He has published parapsychological work in the Australian Journal of Psychology, EdgeScience, and the Bulletin Métapsychique. His other research works focus on military sociology and war studies.</p>
<p>(2024-07-18)</p>]]></content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Micah Hanks：1639, Massachusetts：John Winthrop らが目撃した UFO＋不可解な目撃者の移動 ⇒ この謎を解く]]></title>
        <id>https://ouchaku.github.io/ds/en/blog/2024/07/17/1639</id>
        <link href="https://ouchaku.github.io/ds/en/blog/2024/07/17/1639"/>
        <updated>2024-07-17T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[前置き]]></summary>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="前置き">前置き<a class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to 前置き" title="Direct link to 前置き" href="https://ouchaku.github.io/ds/en/blog/2024/07/17/1639#%E5%89%8D%E7%BD%AE%E3%81%8D">​</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>前半は退屈な内容。40:00 ごろからようやく本題。</li>
</ul>
<a href="https://ouchaku.github.io/ds/img/20240717_micah_hanks_rz.jpg" target="_blank"><img alt="20240717_micah_hanks_rz.jpg" border="0" src="https://ouchaku.github.io/ds/img/20240717_micah_hanks_rz.jpg" width="90%"></a>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="ocr--deepl">OCR + DeepL<a class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to OCR + DeepL" title="Direct link to OCR + DeepL" href="https://ouchaku.github.io/ds/en/blog/2024/07/17/1639#ocr--deepl">​</a></h2>
<a href="https://ouchaku.github.io/ds/img/20240717_1639__rz.jpg" target="_blank"><img alt="20240717_1639__rz.jpg" border="0" src="https://ouchaku.github.io/ds/img/20240717_1639__rz.jpg" width="90%"></a>
<p>初期ニューイングランドのUFO</p>
<ul>
<li>
<p>日付：1639年</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>場所：マサチューセッツ州マディー・リバー（現在のブルックライン）。</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>説明：ジョン・ウィンスロップは、ジェームズ・エベレルと他の2人の男が異常な光に遭遇したことを語っている：
「この年、真面目で慎重な男ジェームズ・エベレルと他の2人が、マディ・リバーで夜中に大きな光を見た。
静止しているときは燃え上がり、3ヤード四方ほどの大きさであった。走るときは豚の形に縮まり、矢のように素早くチャールトンに向かって走り、2～3時間ほど上下した。
チャールトンに向かって矢のように速く走り、2、3時間かけて上下した。彼らは1マイルほど下ったところで身軽になり、それが終わると、潮に逆らって元来た場所まで引き戻された。他の信頼できるダイバーも、同じ場所で同じ光を見た。"</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>出典 ウィンスロップの日記、「ニューイングランドの歴史」、1630-1649年、第1巻。</p>
</li>
</ul>
<hr>
<p>UFOs IN EARLY NEW ENGLAND</p>
<ul>
<li>
<p>DATE: 1639</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>LOCATION: Muddy River (now Brookline), Massachusetts.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>DESCRIPTION: John Winthrop gives an account of James Everell and two other men's encounter with an unusual light:
"In this year one James Everell, a sober, discreet man, and two others, saw a great light in the night at Muddy River.
When it stood still, it flamed up, and was about three yards square; when it ran, it was contracted into the figure of a swine : it ran as swift as an arrow towards Charlton, and so up and down about two or three hours.
They were come down in their lighter about a mile, and, when it was over, they found themselves carried quite back against the tide to the place they came from. Divers other credible persons saw the same light, after, about the same place."</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>SOURCE: Winthrop's Journal, "History of New England," 1630-1649, Volume I.</p>
</li>
</ul>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="この謎を解く">この謎を解く<a class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to この謎を解く" title="Direct link to この謎を解く" href="https://ouchaku.github.io/ds/en/blog/2024/07/17/1639#%E3%81%93%E3%81%AE%E8%AC%8E%E3%82%92%E8%A7%A3%E3%81%8F">​</a></h2>
<p>この現象は orb ＋ 大気中の発光現象で説明がつく。</p>
<p>さらに、</p>
<blockquote><p>豚の描写も奇妙だが、おそらく最も重要なのは、光を観察した男たちが、自分たちが思っていたよりも渓流の奥にいることに気がついたようだという事実である。
(00:42:01)</p><hr><p>そして、ある人たちはこれを、ある種の、行方不明の時の人工物と呼ぶかもしれない、あるいはまた、現代のUFO研究において、アブダクション体験と称されるものが認識されていることになぞらえた。さて、それがここで起きたことなのだろうか？</p></blockquote>
<p>は意識障害が起きていたことを示している。</p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="whisper-ailarge-v2-model--deepl">Whisper AI(large-v2 model) + DeepL<a class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Whisper AI(large-v2 model) + DeepL" title="Direct link to Whisper AI(large-v2 model) + DeepL" href="https://ouchaku.github.io/ds/en/blog/2024/07/17/1639#whisper-ailarge-v2-model--deepl">​</a></h2>
<p>次に、ジョン・ウィンスロップの日記『1630年から1649年までのニューイングランドの歴史』を見てみよう。
ウィンスロップが1639年ごろに残した記録には、非常に興味深いものがいくつかある。
マディ・リバーでの最初のもので、これは私のお気に入りの一つである。
(00:40:57)</p>
<p>ジョン・ウィンスロップは、ジェームズ・エヴリルと他の2人の男が異常な光に遭遇したことを語っている。
これは彼の日記からの実際の記述である。
この年、真面目で慎重な男ジェームス・エヴリルと他の二人は、マディ・リバーで夜中に大きな光を見た。
静止しているとき、それは燃え上がり、3ヤード四方ほどの大きさだった。
それが走ったとき、ところで、これは彼の言う描写の中で最も奇妙なことだが、彼はそれが豚の姿に収縮していたと言った。
(00:41:22)</p>
<p>それは矢のように素早くチャールトンに向かって走った。
そうして2時間か3時間くらい上下していた。
それが終わると、彼ら、また船頭たちは、潮に逆らって、自分たちが来た場所までかなり引き戻されているのに気がついた。
他の信頼できるさまざまな人々も、ほぼ同じ時刻に同じ光を見た。
さて、ここでもまた、非常にユニークな現象が描写されていることに、私はまず気づかないだろう。
(00:41:49)</p>
<p>豚の描写も奇妙だが、おそらく最も重要なのは、光を観察した男たちが、自分たちが思っていたよりも渓流の奥にいることに気がついたようだという事実である。
(00:42:01)</p>
<hr>
<p>そして、ある人たちはこれを、ある種の、行方不明の時の人工物と呼ぶかもしれない、あるいはまた、現代のUFO研究において、アブダクション体験と称されるものが認識されていることになぞらえた。さて、それがここで起きたことなのだろうか？
そうとは言い切れないが、根本的には、この類似性を認識することが重要だと思う。</p>
<hr>
<p>And we now look at John Winthrop's journal, The History of New England from 1630 to 1649.
There are a couple of very interesting accounts that Winthrop gives us from around 1639.
This first one from the Muddy River, and this is maybe one of my very favorites, and I'll just read briefly from the description in my notes here.
(00:40:57)</p>
<p>John Winthrop gives an account of James Everill and two other men's encounter with an unusual light.
And this is the actual account from his journal.
In this year one, James Everill, a sober, discreet man, and two others, saw a great light in the night at Muddy River.
When it stood still, it flamed up and was about three yards square.
When it ran, and this is most strange, by the way, the description he gives, but he said it was contracted into the figure of a swine.
(00:41:22)</p>
<p>It ran as swift as an arrow towards Charlton.
And so up and down about two or three hours.
They were come down in their lighter about a mile, and when it was over, they, again, the boatmen, found themselves carried quite back against the tide to the place they came from.
Diverse other credible persons saw the same light after about the same time.
Now, I wouldn't be the first to notice that, again, there are some very unique phenomena being described here.
(00:41:49)</p>
<p>The description of the swine is strange, but perhaps most significant is the fact that the men who observed the light seemed to feel that they had found themselves further back up the stream than they had thought that they were.
(00:42:01)</p>
<hr>
<p>And some have likened this very much to sort of, you might call them, artifacts of missing time or again, what is purportedly the abduction experience is recognized in modern UFO research. Now, is that what happened here?
We can't say that, but again, fundamentally, I think it's important to recognize that similarity.</p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="動画10046">動画(1:00:46)<a class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to 動画(1:00:46)" title="Direct link to 動画(1:00:46)" href="https://ouchaku.github.io/ds/en/blog/2024/07/17/1639#%E5%8B%95%E7%94%BB10046">​</a></h2>
<p>Anomaly Archives Saturday Streamathon Fundraiser Series 4.3 Micah Hanks</p>
<iframe width="560" height="315" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/77rnKnFmjZw?si=OSoINEa5K4JBmeA9" title="YouTube video player" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin"></iframe>
<p><a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=77rnKnFmjZw" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=77rnKnFmjZw</a></p>
<h3 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="動画概要欄">動画概要欄<a class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to 動画概要欄" title="Direct link to 動画概要欄" href="https://ouchaku.github.io/ds/en/blog/2024/07/17/1639#%E5%8B%95%E7%94%BB%E6%A6%82%E8%A6%81%E6%AC%84">​</a></h3>
<p>30 views  Dec 22, 2020
Anomaly Archives Saturday Streamathon Fundraiser Series 4.3 Micah Hanks</p>
<p>The Anomaly Archives Saturday Streamathons are a series of emergency fundraiser telethons happening each Saturday until 2021.</p>
<p>03:15 pm – Micah Hanks – “UFOs: A Historical Perspective”</p>
<p>We are raising funds to ensure our continued survival into 2021 and beyond. We're drawing together researchers from all corners of the Esoterica realms: Anomalistics, Cryptozoology, Forteana, Parapsychology, and Ufology. We'll be streaming many hours of great content covering these and other fields of inquiry. We'll be sharing a sort of "Fabulous Fortean Film Festival" evening, Plus Music and MORE! All in an effort to raise funds for our 501(c)3 nonprofit community organization to survive the circumstances created by this terrible Covid-Crisis.</p>
<p>(2024-07-17)</p>]]></content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Micah Hanks： 1644-01-18 Massachusetts の事例]]></title>
        <id>https://ouchaku.github.io/ds/en/blog/2024/07/17/1644_01_18</id>
        <link href="https://ouchaku.github.io/ds/en/blog/2024/07/17/1644_01_18"/>
        <updated>2024-07-17T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[前置き]]></summary>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="前置き">前置き<a class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to 前置き" title="Direct link to 前置き" href="https://ouchaku.github.io/ds/en/blog/2024/07/17/1644_01_18#%E5%89%8D%E7%BD%AE%E3%81%8D">​</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>前半は退屈な内容。40:00 ごろからようやく本題。</li>
</ul>
<a href="https://ouchaku.github.io/ds/img/20240717_micah_hanks_rz.jpg" target="_blank"><img alt="20240717_micah_hanks_rz.jpg" border="0" src="https://ouchaku.github.io/ds/img/20240717_micah_hanks_rz.jpg" width="90%"></a>
<ul>
<li>この事件は下の過去記事で取り上げた。</li>
</ul>
<p><a href="http://news21c.blog.fc2.com/blog-entry-4754.html" target="_blank">1638 or 1639年3月：アメリカで記録された最も古い UFO 遭遇事件 （追加）</a> (2014-11-26)</p>
<ul>
<li>この UFO の正体は orb だった筈。</li>
</ul>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="ocr--deepl">OCR + DeepL<a class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to OCR + DeepL" title="Direct link to OCR + DeepL" href="https://ouchaku.github.io/ds/en/blog/2024/07/17/1644_01_18#ocr--deepl">​</a></h2>
<a href="https://ouchaku.github.io/ds/img/20240717_1644_01_18_rz.jpg" target="_blank"><img alt="20240717_1644_01_18_rz.jpg" border="0" src="https://ouchaku.github.io/ds/img/20240717_1644_01_18_rz.jpg" width="90%"></a>
<ul>
<li>
<p>日付：1644年1月18日（日記）</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>場所：マサチューセッツ州ボストン、ボストン港。</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>説明：ジョン・ウィンスロップは、1644年1月18日の日記の中で、何度かボストン港から目撃された光についての説明をしている：「真夜中頃、ボストンにボートで来ていた3人の男が、町の入り江の北のポイントの近くで、人のような形をした2つの光が水面から浮かび上がるのを見た。
町と総督の庭の間にいた彼らは、約25分後に彼らを見た。その1週間後、同じようなものがキャッスル島付近で目撃され、5分の1時間でジョン・ギャロップのポイントにやってきた。"</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>出典 ウィンスロップの日記、『ニューイングランド史』、1630-1649年、第2巻。</p>
</li>
</ul>
<hr>
<ul>
<li>
<p>DATE: January 18, 1644 (journal entry)</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>LOCATION: Boston Harbor, Boston, Massachusetts.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>DESCRIPTION: John Winthrop gives an account of lights seen from Boston Harbor on several occasions, in a journal entry dated January 18, 1644: "About midnight, three men, coming in a boat to Boston, saw two lights arise out of the water near the north point of the town cove, in form like a man, and went at a small distance to the town, and so to the south point, and there vanished away.
They saw them about a quarter of an hour, being between the town and the governor's garden. The like was seen by many, a week after, arising about Castle Island and in one fifth of an hour came to John Gallop's point."</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>SOURCE: Winthrop's Journal, "History of New England," 1630-1649, Volume II.</p>
</li>
</ul>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="whisper-ailarge-v2-model--deepl">Whisper AI(large-v2 model) + DeepL<a class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Whisper AI(large-v2 model) + DeepL" title="Direct link to Whisper AI(large-v2 model) + DeepL" href="https://ouchaku.github.io/ds/en/blog/2024/07/17/1644_01_18#whisper-ailarge-v2-model--deepl">​</a></h2>
<p>このような奇妙な、時間の欠落のような体験は時々ある。
おそらくこれもそのひとつだろう。
ウィンスロップの日記からもう一つ、これも非常に興味深い。
1664年1月18日、つまり1644年が日記の日付である。
この時、マサチューセッツに近いボストン港の近くで観測されたもので、ジョン・ウィンスロップは港から上がってくる光について次のように語っている。そして彼は言った、港から上ってくると。
(00:43:50)</p>
<p>そして彼は言った、真夜中ごろ、ボストンに船で来ていた3人の男が、町の入り江の北の近くの水面から2つの光が生じるのを見た。彼は、この時、人のような形をした豚ではなく、むしろ人のような形をした豚で、町まで少し離れて行き、そうして南の点まで行き、そこで消え去ったと言う。
彼らは、町と総督の庭の間で、約25分ほど彼らを見た。
(00:44:11)</p>
<p>同じようなことは、キャッスル島で発生した1週間後に多くの人に目撃され、5分の1時間でジョン・ギャロップの地点に来た。
この件に関して本当に興味深いのは、やはり時間をかけて、港から光が昇ってくるのを何度も観測していることだ。
ウィンスロップは日誌の中で、目撃の理由についてさらなる推測を述べている。そして、本質的に難破船があり、そこで人が死んでいた。ウィンスロップの目撃談。
(00:44:35)</p>
<p>そして、本質的に人が死んだ難破船があった。ウィンスロップや他の人たちは、おそらくその光は男の霊の存在なのだろうと考えていた。
(00:44:48)</p>
<hr>
<p>しかし、もちろん、私が本当に興味を持っているのは、UFOとして知られている現象、水の中に入っていく光、水の中で見られる光は、決して新しい現象ではないという事実である。UFOを研究する国防総省の現在の取り組み、すなわちUAPタスクフォースが注目するようになったのは確かだ。
そして、私の同僚であるティム・マクミランは、私たちのサイト、thedebrief.orgの彼の記事の中で、USOやこれらの水中UFOが今、主要な関心事であるようだという事実に触れている。
(00:45:27)</p>
<p>しかし、ウィンスロップが1644年にボストン港上空で目撃した、少なくともUSOと呼べるような、あるいはUFOと思われるものが水面から現れたという目撃談は、大いにあり得るだろう。
さてさて、実はそろそろ適切な時期なのだが、今日は少しスコッチを飲むのにふさわしい土曜日だと思わないか？たまには笛を吹かねばなるまい。
(00:45:54)</p>
<hr>
<p>So these kinds of strange, missing time-like experiences do turn up from time to time.
Perhaps this is one such instance.
Another that comes to us from Winthrop's journal, this one also very interesting.
January 18th, 1664 is the date of the journal, or 1644 was the date of the journal entry.
This time, an observation made near Boston Harbor there near Massachusetts, or at Massachusetts, where John Winthrop gives the following account of lights that had been seen coming up out of the harbor. And he said, coming up out of the harbor.
(00:43:50)</p>
<p>And he said, About midnight, three men coming in a boat to Boston saw two lights arise out of the water near the north point of the town cove. He says this time rather than a swine in the form like a man and went at a small distance to the town and so to the south point and there vanished away.
They saw them about a quarter of an hour being between the town and the governor's garden.
(00:44:11)</p>
<p>The like was seen by many a week after arising about Castle Island and in one fifth of an hour came to John Gallop's point.
Now what's really interesting about this one is again, we seem to see over time, several observations of lights rising up out of the harbor.
Now Winthrop in his journal gave further suppositions about what might account for the sightings. And there had been a shipwreck essentially where a man had died. Winthrop sightings.
(00:44:35)</p>
<p>And there had been a shipwreck essentially where a man had died. Winthrop and others had thought that perhaps the lights were the presence of the man's spirit, which yet again, gives us through the lens of a cultural interpretation, one reason why people might have ascribed a human light form to the light.
(00:44:48)</p>
<hr>
<p>But of course, what really interests me is the fact that the phenomena known as UFOs, lights being seen coming out of going into water, being seen below water, that is by no means a new phenomenon. And it's certainly something that has apparently come to the attention of the current Pentagon efforts to study UFOs, i.e. the UAP task force.
And my colleague, Tim McMillan, in his article there at our site, thedebrief.org, touched on the fact that USOs or these underwater UFOs seem to be a primary interest right now and something that I think we're going to be hearing a lot more about in weeks and months to come.
(00:45:27)</p>
<p>But it very well may be that Winthrop gives us here from 1644, a sighting of effectively what we could at least call a USO or what appears to be a UFO arriving out of the water over Boston Harbor.
Now, fairly, you know, actually it's about time it would be apropos, I think, it being a Saturday for a little scotch, don't you? One must wet the proverbial whistle from time to time.
(00:45:54)</p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="動画10046">動画(1:00:46)<a class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to 動画(1:00:46)" title="Direct link to 動画(1:00:46)" href="https://ouchaku.github.io/ds/en/blog/2024/07/17/1644_01_18#%E5%8B%95%E7%94%BB10046">​</a></h2>
<p>Anomaly Archives Saturday Streamathon Fundraiser Series 4.3 Micah Hanks</p>
<iframe width="560" height="315" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/77rnKnFmjZw?si=OSoINEa5K4JBmeA9" title="YouTube video player" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin"></iframe>
<p><a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=77rnKnFmjZw" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=77rnKnFmjZw</a></p>
<h3 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="動画概要欄">動画概要欄<a class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to 動画概要欄" title="Direct link to 動画概要欄" href="https://ouchaku.github.io/ds/en/blog/2024/07/17/1644_01_18#%E5%8B%95%E7%94%BB%E6%A6%82%E8%A6%81%E6%AC%84">​</a></h3>
<p>30 views  Dec 22, 2020
Anomaly Archives Saturday Streamathon Fundraiser Series 4.3 Micah Hanks</p>
<p>The Anomaly Archives Saturday Streamathons are a series of emergency fundraiser telethons happening each Saturday until 2021.</p>
<p>03:15 pm – Micah Hanks – “UFOs: A Historical Perspective”</p>
<p>We are raising funds to ensure our continued survival into 2021 and beyond. We're drawing together researchers from all corners of the Esoterica realms: Anomalistics, Cryptozoology, Forteana, Parapsychology, and Ufology. We'll be streaming many hours of great content covering these and other fields of inquiry. We'll be sharing a sort of "Fabulous Fortean Film Festival" evening, Plus Music and MORE! All in an effort to raise funds for our 501(c)3 nonprofit community organization to survive the circumstances created by this terrible Covid-Crisis.</p>
<p>(2024-07-17)</p>]]></content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Micah Hanks：1890年頃の謎の飛行船]]></title>
        <id>https://ouchaku.github.io/ds/en/blog/2024/07/17/1890_airship</id>
        <link href="https://ouchaku.github.io/ds/en/blog/2024/07/17/1890_airship"/>
        <updated>2024-07-17T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[前置き]]></summary>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="前置き">前置き<a class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to 前置き" title="Direct link to 前置き" href="https://ouchaku.github.io/ds/en/blog/2024/07/17/1890_airship#%E5%89%8D%E7%BD%AE%E3%81%8D">​</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>前半は退屈な内容。40:00 ごろからようやく本題。</li>
</ul>
<a href="https://ouchaku.github.io/ds/img/20240717_micah_hanks_rz.jpg" target="_blank"><img alt="20240717_micah_hanks_rz.jpg" border="0" src="https://ouchaku.github.io/ds/img/20240717_micah_hanks_rz.jpg" width="90%"></a>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="ocr--和訳">OCR ＋ 和訳<a class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to OCR ＋ 和訳" title="Direct link to OCR ＋ 和訳" href="https://ouchaku.github.io/ds/en/blog/2024/07/17/1890_airship#ocr--%E5%92%8C%E8%A8%B3">​</a></h2>
<a href="https://ouchaku.github.io/ds/img/20240717_1890_air_sips_rz.jpg" target="_blank"><img alt="20240717_1890_air_sips_rz.jpg" border="0" src="https://ouchaku.github.io/ds/img/20240717_1890_air_sips_rz.jpg" width="90%"></a>
<p>1890年代の航空船</p>
<ul>
<li>
<p>説明： 1897年4月22日</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>場所：アーカンソー州ホーマン</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>説明： 1897年の有名なフラップ中の着陸した飛行船とその乗員について、指揮者が詳細な説明と付随する画像を提供している。</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>出典 デイリー・アーカンソー・ガゼット（アーカンソー州リトルロック）. 22 Apr 1897, Thu . ページ 3</p>
</li>
</ul>
<hr>
<p>THE 1890s AIR SHIPS</p>
<ul>
<li>
<p>DESCRIPTION: 22 April, 1897</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>LOCATION: Homan, Arkansas.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>DESCRIPTION: A conductor provides detailed account and accompanying image of a landed airship and its occupants during the famous flap of 1897.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>SOURCE: Daily Arkansas Gazette (Little Rock, Arkansas) . 22 Apr 1897, Thu . Page 3</p>
</li>
</ul>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="whisper-ailarge-v2-model--deepl">Whisper AI(large-v2 model) + DeepL<a class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Whisper AI(large-v2 model) + DeepL" title="Direct link to Whisper AI(large-v2 model) + DeepL" href="https://ouchaku.github.io/ds/en/blog/2024/07/17/1890_airship#whisper-ailarge-v2-model--deepl">​</a></h2>
<p>さて、1890年代の飛行船は、この現象の歴史を見てきたほとんどの人にとってよく知られているだろう。デビッド・M・ジェイコブスの著書『アメリカにおけるUFO論争』に話を戻そう。これは、UFOの歴史について書いた人はたくさんいるが、この現象について初めて本格的に歴史的に考察したものである。また、ローレン・デナルトの著書『ミステリーズ』は、UFOの歴史について多くの人が書いている。
(00:46:18)</p>
<p>また、ローレン・デナルトの本、「空の神秘」は、それ以前の歴史であり、彼らの本は、1947年以前のUFOに目を向けようとした最初の本の一つである。私は、南ロンドンを拠点とする素晴らしいミュージシャンである親愛なる友人、ベス・アーシーからコピーを入手した。しかし、このテーマの歴史をもう一度振り返ってみると、飛行船の要素について語る論者がたくさんいたことがわかる。彼は実際、最初の飛行船の構成要素から始めている。
(00:46:47)</p>
<p>ジェイコブスの著書は確かにそうだ。彼は実際、最初の章で1890年代の飛行船から始めて、1947年まで一気に飛ばし、そこで物語を拾い上げている。それは私にとって常に興味深いことだった。私がUFO暗黒時代と呼んでいる時代に起こった、他の種類の目撃談についてもっと話をしよう。というのも、このテーマの歴史家の多くは、デビッド・ジェイコブズや他の歴史家たちに敬意を表しつつも、飛行船から1947年まで、あたかもその時代にUFO目撃談がなかったかのように話を進めているからだ。しかし、その時期には重要なことがあったのだ。
(00:47:19)</p>
<p>しかし、1896年から1897年にかけて、目撃の大きな波があった。その波の一例として、私は新聞好きなので、もう一度この新聞の切り抜きをあげる。newspapers.comで古い記事を検索するのが大好きなんだ。そして歴史の世界は、アームチェア・リサーチャー（腕利きの研究者）にも門戸を開いている。私は古い新聞のアーカイブやオフィスを何時間もかけて掘り下げるのが好きなんだ。
(00:47:45)</p>
<p>この記事で引用されているこの鉄道の機関士、車掌のジム・フーテン大尉が、実際に着陸したとされる飛行船のスケッチを提供しているからだ。さて、肝に銘じておかなければならないのは、私がこの記事を重要だと思う理由は、ジム大尉に関する文献や当時の他の新聞記事を見つけたが、彼が働いていた鉄道路線が実際に存在したからである。
(00:48:15)</p>
<p>1896年、1897年の飛行船の波の頃の話の多くは、明らかに新聞のデマで、これらの話の人気に便乗したものだ。残念なことに、現代の研究者の中には、そのような話はすべて新聞のデマであり、集団ヒステリーであるとか、それに類するものであると主張しようとする人も多い。しかし、おそらくそれとは逆に、いくつかの事例を注意深く見極め、どのように見れば、フーテン船長が私たちの足を引っ張っただけかもしれないという暗示が少なくともあると思う。フーテン船長もその一人だったのかもしれないし、もしかしたら全部冗談で、僕らの足を引っ張ったのかもしれない。
(00:48:54)</p>
<p>フーテン船長は、もしかしたら、全部冗談で、面白おかしくやっているんだと思ったのかもしれない。その可能性は大いにある。とはいえ、少なくとも、その引用をした人物を特定し、その人物が実在したかもしれないという証拠を見つけることができれば、より強力な証拠になると思う。そしてもちろん、この人物は存在したかもしれないという証拠を見つけることができる。
(00:49:09)</p>
<p>そしてもちろん、彼は遭遇したと主張する着陸船の表現を描いたようであり、その乗員は彼が見たものであり、彼が実際に上がって話をしたものである。さて、これは1890年代に登場したある種の初期技術があり、実際に飛行船が飛び回っていたことを証明するのだろうか？いや、必ずしもそうではない。しかし、歴史上のこの時代について、いくつかの報告の背後に実際の技術があったかどうかを調べる、非常に興味深い歴史的研究がなされている。トーマス・エディー・ブラードはもちろん、いくつかの報告の背後にある信じられないような技術について研究している。
(00:49:41)</p>
<p>トーマス・エディー・ブラードはもちろん、この件について驚くべき研究をしてきた。新聞がオンラインにアーカイブされ、ログインして月5ドルを払えば心ゆくまで読むことができるようになる以前、これらの新聞報道を記録することに多くの時間を費やしてきた。彼は全国を旅して、この種の報道を読み漁った。そしてまた、ブラード博士は、本当にこの種のレポートが必要なのだと多くの人に言いたいのだと思う。
(00:50:02)</p>
<p>ブラード博士は、1890年代の飛行船がどのようなものであったにせよ、今日私たちが認識しているような現代のUFO現象の文化的前身であったというのが、私たちが言える最善のことであると言いたいのだろう。もしUFO現象が、私たちの多くが思っているようなもの、つまり地球外生命体による地球訪問やそのようなものとは違っているとしたらどうだろう。
(00:50:28)</p>
<p>歴史を通して見ると、その現象は時代とともに変化し、もしかしたら改善され、より技術的に洗練されていくように見えるとしたら興味深くないだろうか？興味深いことに、歴史的な記述の1つの視点は、十分に深く掘り下げる人にとっては、現象そのものが実際に進歩しているという傾向を示唆しているように見える。そして、それは常に我々の数歩先を行っているにもかかわらず、時間の経過とともに変化しているのである。
(00:50:57)</p>
<p>そして、たとえそれが常に我々より数歩先を行っているとしても、このテーマの歴史家が見てきた指摘された変化は、もしかしたら多くの人が主張するほど、技術は我々よりそれほど先を行っていないかもしれないという考えを、いくらか示唆している。繰り返しになるが、これは単なる推測にすぎない。もし何かあれば、最後にオープンディスカッションの時間を少し残しておきたい。もちろん質問もある。
(00:51:27)</p>
<hr>
<p>Now, the 1890s airships are going to be pretty well known to most people who have looked at the history of this phenomenon. And I'll call back to David M. Jacobs' book, The UFO Controversy in America. This was the first serious historical look at the phenomenon, although there have been a lot of people who've written about the history of UFOs. Again, Lauren Denalt's book, Mysteries of a lot of people who've written about the history of UFOs.
(00:46:18)</p>
<p>Again, Lauren Denalt's book, Mysteries of the Skies, was an earlier history and theirs significantly also tried to look at pre-1947 UFOs, one of the first books that really committed to doing that. I obtained a copy from my dear friend, Beth Arsey, a fantastic musician based in South London. But if we look again back at the history of the subject, you do see that there have been many commentators who have talked about the airship component and David M. Jacobs in his book certainly did. He actually begins in the first airship component and David M.
(00:46:47)</p>
<p>Jacobs in his book certainly did. He actually begins in the first chapter with the 1890s airships, and then he skips all the way ahead to 1947 and picks up the narrative there. And that's always been interesting to me. And we'll talk more about these other kinds of sightings that occurred in what I call that ufological dark ages, because many historians of the subject, with all respect to David Jacobs and others who have chronicled that history, many have seemingly overstepped from the airships to 1947 as though there were no UFO sightings during that period. I think quite the contrary, there certainly were, but we had a significant during that period.
(00:47:19)</p>
<p>I think quite the contrary, there certainly were, but we had a significant wave of sightings that occurred between 1896 and 1897. And as an example of that wave, I give this newspaper clipping again, I'm a newspaper hound. I love to get on newspapers.com and search for old articles. And the world of history has really opened up to armchair researchers, even though I love spending a lot of time in the field, some of the best research, you don't have to leave your office to be able to do it. And I love spending hours digging through old newspaper archives and office to be able to do it.
(00:47:45)</p>
<p>And I love spending hours digging through old newspaper archives and finding accounts like this one, significant because the engineer, this conductor of this rail line, who was quoted in this article, Captain Jim Hooten, actually provided a sketch of the alleged landed airship. Now, the thing we have to keep in mind, and the reason I find this significant is because we had here a character who, again, I've found references to Captain Jim and other newspaper articles from the era, the rail line that he worked for actually existed.
(00:48:15)</p>
<p>Many of the stories from around the 1896, 1897 airship wave are quite obviously newspaper hoaxes that were kind of cashing in on the popularity of these stories. Unfortunately, there are many modern researchers who have tried to make the argument that therefore all of them were probably newspaper hoaxes, that or mass hysteria or something similar. But perhaps to the contrary, I think that if you really are careful in discerning and how you look at some of the cases, there is at least the implication, now for all we know, Captain Hooten here might just have been pulling our leg. It could be that he was part of the, he thought maybe that it was all a joke and pulling our leg.
(00:48:54)</p>
<p>It could be that he was part of the, he thought maybe that it was all a joke and in good fun and he wanted to get in on it. That's very possible. Nonetheless, though, I think that we have at very least a stronger case when we have a person to whom the quotes can be attributed and we can find evidence that this person might've existed. And of course, that he seems to have we can find evidence that this person might've existed.
(00:49:09)</p>
<p>And of course, that he seems to have drawn a representation of the landed craft that he claimed to have encountered, the occupants of which he saw and which he actually went up and spoke to. Now, does that prove that there was some sort of nascent technology that appeared in the 1890s and that there were actual airships being flown around? No, it doesn't necessarily, but there has been some very interesting historical research done looking at this period in history, looking at whether there was perhaps an actual technology behind some of the reports. Thomas Eddie Bullard, of course, has done incredible technology behind some of the reports.
(00:49:41)</p>
<p>Thomas Eddie Bullard, of course, has done incredible research into this and spent a lot of time back in the day chronicling these newspaper reports before these newspapers were archived online and one could log on and pay five bucks a month and read to their heart's content. Now, he traveled around the country reading and digging for these kinds of reports. And again, I think that Dr. Bullard would like many say that really the these kinds of reports.
(00:50:02)</p>
<p>And again, I think that Dr. Bullard would like many say that really the best we can say is that whatever the airships of the 1890s constituted, they were a cultural predecessor to the modern UFO phenomena as we recognize it today. But it's interesting sometimes I think, and if we're going to step over into the realm of speculation here for a moment, it is interesting sometimes to think, you know, what if the UFO phenomenon is unlike what most of us take it to be, i.e., you know, visitation to earth by extraterrestrials or something like that.
(00:50:28)</p>
<p>Wouldn't it be interesting if looking throughout history, the phenomenon seems to change and maybe even improve and become more technologically sophisticated over time? Interestingly, one perspective on historical accounts, for those who dig deeply enough, does seem to sort of suggest that sort of trend that the phenomena itself actually is progressing even as we are observing it over time. And even though it's always a few steps ahead of us, the noted changes that it over time.
(00:50:57)</p>
<p>And even though it's always a few steps ahead of us, the noted changes that historians of this subject have seen does somewhat bespeak the idea that maybe the technology isn't so far ahead of us as many would contend. Now again, that's just speculation, but it's interesting sometimes to entertain ideas like that. We're kind of getting close to the primary lecture here, and I do want to leave a little time for open discussion here at the end if we have any, and also of course questions if there are some. But I'll kind of leave as far as the actual and also of course questions if there are some.
(00:51:27)</p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="動画10046">動画(1:00:46)<a class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to 動画(1:00:46)" title="Direct link to 動画(1:00:46)" href="https://ouchaku.github.io/ds/en/blog/2024/07/17/1890_airship#%E5%8B%95%E7%94%BB10046">​</a></h2>
<p>Anomaly Archives Saturday Streamathon Fundraiser Series 4.3 Micah Hanks</p>
<iframe width="560" height="315" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/77rnKnFmjZw?si=OSoINEa5K4JBmeA9" title="YouTube video player" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin"></iframe>
<p><a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=77rnKnFmjZw" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=77rnKnFmjZw</a></p>
<h3 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="動画概要欄">動画概要欄<a class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to 動画概要欄" title="Direct link to 動画概要欄" href="https://ouchaku.github.io/ds/en/blog/2024/07/17/1890_airship#%E5%8B%95%E7%94%BB%E6%A6%82%E8%A6%81%E6%AC%84">​</a></h3>
<p>30 views  Dec 22, 2020
Anomaly Archives Saturday Streamathon Fundraiser Series 4.3 Micah Hanks</p>
<p>The Anomaly Archives Saturday Streamathons are a series of emergency fundraiser telethons happening each Saturday until 2021.</p>
<p>03:15 pm – Micah Hanks – “UFOs: A Historical Perspective”</p>
<p>We are raising funds to ensure our continued survival into 2021 and beyond. We're drawing together researchers from all corners of the Esoterica realms: Anomalistics, Cryptozoology, Forteana, Parapsychology, and Ufology. We'll be streaming many hours of great content covering these and other fields of inquiry. We'll be sharing a sort of "Fabulous Fortean Film Festival" evening, Plus Music and MORE! All in an effort to raise funds for our 501(c)3 nonprofit community organization to survive the circumstances created by this terrible Covid-Crisis.</p>
<p>(2024-07-17)</p>]]></content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Micah Hanks：1492-10-11, Columbus らが目撃した UFO は松明の類だろう]]></title>
        <id>https://ouchaku.github.io/ds/en/blog/2024/07/17/1942_10_11_columbus</id>
        <link href="https://ouchaku.github.io/ds/en/blog/2024/07/17/1942_10_11_columbus"/>
        <updated>2024-07-17T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[前置き]]></summary>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="前置き">前置き<a class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to 前置き" title="Direct link to 前置き" href="https://ouchaku.github.io/ds/en/blog/2024/07/17/1942_10_11_columbus#%E5%89%8D%E7%BD%AE%E3%81%8D">​</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>前半は退屈な内容。40:00 ごろからようやく本題。</li>
</ul>
<a href="https://ouchaku.github.io/ds/img/20240717_micah_hanks_rz.jpg" target="_blank"><img alt="20240717_micah_hanks_rz.jpg" border="0" src="https://ouchaku.github.io/ds/img/20240717_micah_hanks_rz.jpg" width="90%"></a>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="ocr--和訳">OCR ＋ 和訳<a class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to OCR ＋ 和訳" title="Direct link to OCR ＋ 和訳" href="https://ouchaku.github.io/ds/en/blog/2024/07/17/1942_10_11_columbus#ocr--%E5%92%8C%E8%A8%B3">​</a></h2>
<a href="https://ouchaku.github.io/ds/img/20240717_columbus_rz.jpg" target="_blank"><img alt="20240717_columbus_rz.jpg" border="0" src="https://ouchaku.github.io/ds/img/20240717_columbus_rz.jpg" width="90%"></a>
<p>コロンブス：新世界の奇妙な光</p>
<ul>
<li>
<p>日付：1492年10月11日</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>場所：グアナハニの東約32〜37海里（正確な位置はまだ論争がある）。</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>説明：クリストファー・コロンブスは遠くで「小さなろうそくのような、上がったり下がったりする」かすかな光を見たと語る。サンタ・マリア号に乗船していたペロ・ギテレスとロドリゴ・サンチェス・デ・セゴビアの2人もこのことを聞いたが、ギテレスだけがその光を確認することができた。コロンブスの日誌の記述によれば、この光はピンタ号から観測されたとされている。</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>出典 フェルディナンド・コロンブスの『提督の生涯』（Vita del Ammiraglio）、プレトス・コロンビーノス（Pleitos colombinos：コロンブスの相続人をめぐる長期の訴訟）の議事録、その他いくつかの資料。</p>
</li>
</ul>
<p>COLUMBUS: STRANGE LIGHTS IN THE NEW WORLD</p>
<ul>
<li>
<p>DATE: October 11, 1492</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>LOCATION: Approx. 32 - 37 nautical miles east of Guanahani (exact location remains disputed).</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>DESCRIPTION: Christopher Columbus describes seeing a faint light "like a little wax candle, rising and falling" in the distance. Two others aboard the Santa Maria, Pero Guiterrez and Rodrigo Sanchez de Segovia, are told about this, but only Guiterrez is also able to see and confirm it. The light was reportedly observed from the Pinta, according to the account in Columbus's journal.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>SOURCES: Ferdinand Columbus' Vita del Ammiraglio (The Life of the Admiral), the proceedings of the Pleitos colombinos (the long lawsuit involving the heirs of Columbus) and some other sources.</p>
</li>
</ul>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="whisper-ailarge-v2-model--deepl">Whisper AI(large-v2 model) + DeepL<a class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Whisper AI(large-v2 model) + DeepL" title="Direct link to Whisper AI(large-v2 model) + DeepL" href="https://ouchaku.github.io/ds/en/blog/2024/07/17/1942_10_11_columbus#whisper-ailarge-v2-model--deepl">​</a></h2>
<p>特に近年、コロンブスがUFOを見たとされる事実について、多くの人が話しているのを目にする。
さて、本当にそうなのだろうか？これだけは言っておこう。
彼は確かに光を見た。
しかし、その光は何だったのか？
これも有名な歴史的事件なのだろうか？
さて、私たちが知っているのは、実は彼の個人的な日記に書かれていたことなのだが、それはその後出版された。フェルディナンド・コロンブスの『アミラグリオ記』（Vita del Amiraglio）だ。
(00:38:52)</p>
<p>フェルディナンド・コロンブスの『提督の生涯』（Vita del Amiraglio）だ。コロンブスがグアナハナイに上陸しようとしていた夜、あるいは早朝に、コロンブスは遠くに小さなロウソクのようなものを見たと語っている。そして、コロンブスはこのことを遠く離れた船員たちに知らせた。
(00:39:12)</p>
<p>そこで彼は、ペドロ・グティエレスとロドリゴ・サンチェス・デ・セゴビアという2人組の船員にこのことを知らせた。
(00:39:15)</p>
<hr>
<p>一人は見たが、もう一人は見ていない。
しかし、コロンブスと一緒に、彼らは遠くにこの小さな光を見たと言う、追加の目撃者の裏付けがあった。
そしてなぜか、多くの人がこれを歴史上最も早いUFO目撃談の一つと見ている。
果たしてそうだろうか？
私はおそらくそうではないと思う。
繰り返すが、コロンブスはそれを小さなロウソクのように見えたと述べている。
(00:39:41)</p>
<p>おそらく最も可能性の高い説明は、松明が運ばれてきたか、あるいは先住民のタイノ族が住んでいた近隣の島々で実際に起こった火事のどちらかだろうということだ。しかし、確かにコロンブスは光を見た。
というのも、神秘的な光が確かに目撃され、それが記録され、その体験があったという実際の証言が歴史的記録に残っており、この神秘的な光を複数の目撃者が目撃しているからである。
(00:40:09)</p>
<p>UFO擁護論者の多くは、ある種の照明に関わる歴史的なミステリーだと考えている。
私たちは、UFOの証拠となりうるものを解釈する際には、非常に注意深く見極める必要がある。
この例では、この光が本当に地平線の上に見えたという証拠はあまりない。
(00:40:31)</p>
<p>たとえそれが空に現れたとしても、それを説明するものがあるかもしれない。
しかし、これははるかに興味深い歴史的記述だと私は思う。</p>
<hr>
<p>I have seen many people, especially in recent years, talking about the fact that Columbus purportedly saw a UFO.
Well, is that really true? I'll tell you this.
He certainly saw a light.
But what was the light?
Is this another famous historical case that maybe we can solve?
Now, what we do know is that actually in his personal journal, but it was published thereafter. I actually have the source there, Ferdinand Columbus's Vita del Amiraglio, thereafter.
(00:38:52)</p>
<p>I actually have the source there, Ferdinand Columbus's Vita del Amiraglio, The Life of the Admiral. This actually features this account from Columbus where he, as they're approaching landfall at Guanahanai, in the night or the early morning rather, Columbus says that he sees what he said resembled a little wax candle off in the distance. And so he actually brings this to the attention of a couple of his shipmates distance.
(00:39:12)</p>
<p>And so he actually brings this to the attention of a couple of his shipmates there, Pedro Gutierrez and Rodrigo Sanchez de Segovia.
(00:39:15)</p>
<hr>
<p>One of them saw it, the other did not.
But there was additional witness corroboration that, along with Columbus, said that they saw this little light out there in the distance.
And for some reason, many people have looked at this as being one of history's earliest UFO sightings.
Is it necessarily?
I would argue it probably is not.
Again, the way that Columbus described it, he said it looked like a little wax candle.
(00:39:41)</p>
<p>Perhaps the likeliest explanation is that it was either a torch being carried or maybe it was actually a fire on one of the neighboring islands that was inhabited by the native Taino. But yes, Columbus certainly did see a light.
But again, this is an important one to look at because although there was a mysterious light certainly seen and it was certainly recorded and there is in the historical record a actual testament to that experience having happened and a multiple witness sighting of this mysterious light.
(00:40:09)</p>
<p>Because I think that it is a historical mystery involving some sort of illumination, many UFO advocates have kind of gravitated toward and said, therefore, aliens, right?
Kind of talking about what we were saying earlier, we should be very careful and discerning in what we interpret to be possible evidence of UFOs.
And in this instance, there isn't really much evidence that this light was ever really seen above the horizon.
(00:40:31)</p>
<p>Even if it did appear in the sky, there may be things that would account for that.
This is a far more interesting historical account, in my opinion, though.</p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="動画10046">動画(1:00:46)<a class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to 動画(1:00:46)" title="Direct link to 動画(1:00:46)" href="https://ouchaku.github.io/ds/en/blog/2024/07/17/1942_10_11_columbus#%E5%8B%95%E7%94%BB10046">​</a></h2>
<p>Anomaly Archives Saturday Streamathon Fundraiser Series 4.3 Micah Hanks</p>
<iframe width="560" height="315" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/77rnKnFmjZw?si=OSoINEa5K4JBmeA9" title="YouTube video player" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin"></iframe>
<p><a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=77rnKnFmjZw" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=77rnKnFmjZw</a></p>
<h3 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="動画概要欄">動画概要欄<a class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to 動画概要欄" title="Direct link to 動画概要欄" href="https://ouchaku.github.io/ds/en/blog/2024/07/17/1942_10_11_columbus#%E5%8B%95%E7%94%BB%E6%A6%82%E8%A6%81%E6%AC%84">​</a></h3>
<p>30 views  Dec 22, 2020
Anomaly Archives Saturday Streamathon Fundraiser Series 4.3 Micah Hanks</p>
<p>The Anomaly Archives Saturday Streamathons are a series of emergency fundraiser telethons happening each Saturday until 2021.</p>
<p>03:15 pm – Micah Hanks – “UFOs: A Historical Perspective”</p>
<p>We are raising funds to ensure our continued survival into 2021 and beyond. We're drawing together researchers from all corners of the Esoterica realms: Anomalistics, Cryptozoology, Forteana, Parapsychology, and Ufology. We'll be streaming many hours of great content covering these and other fields of inquiry. We'll be sharing a sort of "Fabulous Fortean Film Festival" evening, Plus Music and MORE! All in an effort to raise funds for our 501(c)3 nonprofit community organization to survive the circumstances created by this terrible Covid-Crisis.</p>
<p>(2024-07-17)</p>]]></content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Micah Hanks：1943-04-05, California：Casey の目撃した「奇妙な飛行機」]]></title>
        <id>https://ouchaku.github.io/ds/en/blog/2024/07/17/1943_04_05_casey</id>
        <link href="https://ouchaku.github.io/ds/en/blog/2024/07/17/1943_04_05_casey"/>
        <updated>2024-07-17T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[前置き]]></summary>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="前置き">前置き<a class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to 前置き" title="Direct link to 前置き" href="https://ouchaku.github.io/ds/en/blog/2024/07/17/1943_04_05_casey#%E5%89%8D%E7%BD%AE%E3%81%8D">​</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>前半は退屈な内容。40:00 ごろからようやく本題。</li>
</ul>
<a href="https://ouchaku.github.io/ds/img/20240717_micah_hanks_rz.jpg" target="_blank"><img alt="20240717_micah_hanks_rz.jpg" border="0" src="https://ouchaku.github.io/ds/img/20240717_micah_hanks_rz.jpg" width="90%"></a>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="ocr--deepl">OCR + DeepL<a class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to OCR + DeepL" title="Direct link to OCR + DeepL" href="https://ouchaku.github.io/ds/en/blog/2024/07/17/1943_04_05_casey#ocr--deepl">​</a></h2>
<a href="https://ouchaku.github.io/ds/img/20240717_1943_04_05_rz.jpg" target="_blank"><img alt="20240717_1943_04_05_rz.jpg" border="0" src="https://ouchaku.github.io/ds/img/20240717_1943_04_05_rz.jpg" width="90%"></a>
<p>1947年以前のUFO</p>
<p>1943: ケーシーの奇妙な「飛行機</p>
<p>1943年4月5日午前9時50分、航空作家で飛行教官であったジェリー・ケーシーは、BT-13A練習機の学生パイロットとともに、カリフォルニア州ロングビーチ上空で奇妙な「飛行機」を観察した。その飛行機がケイシーの目に留まったのは、東に向かう "奇妙な閃光 "が彼の目を捉えたときであった。ケイシーが目を向けると、その飛行機が彼らの飛行機の方向に急降下していくのが見えた。ケイシーは、窓もプロペラも、推進装置のようなものも見えなかった。彼はそれを楕円形で、上下とも中央に向かって丸みを帯びた「こぶ」があると表現した。</p>
<hr>
<p>PRE-1947 UFOs</p>
<p>1943: CASEY'S ODD "PLANE"</p>
<p>On April 5, 1943 at 9:50 AM, aviation writer and flight instructor Gerry Casey, along with a student pilot in a BT-13A trainer, observed a strange "plane" over Long Beach, California. The craft was brought to Casey's attention when a "peculiar flash" toward the east caught his eye; as Casey turned to look, he observed the craft entering a dive in the direction of their aircraft. Casey could see no windows, propellers, or any kind of visible propulsion mechanism. He described it as elliptical in shape, with a rounded "hump" toward the center on both top and bottom.</p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="コメント">コメント<a class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to コメント" title="Direct link to コメント" href="https://ouchaku.github.io/ds/en/blog/2024/07/17/1943_04_05_casey#%E3%82%B3%E3%83%A1%E3%83%B3%E3%83%88">​</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>この UFO の正体は下の過去記事で述べた「自転する orb」だと判断する。</li>
</ul>
<blockquote><a href="https://ouchaku.github.io/ds/img/20240717_best4.jpg" target="_blank"><img alt="20240717_best4.jpg" border="0" src="https://ouchaku.github.io/ds/img/20240717_best4.jpg" width="90%"></a><p>ref: <a href="http://news21c.blog.fc2.com/blog-entry-21040.html" target="_blank">❑ 画像解析の専門家が本物と認めた最良の UFO 写真 → この正体を解く （途中2）</a> (2023-06-23)</p></blockquote>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="whisper-ailarge-v2-model--deepl">Whisper AI(large-v2 model) + DeepL<a class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Whisper AI(large-v2 model) + DeepL" title="Direct link to Whisper AI(large-v2 model) + DeepL" href="https://ouchaku.github.io/ds/en/blog/2024/07/17/1943_04_05_casey#whisper-ailarge-v2-model--deepl">​</a></h2>
<p>またしてもバリー・グリーンウッドが素晴らしい例を示してくれる。1943年4月5日、午前9時50分。
(00:52:01)</p>
<hr>
<p>ジェリー・ケーシーは航空作家であり、飛行教官であった。そして、彼には当時、BT-13A練習機で彼と一緒に飛んでいた生徒がいた。彼らは奇妙なものを見た。もっと良い言葉はないが、先にも述べたように、当時の言い回しで言えば、物体のように見えるものがあれば、彼らはその存在を知っていた。飛行機が飛んでいた。だから彼らは、この奇妙な飛行機がカリフォルニアのロングビーチ上空で観測されたと言うのだ。しかし、彼らがこの飛行機をどう説明しているか聞いてみよう。
(00:52:28)</p>
<p>それは彼が彼の目の角から一種の奇妙なフラッシュを見て、彼が東の方に向こうを見ると、彼はこの飛行機が急降下して、彼らの方向に向かうのを見た。窓もプロペラもなく、推進装置のようなものもない。
飛行機には見えないが、楕円形だと彼は言った。それは光っていた飛行機には見えないが、彼が言ったこの飛行機は楕円形をしていた。
(00:52:48)</p>
<p>それはオレンジ色に光っていて、上と下の両方に中心に向かって丸みを帯びたこぶのようなものがあった。私たちのとても幸運なことに、彼はまた、彼が見たものをスケッチした。1943. 私の考えでは、今見えているものは2つのうちの1つに見える。
それは確かに、私たちが今日認識しているような掃射翼タイプのステルス航空機の横顔のような外見をしているが、少なくとも表面的には、古典的な空飛ぶ円盤にも似ているのではないだろうか？1943年、カリフォルニア上空。さて、古典的な空飛ぶ円盤だと言った人たち、そうではないか？1943年のカリフォルニア上空だ。
(00:53:27)</p>
<hr>
<p>And yet again, Barry Greenwood gives us this excellent example. On April 5th, 1943 at 9 50 a.m.
(00:52:01)</p>
<hr>
<p>Jerry Casey, an aviation writer and flight instructor, and he has actually a student flying with him at the time in a BT-13A trainer, they see a strange what again for lack of any better term, and as I mentioned earlier using the parlance of their day, what they knew to exist if there's what appears to be an object, an aircraft flying, I mean it's a plane, right? So they say this weird plane was observed over Long Beach, California. But now listen to how they describe this plane.
(00:52:28)</p>
<p>It was brought to his attention once he sees a kind of peculiar flash out of the corner of his eye and he looks over there toward the east and he sees this craft coming into a dive and headed in their direction. There aren't any windows or propellers, no kind of propulsion mechanism.
It doesn't look like a plane, but this plane he said was elliptical in shape. It was glowingIt doesn't look like a plane, but this plane he said was elliptical in shape.
(00:52:48)</p>
<p>It was glowing orange and it had a rounded sort of hump toward the center on both the top and the bottom and to our very much to our good fortune, he also sketched what he saw. 1943. Now to my way of thinking, what we're seeing right there looks like one of two things.
It certainly has the appearance of maybe some of the swept wing type stealth aircraft that we recognize today as seen in profile, but at very least superficially it also resembles a classic flying saucer, does it not? 1943 over California. Now for those who have said that the classic flying saucer, does it not? 1943 over California.
(00:53:27)</p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="動画10046">動画(1:00:46)<a class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to 動画(1:00:46)" title="Direct link to 動画(1:00:46)" href="https://ouchaku.github.io/ds/en/blog/2024/07/17/1943_04_05_casey#%E5%8B%95%E7%94%BB10046">​</a></h2>
<p>Anomaly Archives Saturday Streamathon Fundraiser Series 4.3 Micah Hanks</p>
<iframe width="560" height="315" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/77rnKnFmjZw?si=OSoINEa5K4JBmeA9" title="YouTube video player" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin"></iframe>
<p><a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=77rnKnFmjZw" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=77rnKnFmjZw</a></p>
<h3 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="動画概要欄">動画概要欄<a class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to 動画概要欄" title="Direct link to 動画概要欄" href="https://ouchaku.github.io/ds/en/blog/2024/07/17/1943_04_05_casey#%E5%8B%95%E7%94%BB%E6%A6%82%E8%A6%81%E6%AC%84">​</a></h3>
<p>30 views  Dec 22, 2020
Anomaly Archives Saturday Streamathon Fundraiser Series 4.3 Micah Hanks</p>
<p>The Anomaly Archives Saturday Streamathons are a series of emergency fundraiser telethons happening each Saturday until 2021.</p>
<p>03:15 pm – Micah Hanks – “UFOs: A Historical Perspective”</p>
<p>We are raising funds to ensure our continued survival into 2021 and beyond. We're drawing together researchers from all corners of the Esoterica realms: Anomalistics, Cryptozoology, Forteana, Parapsychology, and Ufology. We'll be streaming many hours of great content covering these and other fields of inquiry. We'll be sharing a sort of "Fabulous Fortean Film Festival" evening, Plus Music and MORE! All in an effort to raise funds for our 501(c)3 nonprofit community organization to survive the circumstances created by this terrible Covid-Crisis.</p>
<p>(2024-07-17)</p>]]></content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[SMiles Lewis： ET による遺伝子改造で、街中の ET が目視できるようなった人のことを私は知っている]]></title>
        <id>https://ouchaku.github.io/ds/en/blog/2024/07/17/et_walk_street</id>
        <link href="https://ouchaku.github.io/ds/en/blog/2024/07/17/et_walk_street"/>
        <updated>2024-07-17T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[前置き]]></summary>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="前置き">前置き<a class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to 前置き" title="Direct link to 前置き" href="https://ouchaku.github.io/ds/en/blog/2024/07/17/et_walk_street#%E5%89%8D%E7%BD%AE%E3%81%8D">​</a></h2>
<p>SMiles Lewis が本気でタイトルのような ぶっ飛んだ 主張をしている。その主張の具体的根拠は何も語らず、その主張を足場にして</p>
<ul>
<li>ホログラフィックな全体性が…</li>
<li>意識の拡張が…</li>
<li>トランスパーソナルな理解が…</li>
<li>Ken Wilber の無境界の理論が…</li>
</ul>
<p>といったヨタ話をひたすら繰り広げている。</p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="whisper-ailarge-v2-model--deepl">Whisper AI(large-v2 model) + DeepL<a class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Whisper AI(large-v2 model) + DeepL" title="Direct link to Whisper AI(large-v2 model) + DeepL" href="https://ouchaku.github.io/ds/en/blog/2024/07/17/et_walk_street#whisper-ailarge-v2-model--deepl">​</a></h2>
<hr>
<p>例えば、人間がこれらの存在によって遺伝子を増強され、変更され、編集され、例えば、私たちがグレーのエイリアンと呼んでいる存在が、誰も見ることができないのに、人通りの多い都心で白昼堂々と通りを歩いているのを見ることができるようになったという状況を、私は知っている。
つまり、私たちの意識状態を変調させ、より拡大させたことで、帯域幅が広がり、平均的な人間には知覚できない要素を知覚できるようになったのだ。
(00:25:58)</p>
<p>そして彼らがより拡大した状態にあるとき、これらの存在が私たちのすぐそばにいることに気づく。
だから私たちがこの質問について話すとき、彼らは私たちとともにいるのだろうか？
私たちが話しているように、彼らは私たちの中にいるのだろうか？
もちろん、彼らは常に知覚できるわけではないが、いる。
これは重要な違いだ。
そして、今日話しているような一般的な区別、つまり境界線は、本当はもっと重要なことなんだ。
(00:26:20)</p>
<p>知覚可能とは何か？
知覚の範囲と、究極的に実在し、究極的に区別され、分割され、分離されたものなどとは何か。
ここまでは、さまざまな人間が、さまざまな状態や領域で、さまざまな種類の実体と出会う経験について話してきた。
私たちの物理的な領域もまた、ある特定の変調に過ぎず、物理的な外観、物理的な感覚、物理的な直感的な性質は、まさに完全に没入した精神状態で期待されるものなのだ。
(00:27:00)</p>
<p>しかし、私たちは、身体性の出現が、実際には意識の変調だけでなく、全体的な何か根本的なことを語っているのだと思い違いをすべきではない。
人々が経験することに加えて、現実そのものの性質について、さらには私たち自身の性質、私たち自身の根源的な性質についてさえも、これらの存在から私たち、人間に対して非常に頻繁に伝えられているメッセージにも目を向けるべきである。
(00:27:31)</p>
<p>彼らは何を語っているのか？
今指摘したこととまったく同じことだ。
それは、すべては究極的にはつながっているという事実であり、これらの分断線は私たちが作り出した地図の人工物にすぎず、根底にある現実を示すものではないということだ。
このことは、これらの領域を移動し、横断する能力だけでなく、私たちに与えるメッセージにおいても証明されている。
そして非常に重要なのは、そう言われているからといって、それを鵜呑みにしてはいけないということだ。
(00:27:59)</p>
<p>私たちはまた、より拡大された領域のような出会いをしたときの人々の経験とも比較すべきだ。
そして私たちが発見するのは、それは常に1対1であり、人々の経験と完全に一致するということだ。
だからこそ、この種の出会いを経験した人たちの世界観の転換に、説得力のある証拠が見られるのだ。
何度も言ってきたように、彼らはしばしば戻ってくる。死を恐れなくなり、物質的なものに興味を持たなくなり、他の自己ともつながっている、より大きな自己の感覚の中で、この転生の広い広がりにずっと集中しているのだ。
(00:28:37)</p>
<p>だから私たちは、経験においても、メッセージにおいても、そして人々の経験におけるそれらの相互関係のあり方においても、これを見ることができるのだ。
(00:28:45)</p>
<hr>
<p>このポッドキャストで取り上げたケースから、簡単な例を挙げると、ある出会いがあった。
その後、出発するときに、よくあるように存在論的なショックがあったにもかかわらず、彼らは深い経験をした。
(00:29:12)</p>
<p>しかし、この存在、もう一人の異星人は、その体から出てきて、このカップルの前で踊るような光の球体になった。
そしてこの存在は、この男を体から引きずり出すことができた。
アンドロメダ銀河と天の川銀河が重力に引っ張られて互いの周りを踊り始めるのを見るのと同じようにね。
(00:29:38)</p>
<p>そしてこの体験の中で、この若者は、それが彼の視野全体を変え、彼の人生で最も深遠な体験であり、間違いなく、自分の覚醒状態とは何なのか、そしてそれが彼やすべての意識ある存在に利用可能な全体性のほんの小さな縮図であることについての彼の視野を徹底的に変えたと語った。
さて、このエピソードではこれまで、地図と領土の区別について、また一方と他方を混同してはいけないことについて話してきた。
(00:30:09)</p>
<p>さて、これはUFO現象を理解するために私たちがテーブルの上に置く可能性、可能性に対する私たちの理解にも関わってくる。
そして、これは私が先週ソーシャルメディアに投稿したことに関連している。
私は言った、引用、ある考え、存在はこの構成の外から発生することができ、それでもなお、ある至高に包括的な平面からの天使や悪魔のような引用できない究極の形態ではない。
(00:30:37)</p>
<p>私たちは、想像力の貧困や、永続的だが証明されていない仮定に支配されないように注意する必要がある。
つまり、ここでもまた地図と領土の話になる。
私たちは自分の地図、つまり既存の地図を頼りに、これから遭遇する新しい地形を理解しようとしている。
しかし、私たちはすでに何千年にもわたって蓄積してきた経験的データを持っており、その地図、つまり形而上学的に可能性を理解しようとする地図は不十分であり、ひどく不十分であることを示唆している。
(00:31:14)</p>
<p>ここで私が言っているのは、真に非二元的な理解、トランスパーソナルな理解と、一神教の伝統の中にある思考や構造、教義や教義を生み出す概念との違いについてだ。
現実にはフラクタルな側面があり、現実にはホログラフィックな側面がある。それは、根本的に私たちはすべて同じものであるだけでなく、私たちの個性の中にある全体性のフラクタルな破片でもあるという事実を物語っている。
(00:31:56)</p>
<p>なぜなら、それらは究極的には同じホログラフィックな全体のフラクタルな断片であり、小さな断片ではなく、全体性、全体性のレンダリングなのだから。
(00:32:34)</p>
<hr>
<p>And so for instance, I'm aware of situations where human beings have had their genetics augmented, changed, edited by these beings and are now able to, for instance, see gray aliens, the beings we call gray aliens, walking down the street in broad daylight in a busy metropolitan center when no one else can see them.
So again, what this has done is it's modulated our consciousness state, made it more expansive so the bandwidth is now broader and they can perceive elements that the average human cannot.
(00:25:58)</p>
<p>And when they are in this more expanded state, they find that these beings are right in our midst.
And so when we talk about this question around, are they with us?
Are they here amongst us as we speak?
Of course they are, although they're not always perceivable.
This is a key distinction.
And that these distinctions in general that we're talking about today, these boundaries, really are more about that.
(00:26:20)</p>
<p>What is perceivable?
What is the range of perception versus what is ultimately real and ultimately distinct, divided, separate, etc.
Now so far we've been talking about the experience of different human beings encountering these different kinds of entities in different kinds of states or realms, which again, we're just looking at like a different modulation of consciousness because that's ultimately what it is.
And that our physical realm is again, just one particular modulation and the appearance of physicality, the feeling of physicality, the visceral nature of the physicality is exactly what we would expect in a fully immersive mental state.
(00:27:00)</p>
<p>But we shouldn't make the mistake of assuming that appearance of physicality is actually speaking about something fundamental, not just of that modulation of consciousness, but of the totality, which is again, what reductionistic materialists would have us believe.
Now, in addition to the experiences people have, we should also look to the messages that are so often conveyed by these beings to us, to human beings, about the nature of reality itself, and even about our own nature, our own fundamental nature.
(00:27:31)</p>
<p>What do they speak of?
The very same thing I just pointed to.
That being the fact that everything is ultimately connected, that these dividing lines are only artifacts of the maps that we create, not indicative of the underlying reality.
They demonstrate this not just in their capacity to move around and across these domains, but also in the messages they provide to us.
And very importantly, we shouldn't just believe it because that's what's being said to us.
(00:27:59)</p>
<p>We should also compare that with people's experience when they have these more expanded realm kind of encounters.
And what we find is that those are always one to one, that this completely fits with people's experience.
And this is why we see such compelling evidence in the kind of worldview shifts that happen for people who've had these kinds of encounters.
They often come back, as I've said many times, no longer fearing death, no longer being interested in material goods, being much more focused on the broad sweep of this incarnation amongst a much larger sense of self that is connected to other selves as well.
(00:28:37)</p>
<p>So we see this both again in experience and in the messages and in the way that those interrelate in people's experience.
(00:28:45)</p>
<hr>
<p>And as a quick example here, again, from a case that I've covered over the course of this podcast, there was an encounter where these two young adults, they were late teenagers basically who were parents of a newborn, were taken aboard a craft.
And then afterwards, as they were leaving, even though there was ontological shock involved, as is often the case, they had this profound experience, specifically the young man who had been in the military and was a pretty straight and narrow just-a-facts man kind of guy.
(00:29:12)</p>
<p>But this being, this other alien being, came out of its body and became a dancing sphere of light in front of this couple.
And then this being was able to draw this man out of his body.
And then these two spheres of light proceeded to kind of join together in this kind of cosmic dance in the same way that we might eventually see the Andromeda galaxy and the Milky Way galaxy begin to dance around each other when their gravities pull them together, something like that.
(00:29:38)</p>
<p>And in this experience, this young man said that it changed his entire perspective, that it was the most profound experience of his life, and undoubtedly, thoroughly changed his perspective on what his waking state was and just what a tiny microcosm of the totality available to him and to every conscious being that represented.
Now thus far in this episode, we've been talking about the distinction between the map and the territory and how we shouldn't confuse one for the other.
(00:30:09)</p>
<p>Now this also comes down to our understanding of the possibilities, the possibilities we put on the table to make sense of the UFO phenomenon.
And this relates to something I posted to social media this last week.
I said, quote, a thought, beings can arise from outside of this construct and still not be quote unquote ultimate forms as in angels and demons from some supremely overarching plane.
(00:30:37)</p>
<p>We need to be careful not to let a poverty of imagination and enduring but unproven assumptions rule the day, unquote.
So this again gets to the map versus the territory.
We look to our maps, our preexisting maps to make sense of this new terrain that we're coming across, assuming that our maps are sufficient to answer those kinds of questions.
But the thing is, we already have empirical data that's been building up over millennia suggesting that that map, this map that tries to make sense of the possibilities metaphysically is insufficient, is woefully insufficient.
(00:31:14)</p>
<p>And here I'm referring to the difference between a truly non-dual understanding, a transpersonal understanding and the notions that give rise to the thoughts and the structures and the dogma and the doctrine within monotheistic traditions.
And what I'm saying here is that the data we have at hand seems to point towards a non-dual reality, that there is a fractal aspect to reality and a holographic aspect to reality that speaks to the fact that fundamentally we are not only all the same thing but also fractal shards of the totality in our individuality, which seems paradoxical but is the nature of reality itself.
(00:31:56)</p>
<p>And this is why we can learn just as much by exploring our rich interiority as we can by exploring the cosmos, because ultimately those are fragments, fractal fragments of the same holographic whole, representing not tiny pieces but renderings of the entirety, of the totality.
(00:32:34)</p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="動画4357">動画(43:57)<a class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to 動画(43:57)" title="Direct link to 動画(43:57)" href="https://ouchaku.github.io/ds/en/blog/2024/07/17/et_walk_street#%E5%8B%95%E7%94%BB4357">​</a></h2>
<p>104 - Consciousness Continuum</p>
<iframe width="560" height="315" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/ChuPJLz5Y2M?si=O86EOspEIPWPf5oS" title="YouTube video player" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin"></iframe>
<p><a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=ChuPJLz5Y2M" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">www.youtube.com/watch?v=ChuPJLz5Y2M</a></p>
<h3 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="動画概要欄">動画概要欄<a class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to 動画概要欄" title="Direct link to 動画概要欄" href="https://ouchaku.github.io/ds/en/blog/2024/07/17/et_walk_street#%E5%8B%95%E7%94%BB%E6%A6%82%E8%A6%81%E6%AC%84">​</a></h3>
<p>1,400 views  Jun 30, 2024  Point of Convergence</p>
<p>今や有名になった2017年のニューヨーク・タイムズ紙の記事「光るオーラと "ブラックマネー"」で発覚した事実に始まる： ペンタゴンの謎のU.F.O.プログラム」、そしてルイス・エリゾンドやデヴィッド・グルーシュのような元軍内部関係者による疑惑が明るみに出たことで、一般の人々は、このコミュニティの一員である私たちがずっと以前から知っていた現実、つまり、人間以外の知的生命体とその技術的驚異が私たちのすぐそばにいる（そして今もいる）という現実に徐々に慣れつつある。</p>
<p>それでも、このような濁った（しかし、しばしば爽快な）水の奥深くへ日頃から潜り込んでいる私たちにとって、このような暴露は、市井の平均的なジョーやジェーンにとっては驚くようなものであっても、実際には始まりに過ぎないことを知っている。というのも、端的に言えば、人間の経験には、西洋文明を支配する一般的なパラダイム（少なくとも現時点では）とは相容れない要素が数多く存在するからだ。これらの要素には、体外離脱、臨死体験、超能力現象、シンクロニシティ、亡くなったはずの愛する人との接触、タイムスリップなどが含まれる。そして、これはほんの手始めに過ぎない。</p>
<p>歴史的に礼儀正しい会話の端に追いやられてきたこれらの要素は、何が可能かについての主流派の理解を引き延ばすだけでなく、何が現実なのかを理解するために私たちが自信を持って作り上げた地図そのものにも疑問を投げかけている。例えば、洗練された、明らかに人間ではない知的生命体（エイリアン）を扱う問題に関して言えば、国防総省が回収した機体や、人間ではない生命体（私たちと同じ、明らかに生物学的な生命体）の死体さえも保管しているとされる問題だけでなく、テーブルの上には、他の種類の非従来型の遭遇の多くの信頼できる証言がある。</p>
<p>実のところ、重要なことは、「現実」であることに変わりはないのだが、幽体離脱と表現した方がいいような存在との遭遇を示すデータがかなりあるのだ。このような存在は、さまざまな立場の人々によって一貫した方法で説明されており、私たちと同じように「実在」し、独立した存在であると主張しているようだ。人々が遭遇する他の生命体は、おそらく準物理的と表現した方がよいだろう。また、他の生命体は、私たちが家の異なる部屋を行き来するように、異なる領域を行き来しているように見える。</p>
<p>さらに、人間は時に自分の身体の外、さらにはこの3次元の "物理的 "構造体の外で行動していることに気づく。遭遇した異星人はまた、肉体を含むこともあれば含まないこともある方法で、人間の意識を動かすことができるようだ。要するに、ここで強調されているのは、物理主義的なパラダイムが全く成り立たないということだ。</p>
<p>しかし、このような場合、我々はどのように進めばいいのだろうか？現代の地図が、せいぜいもっと広大な領域のほんの一角を映し出す近似図に過ぎないことが露呈したのだとしたら、私たちはどのように進むべきなのだろうか？そして、生者と死者、睡眠状態と覚醒状態、物理的な領域とエーテル的な領域の間の一見幻想的な境界をどのように調和させることができるのだろうか？これはすべて、かなり野心的な探求に相当する。しかし、ポッドキャスト「ポイント・オブ・コンバージェンス」の第104回目のエピソードでは、まさにこのような問題に取り組もうとしている。</p>
<hr>
<p>Beginning with the revelations that arose in a now famous 2017 New York Times article titled “Glowing Auras and ‘Black Money’: The Pentagon’s Mysterious U.F.O. Program”, and further brought to light with the allegations made by former military insiders like Luis Elizondo and David Grusch, the general public is being slowly acclimated to a reality that those of us who are part of this community have long known to be the case: non-human intelligences and their technological marvels have been (and continue to be) in our very midst.</p>
<p>Still, for those of us who regularly dive deep into these murky (but often exhilarating) waters, we know that these revelations - as startling as they are to the average Joe and Jane on the street - are really just the beginning. And that’s because, simply put, there are numerous elements of human experience that simply don’t play well with the prevailing paradigm that rules in Western civilization - at least at present. These elements include out of body experiences, near death experiences, psi phenomena, synchronicity, contact with supposed deceased loved ones, and time slippages. And that’s just for starters.</p>
<p>Not only do these elements that have historically been forced to the fringes of polite conversation stretch the mainstream’s understanding of what’s possible, they also call into question the very maps we’ve so confidently crafted to make sense of what’s real altogether. For instance, when it comes to the matter of dealing with sophisticated, apparently non-human intelligences (ie. aliens), not only do we have the matter of the DoD allegedly housing the recovered craft and even the cadavers of non-human life forms - life forms that are decidedly biological, just like us -  also on the table are the credible accounts of a host of other kind of non-conventional encounters.</p>
<p>Truth be told, there is a considerable body of data pointing to encounters with beings that are better described as ethereal, though - importantly - no less “real”. These beings are described by people from different walks of life in such consistent ways that they seem to claim just as much “real” and independent existence as we do. Other life forms that people encounter are perhaps better described as quasi-physical, and still others seem to navigate between these different domains like we might move between different rooms of a house.</p>
<p>Furthermore, human beings sometimes find themselves acting outside of their own bodies - and even outside of this 3D “physical” construct altogether - interacting with alien beings of various sorts and sometimes even with their own supposedly deceased loved ones in the process. The beings encountered also seem capable of moving human consciousness in ways that sometimes include the physical body, and other times do not. In short, what’s being highlighted here is the untenable nature of the physicalist paradigm altogether.</p>
<p>But all this being the case, how are we to proceed? If our modern maps have been exposed as - at best - approximations reflecting only one tiny corner of a much more expansive territory, how are we to make our way forward? And how can we reconcile the seemingly illusory boundaries between the living and the dead, sleep and waking states, and physical and ethereal realms? This all amounts to some pretty ambitious inquiry. But these are exactly the matters that we’ll seek to engage with in this the 104th episode of the Point of Convergence podcast.</p>
<p>(2024-07-17)</p>]]></content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[1980-03, 中央に窪みのある orb の動画映像]]></title>
        <id>https://ouchaku.github.io/ds/en/blog/2024/07/16/dimped_orb</id>
        <link href="https://ouchaku.github.io/ds/en/blog/2024/07/16/dimped_orb"/>
        <updated>2024-07-16T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[前置き]]></summary>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="前置き">前置き<a class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to 前置き" title="Direct link to 前置き" href="https://ouchaku.github.io/ds/en/blog/2024/07/16/dimped_orb#%E5%89%8D%E7%BD%AE%E3%81%8D">​</a></h2>
<p>たぶん、この窪みや楕円形状は orb そのものの形状ではなく、カメラ内部の光学的特性による形状ではないかと思うが<sup><a id="user-content-fnref-1-d27f14" data-footnote-ref="true" aria-describedby="footnote-label" href="https://ouchaku.github.io/ds/en/blog/2024/07/16/dimped_orb#user-content-fn-1-d27f14">1</a></sup>、一応記録しておく。</p>
<p>切り出し静止画を付けたが、元は動画映像。</p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="切り出し静止画">切り出し静止画<a class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to 切り出し静止画" title="Direct link to 切り出し静止画" href="https://ouchaku.github.io/ds/en/blog/2024/07/16/dimped_orb#%E5%88%87%E3%82%8A%E5%87%BA%E3%81%97%E9%9D%99%E6%AD%A2%E7%94%BB">​</a></h2>
<a href="https://ouchaku.github.io/ds/img/20240713_concaveed_orb.jpg" target="_blank"><img alt="20240713_concaveed_orb.jpg" border="0" src="https://ouchaku.github.io/ds/img/20240713_concaveed_orb.jpg" width="90%"></a>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="関連">関連<a class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to 関連" title="Direct link to 関連" href="https://ouchaku.github.io/ds/en/blog/2024/07/16/dimped_orb#%E9%96%A2%E9%80%A3">​</a></h2>
<p><a href="http://news21c.blog.fc2.com/blog-entry-21078.html" target="_blank">❑ 国境警備隊隊長が撮影した「窪みのある、自転する orb の動画」</a> (2023-07-03)</p>
<p><a href="http://news21c.blog.fc2.com/blog-entry-21096.html" target="_blank">❑ Skinwalker ranch で撮影された「窪みのある orb」（途中 1）</a> (2023-07-08)</p>
<p><a href="http://news21c.blog.fc2.com/blog-entry-21269.html" target="_blank">❑ Shane Ryan: 1966-04-06, Westall UFO 事件: UFO が半透明になって木々を無抵抗ですり抜けつつ透明になって消えた</a> (2023-08-23)</p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="動画13635">動画(1:36:35)<a class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to 動画(1:36:35)" title="Direct link to 動画(1:36:35)" href="https://ouchaku.github.io/ds/en/blog/2024/07/16/dimped_orb#%E5%8B%95%E7%94%BB13635">​</a></h2>
<p>Invasion: UFO Encounters and Alien Beings
<a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=AxK6S_Zh5ug" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">www.youtube.com/watch?v=AxK6S_Zh5ug</a></p>
<p>95,600 views  Apr 26, 2012</p>
<p>(2024-07-16)</p>
<!-- -->
<section data-footnotes="true" class="footnotes"><h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7 sr-only" id="footnote-label">Footnotes<a class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Footnotes" title="Direct link to Footnotes" href="https://ouchaku.github.io/ds/en/blog/2024/07/16/dimped_orb#footnote-label">​</a></h2>
<ol>
<li id="user-content-fn-1-d27f14">
<p>点光源を撮影するとき、ピントを少しずらすとボケるが、さらにピントをずらすとこういったカメラの内部機構を反映した映像になる。通常はカメラの絞りの形状が反映する筈だが、この画像のような窪みが見える事例は初めて。なので記録する価値が若干はあるやも。 <a data-footnote-backref="" aria-label="Back to reference 1" class="data-footnote-backref" href="https://ouchaku.github.io/ds/en/blog/2024/07/16/dimped_orb#user-content-fnref-1-d27f14">↩</a></p>
</li>
</ol>
</section>]]></content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[1950-05-11, Oregon：McMinnville UFO 事件：Evelyn Trent の証言音声]]></title>
        <id>https://ouchaku.github.io/ds/en/blog/2024/07/16/evenly_trent</id>
        <link href="https://ouchaku.github.io/ds/en/blog/2024/07/16/evenly_trent"/>
        <updated>2024-07-16T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[前置き]]></summary>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="前置き">前置き<a class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to 前置き" title="Direct link to 前置き" href="https://ouchaku.github.io/ds/en/blog/2024/07/16/evenly_trent#%E5%89%8D%E7%BD%AE%E3%81%8D">​</a></h2>
<p>本人の証言音声を見かけたので、証言文字起こし＋和訳 を記録しておく。</p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="関連">関連<a class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to 関連" title="Direct link to 関連" href="https://ouchaku.github.io/ds/en/blog/2024/07/16/evenly_trent#%E9%96%A2%E9%80%A3">​</a></h2>
<p><a href="http://news21c.blog.fc2.com/blog-entry-21826.html" target="_blank">❏ 1950-05-11, Oregon : McMinnville UFO 事件の最初の UFO 目撃者</a> (2024-01-18)</p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="whisper-ailarge-v2-model--deepl">Whisper AI(large-v2 model) + DeepL<a class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Whisper AI(large-v2 model) + DeepL" title="Direct link to Whisper AI(large-v2 model) + DeepL" href="https://ouchaku.github.io/ds/en/blog/2024/07/16/evenly_trent#whisper-ailarge-v2-model--deepl">​</a></h2>
<p>これらのUFOは空高く飛んでいたが、もっと地上に近い他の地域から報告されたものもあった。たとえば、オレゴン州マクミンビルのポール・トレント夫人が50年代初頭に見たというUFOだ。
たまたま上を見上げたら、こんなものが見えたんだ。家に駆け込んで彼に話したよ。
(00:49:45)</p>
<p>彼はカメラを片っ端から追いかけ、私はカメラをもう片っ端から追いかけた。
どんな感じだったか教えてくれる？</p>
<p>まあ、紐も何もない靴くらいの大きさかな。
底は平らで、銀色だった。
(00:50:04)</p>
<p>私はゴツゴツしたものにぶつかるところだった。
煙も音も一度もなかった。
地面にどれくらい近かったと言った？
そうだな、電線のすぐ上だった。
ただ、距離とかはわからないんだ。
しばらくホバリングしていたはずなんだけど、そんな感じで、彼は写真を撮ったんだ。写真の最初の方で、フィルムを巻き直して、もう一枚撮ろうとしたんだけど、撮った途端、向きを変えて、あっという間に飛び去ってしまったんだ。
(00:50:34)</p>
<hr style="height:3px;border-width:3px;color:orange;background-color:blue">
<p>Those UFOs were high in the sky, but some were reported from other parts of the country more down to Earth, such as the UFO Mrs. Paul Trent of McMinnville, Oregon, said she saw in the early 50s.
And I happened to look up, and I seen this thing, and I ran into the house to tell him about it.
(00:49:45)</p>
<p>He went one way after a camera, and I went the other way after a camera, and between the both of us, we found it.
Can you tell us what it looked like?
Well, about the best thing I could say would be just about the size of a pair of shoes without any strings or anything like that.
It was all flat on the bottom, and it was silvery color.
(00:50:04)</p>
<p>I was about to run into a rugged.
There was no smoke, no noise, even once.
How close to the ground did you say it was?
Well, it was just above the electric light wires away.
I just, you know, the distance and stuff, I just don't know.
It should have hovered for a while, you know, just like that, and he took the picture, and right at the beginning of the picture, he wound the film to re-roll it, you know, to take another one, and as soon as he took it, it turned and just took off very fast.
(00:50:34)</p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="動画13635">動画(1:36:35)<a class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to 動画(1:36:35)" title="Direct link to 動画(1:36:35)" href="https://ouchaku.github.io/ds/en/blog/2024/07/16/evenly_trent#%E5%8B%95%E7%94%BB13635">​</a></h2>
<p>Invasion: UFO Encounters and Alien Beings
<a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=AxK6S_Zh5ug" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">www.youtube.com/watch?v=AxK6S_Zh5ug</a></p>
<p>95,600 views  Apr 26, 2012</p>
<p>(2024-07-16)</p>]]></content>
    </entry>
</feed>